<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>My Customized Papers</title><link>https://github.com/your_username/your_repo</link><description>Aggregated research papers</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:49 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>[C&amp;S 2026] SemTaint: A scalable taint analysis approach for JavaWeb frameworks and composite containers</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167404825005103?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: April 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Computers &amp; Security, Volume 163&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Haotian Huang, Ruibin Yan, Jian Gao&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Computers &amp; Security</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:49 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167404825005103</guid></item><item><title>[SCP 2026] DATVD: A novel vulnerability detection method based on dynamic attention and hybrid convolutional pooling</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167642326000080?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: June 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Science of Computer Programming, Volume 251&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Jinfu Chen, Jinyu Mu, Saihua Cai, Jiapeng Zhou, Ziyan Liu, Xinping Shi&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Science of Computer Programming</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:23 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167642326000080</guid></item><item><title>[JSS 2026] RLV: LLM-based vulnerability detection by retrieving and refining contextual information</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016412122500425X?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: May 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Journal of Systems and Software, Volume 235&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Fangcheng Qiu, Zhongxin Liu, Bingde Hu, Zhengong Cai, Lingfeng Bao, Xinyu Wang&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Systems and Software</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016412122500425X</guid></item><item><title>[JSS 2026] Clash: Enhancing context-sensitivity in data-flow analysis for mitigating the impact of indirect calls</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0164121225004224?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: May 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Journal of Systems and Software, Volume 235&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Jinyan Xie, Yingzhou Zhang, Mingzhe Hu, Liping Han, Le Yu, Qiuran Ding&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Systems and Software</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:22 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0164121225004224</guid></item><item><title>[IST 2026] COTVD: A function-level vulnerability detection framework using chain-of-thought reasoning with large language models</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000327?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: May 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Information and Software Technology, Volume 193&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Yinan Chen, Xiangping Chen, Yuan Huang, Changlin Yang, Lei Yun&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Information and Software Technology</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000327</guid></item><item><title>[IST 2026] EdgeSim: Firmware vulnerability detection with control transfer-enhanced binary code similarity detection</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000091?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: April 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Information and Software Technology, Volume 192&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Li Liu, Shen Wang, Xunzhi Jiang&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Information and Software Technology</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000091</guid></item><item><title>[IST 2026] CSVD-AES: Cross-project software vulnerability detection based on active learning with metric fusion</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000042?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: April 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Information and Software Technology, Volume 192&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Zhidan Yuan, Xiang Chen, Juan Zhang, Weiming Zeng&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Information and Software Technology</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000042</guid></item><item><title>[IST 2026] VulSEG: Enhanced graph-based vulnerability detection system with advanced text embedding</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584925003465?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: April 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Information and Software Technology, Volume 192&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Wenjing Cai, Xin Liu, Lipeng Gao&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Information and Software Technology</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 16:45:20 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584925003465</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Evaluating Large Language Models on Solved and Unsolved Problems in Graph Theory: Implications for Computing Education</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05059</link><description>arXiv:2602.05059v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models are increasingly used by students to explore advanced material in computer science, including graph theory. As these tools become integrated into undergraduate and graduate coursework, it is important to understand how reliably they support mathematically rigorous thinking. This study examines the performance of a LLM on two related graph theoretic problems: a solved problem concerning the gracefulness of line graphs and an open problem for which no solution is currently known. We use an eight stage evaluation protocol that reflects authentic mathematical inquiry, including interpretation, exploration, strategy formation, and proof construction.
  The model performed strongly on the solved problem, producing correct definitions, identifying relevant structures, recalling appropriate results without hallucination, and constructing a valid proof confirmed by a graph theory expert. For the open problem, the model generated coherent interpretations and plausible exploratory strategies but did not advance toward a solution. It did not fabricate results and instead acknowledged uncertainty, which is consistent with the explicit prompting instructions that directed the model to avoid inventing theorems or unsupported claims.
  These findings indicate that LLMs can support exploration of established material but remain limited in tasks requiring novel mathematical insight or critical structural reasoning. For computing education, this distinction highlights the importance of guiding students to use LLMs for conceptual exploration while relying on independent verification and rigorous argumentation for formal problem solving.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05059v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Understanding LLM Evaluator Behavior: A Structured Multi-Evaluator Framework for Merchant Risk Assessment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05110</link><description>arXiv:2602.05110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly used as evaluators of reasoning quality, yet their reliability and bias in payments-risk settings remain poorly understood. We introduce a structured multi-evaluator framework for assessing LLM reasoning in Merchant Category Code (MCC)-based merchant risk assessment, combining a five-criterion rubric with Monte-Carlo scoring to evaluate rationale quality and evaluator stability. Five frontier LLMs generate and cross-evaluate MCC risk rationales under attributed and anonymized conditions. To establish a judge-independent reference, we introduce a consensus-deviation metric that eliminates circularity by comparing each judge's score to the mean of all other judges, yielding a theoretically grounded measure of self-evaluation and cross-model deviation. Results reveal substantial heterogeneity: GPT-5.1 and Claude 4.5 Sonnet show negative self-evaluation bias (-0.33, -0.31), while Gemini-2.5 Pro and Grok 4 display positive bias (+0.77, +0.71), with bias attenuating by 25.8 percent under anonymization. Evaluation by 26 payment-industry experts shows LLM judges assign scores averaging +0.46 points above human consensus, and that the negative bias of GPT-5.1 and Claude 4.5 Sonnet reflects closer alignment with human judgment. Ground-truth validation using payment-network data shows four models exhibit statistically significant alignment (Spearman rho = 0.56 to 0.77), confirming that the framework captures genuine quality. Overall, the framework provides a replicable basis for evaluating LLM-as-a-judge systems in payment-risk workflows and highlights the need for bias-aware protocols in operational financial settings.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05110v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Hallucination-Resistant Security Planning with a Large Language Model</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05279</link><description>arXiv:2602.05279v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are promising tools for supporting security management tasks, such as incident response planning. However, their unreliability and tendency to hallucinate remain significant challenges. In this paper, we address these challenges by introducing a principled framework for using an LLM as decision support in security management. Our framework integrates the LLM in an iterative loop where it generates candidate actions that are checked for consistency with system constraints and lookahead predictions. When consistency is low, we abstain from the generated actions and instead collect external feedback, e.g., by evaluating actions in a digital twin. This feedback is then used to refine the candidate actions through in-context learning (ICL). We prove that this design allows to control the hallucination risk by tuning the consistency threshold. Moreover, we establish a bound on the regret of ICL under certain assumptions. To evaluate our framework, we apply it to an incident response use case where the goal is to generate a response and recovery plan based on system logs. Experiments on four public datasets show that our framework reduces recovery times by up to 30% compared to frontier LLMs.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05279v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Aspect-Aware MOOC Recommendation in a Heterogeneous Network</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05297</link><description>arXiv:2602.05297v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: MOOC recommendation systems have received increasing attention to help learners navigate and select preferred learning content. Traditional methods such as collaborative filtering and content-based filtering suffer from data sparsity and over-specialization. To alleviate these limitations, graph-based approaches have been proposed; however, they still rely heavily on manually predefined metapaths, which often capture only superficial structural relationships and impose substantial burdens on domain experts as well as significant engineering costs. To overcome these limitations, we propose AMR (Aspect-aware MOOC Recommendation), a novel framework that models path-specific multiple aspects by embedding the semantic content of nodes within each metapath. AMR automatically discovers metapaths through bi-directional walks, derives aspect-aware path representations using a bi-LSTM-based encoder, and incorporates these representations as edge features in the learner-learner and KC-KC subgraphs to achieve fine-grained semantically informed KC recommendations. Extensive experiments on the large-scale MOOCCube and PEEK datasets show that AMR consistently outperforms state-of-the-art graph neural network baselines across key metrics such as HR@K and nDCG@K. Further analysis confirms that AMR effectively captures rich path-specific aspect information, allowing more accurate recommendations than those methods that rely solely on predefined metapaths. The code will be available upon accepted.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05297v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] ProAct: Agentic Lookahead in Interactive Environments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05327</link><description>arXiv:2602.05327v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing Large Language Model (LLM) agents struggle in interactive environments requiring long-horizon planning, primarily due to compounding errors when simulating future states. To address this, we propose ProAct, a framework that enables agents to internalize accurate lookahead reasoning through a two-stage training paradigm. First, we introduce Grounded LookAhead Distillation (GLAD), where the agent undergoes supervised fine-tuning on trajectories derived from environment-based search. By compressing complex search trees into concise, causal reasoning chains, the agent learns the logic of foresight without the computational overhead of inference-time search. Second, to further refine decision accuracy, we propose the Monte-Carlo Critic (MC-Critic), a plug-and-play auxiliary value estimator designed to enhance policy-gradient algorithms like PPO and GRPO. By leveraging lightweight environment rollouts to calibrate value estimates, MC-Critic provides a low-variance signal that facilitates stable policy optimization without relying on expensive model-based value approximation. Experiments on both stochastic (e.g., 2048) and deterministic (e.g., Sokoban) environments demonstrate that ProAct significantly improves planning accuracy. Notably, a 4B parameter model trained with ProAct outperforms all open-source baselines and rivals state-of-the-art closed-source models, while demonstrating robust generalization to unseen environments. The codes and models are available at https://github.com/GreatX3/ProAct</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05327v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Clinical Validation of Medical-based Large Language Model Chatbots on Ophthalmic Patient Queries with LLM-based Evaluation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05381</link><description>arXiv:2602.05381v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Domain specific large language models are increasingly used to support patient education, triage, and clinical decision making in ophthalmology, making rigorous evaluation essential to ensure safety and accuracy. This study evaluated four small medical LLMs Meerkat-7B, BioMistral-7B, OpenBioLLM-8B, and MedLLaMA3-v20 in answering ophthalmology related patient queries and assessed the feasibility of LLM based evaluation against clinician grading. In this cross sectional study, 180 ophthalmology patient queries were answered by each model, generating 2160 responses. Models were selected for parameter sizes under 10 billion to enable resource efficient deployment. Responses were evaluated by three ophthalmologists of differing seniority and by GPT-4-Turbo using the S.C.O.R.E. framework assessing safety, consensus and context, objectivity, reproducibility, and explainability, with ratings assigned on a five point Likert scale. Agreement between LLM and clinician grading was assessed using Spearman rank correlation, Kendall tau statistics, and kernel density estimate analyses. Meerkat-7B achieved the highest performance with mean scores of 3.44 from Senior Consultants, 4.08 from Consultants, and 4.18 from Residents. MedLLaMA3-v20 performed poorest, with 25.5 percent of responses containing hallucinations or clinically misleading content, including fabricated terminology. GPT-4-Turbo grading showed strong alignment with clinician assessments overall, with Spearman rho of 0.80 and Kendall tau of 0.67, though Senior Consultants graded more conservatively. Overall, medical LLMs demonstrated potential for safe ophthalmic question answering, but gaps remained in clinical depth and consensus, supporting the feasibility of LLM based evaluation for large scale benchmarking and the need for hybrid automated and clinician review frameworks to guide safe clinical deployment.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05381v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Refine and Purify: Orthogonal Basis Optimization with Null-Space Denoising for Conditional Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05464</link><description>arXiv:2602.05464v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conditional representation learning aims to extract criterion-specific features for customized tasks. Recent studies project universal features onto the conditional feature subspace spanned by an LLM-generated text basis to obtain conditional representations. However, such methods face two key limitations: sensitivity to subspace basis and vulnerability to inter-subspace interference. To address these challenges, we propose OD-CRL, a novel framework integrating Adaptive Orthogonal Basis Optimization (AOBO) and Null-Space Denoising Projection (NSDP). Specifically, AOBO constructs orthogonal semantic bases via singular value decomposition with a curvature-based truncation. NSDP suppresses non-target semantic interference by projecting embeddings onto the null space of irrelevant subspaces. Extensive experiments conducted across customized clustering, customized classification, and customized retrieval tasks demonstrate that OD-CRL achieves a new state-of-the-art performance with superior generalization.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05464v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] ALIVE: Awakening LLM Reasoning via Adversarial Learning and Instructive Verbal Evaluation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05472</link><description>arXiv:2602.05472v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The quest for expert-level reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs) has been hampered by a persistent \textit{reward bottleneck}: traditional reinforcement learning (RL) relies on scalar rewards that are \textbf{costly} to scale, \textbf{brittle} across domains, and \textbf{blind} to the underlying logic of a solution. This reliance on external, impoverished signals prevents models from developing a deep, self-contained understanding of reasoning principles. We introduce \textbf{ALIVE} (\emph{Adversarial Learning with Instructive Verbal Evaluation}), a hands-free alignment framework that moves beyond scalar reward optimization toward intrinsic reasoning acquisition. Grounded in the principle of \emph{Cognitive Synergy}, ALIVE unifies problem posing, solving, and judging within a single policy model to internalize the logic of correctness. By coupling adversarial learning with instructive verbal feedback, ALIVE enables models to internalize evaluative criteria directly from raw corpora, effectively transforming external critiques into an endogenous reasoning faculty. Empirical evaluations across mathematical reasoning, code generation, and general logical inference benchmarks demonstrate that ALIVE consistently mitigates reward signal limitations. With identical data and compute, it achieves accuracy gains, markedly improved cross-domain generalization, and higher self-correction rates. These results indicate that the reasoning trinity fosters a self-sustaining trajectory of capability growth, positioning ALIVE as a scalable foundation for general-purpose reasoning alignment without human-in-the-loop supervision.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05472v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Graph-based Agent Memory: Taxonomy, Techniques, and Applications</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05665</link><description>arXiv:2602.05665v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Memory emerges as the core module in the Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents for long-horizon complex tasks (e.g., multi-turn dialogue, game playing, scientific discovery), where memory can enable knowledge accumulation, iterative reasoning and self-evolution. Among diverse paradigms, graph stands out as a powerful structure for agent memory due to the intrinsic capabilities to model relational dependencies, organize hierarchical information, and support efficient retrieval. This survey presents a comprehensive review of agent memory from the graph-based perspective. First, we introduce a taxonomy of agent memory, including short-term vs. long-term memory, knowledge vs. experience memory, non-structural vs. structural memory, with an implementation view of graph-based memory. Second, according to the life cycle of agent memory, we systematically analyze the key techniques in graph-based agent memory, covering memory extraction for transforming the data into the contents, storage for organizing the data efficiently, retrieval for retrieving the relevant contents from memory to support reasoning, and evolution for updating the contents in the memory. Third, we summarize the open-sourced libraries and benchmarks that support the development and evaluation of self-evolving agent memory. We also explore diverse application scenarios. Finally, we identify critical challenges and future research directions. This survey aims to offer actionable insights to advance the development of more efficient and reliable graph-based agent memory systems. All the related resources, including research papers, open-source data, and projects, are collected for the community in https://github.com/DEEP-PolyU/Awesome-GraphMemory.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05665v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] LeakBoost: Perceptual-Loss-Based Membership Inference Attack</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05748</link><description>arXiv:2602.05748v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Membership inference attacks (MIAs) aim to determine whether a sample was part of a model's training set, posing serious privacy risks for modern machine-learning systems. Existing MIAs primarily rely on static indicators, such as loss or confidence, and do not fully leverage the dynamic behavior of models when actively probed. We propose LeakBoost, a perceptual-loss-based interrogation framework that actively probes a model's internal representations to expose hidden membership signals. Given a candidate input, LeakBoost synthesizes an interrogation image by optimizing a perceptual (activation-space) objective, amplifying representational differences between members and non-members. This image is then analyzed by an off-the-shelf membership detector, without modifying the detector itself. When combined with existing membership inference methods, LeakBoost achieves substantial improvements at low false-positive rates across multiple image classification datasets and diverse neural network architectures. In particular, it raises AUC from near-chance levels (0.53-0.62) to 0.81-0.88, and increases TPR at 1 percent FPR by over an order of magnitude compared to strong baseline attacks. A detailed sensitivity analysis reveals that deeper layers and short, low-learning-rate optimization produce the strongest leakage, and that improvements concentrate in gradient-based detectors. LeakBoost thus offers a modular and computationally efficient way to assess privacy risks in white-box settings, advancing the study of dynamic membership inference.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05748v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] RocqSmith: Can Automatic Optimization Forge Better Proof Agents?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05762</link><description>arXiv:2602.05762v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: This work studies the applicability of automatic AI agent optimization methods to real-world agents in formal verification settings, focusing on automated theorem proving in Rocq as a representative and challenging domain. We evaluate how different automatic agent optimizers perform when applied to the task of optimizing a Rocq proof-generation agent, and assess whether parts of the fine-grained tuning of agentic systems, such as prompt design, contextual knowledge, and control strategies, can be automated. Our results show that while several optimizers yield measurable improvements, simple few-shot bootstrapping is the most consistently effective; however, none of the studied methods matches the performance of a carefully engineered state-of-the-art proof agent.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05762v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] TKG-Thinker: Towards Dynamic Reasoning over Temporal Knowledge Graphs via Agentic Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05818</link><description>arXiv:2602.05818v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Temporal knowledge graph question answering (TKGQA) aims to answer time-sensitive questions by leveraging temporal knowledge bases. While Large Language Models (LLMs) demonstrate significant potential in TKGQA, current prompting strategies constrain their efficacy in two primary ways. First, they are prone to reasoning hallucinations under complex temporal constraints. Second, static prompting limits model autonomy and generalization, as it lack optimization through dynamic interaction with temporal knowledge graphs (TKGs) environments. To address these limitations, we propose \textbf{TKG-Thinker}, a novel agent equipped with autonomous planning and adaptive retrieval capabilities for reasoning over TKGs. Specifically, TKG-Thinker performs in-depth temporal reasoning through dynamic multi-turn interactions with TKGs via a dual-training strategy. We first apply Supervised Fine-Tuning (SFT) with chain-of thought data to instill core planning capabilities, followed by a Reinforcement Learning (RL) stage that leverages multi-dimensional rewards to refine reasoning policies under intricate temporal constraints. Experimental results on benchmark datasets with three open-source LLMs show that TKG-Thinker achieves state-of-the-art performance and exhibits strong generalization across complex TKGQA settings.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05818v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Agent2Agent Threats in Safety-Critical LLM Assistants: A Human-Centric Taxonomy</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05877</link><description>arXiv:2602.05877v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The integration of Large Language Model (LLM)-based conversational agents into vehicles creates novel security challenges at the intersection of agentic AI, automotive safety, and inter-agent communication. As these intelligent assistants coordinate with external services via protocols such as Google's Agent-to-Agent (A2A), they establish attack surfaces where manipulations can propagate through natural language payloads, potentially causing severe consequences ranging from driver distraction to unauthorized vehicle control. Existing AI security frameworks, while foundational, lack the rigorous "separation of concerns" standard in safety-critical systems engineering by co-mingling the concepts of what is being protected (assets) with how it is attacked (attack paths). This paper addresses this methodological gap by proposing a threat modeling framework called AgentHeLLM (Agent Hazard Exploration for LLM Assistants) that formally separates asset identification from attack path analysis. We introduce a human-centric asset taxonomy derived from harm-oriented "victim modeling" and inspired by the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, and a formal graph-based model that distinguishes poison paths (malicious data propagation) from trigger paths (activation actions). We demonstrate the framework's practical applicability through an open-source attack path suggestion tool AgentHeLLM Attack Path Generator that automates multi-stage threat discovery using a bi-level search strategy.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05877v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] AgenticPay: A Multi-Agent LLM Negotiation System for Buyer-Seller Transactions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06008</link><description>arXiv:2602.06008v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based agents are increasingly expected to negotiate, coordinate, and transact autonomously, yet existing benchmarks lack principled settings for evaluating language-mediated economic interaction among multiple agents. We introduce AgenticPay, a benchmark and simulation framework for multi-agent buyer-seller negotiation driven by natural language. AgenticPay models markets in which buyers and sellers possess private constraints and product-dependent valuations, and must reach agreements through multi-round linguistic negotiation rather than numeric bidding alone. The framework supports a diverse suite of over 110 tasks ranging from bilateral bargaining to many-to-many markets, with structured action extraction and metrics for feasibility, efficiency, and welfare. Benchmarking state-of-the-art proprietary and open-weight LLMs reveals substantial gaps in negotiation performance and highlights challenges in long-horizon strategic reasoning, establishing AgenticPay as a foundation for studying agentic commerce and language-based market interaction. Code and dataset are available at the link: https://github.com/SafeRL-Lab/AgenticPay.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06008v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] DyTopo: Dynamic Topology Routing for Multi-Agent Reasoning via Semantic Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06039</link><description>arXiv:2602.06039v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-agent systems built from prompted large language models can improve multi-round reasoning, yet most existing pipelines rely on fixed, trajectory-wide communication patterns that are poorly matched to the stage-dependent needs of iterative problem solving. We introduce DyTopo, a manager-guided multi-agent framework that reconstructs a sparse directed communication graph at each round. Conditioned on the manager's round goal, each agent outputs lightweight natural-language query (need) and \key (offer) descriptors; DyTopo embeds these descriptors and performs semantic matching, routing private messages only along the induced edges. Across code generation and mathematical reasoning benchmarks and four LLM backbones, DyTopo consistently outperforms over the strongest baseline (avg. +6.2). Beyond accuracy, DyTopo yields an interpretable coordination trace via the evolving graphs, enabling qualitative inspection of how communication pathways reconfigure across rounds.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06039v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Doc2Spec: Synthesizing Formal Programming Specifications from Natural Language via Grammar Induction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04892</link><description>arXiv:2602.04892v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Ensuring that API implementations and usage comply with natural language programming rules is critical for software correctness, security, and reliability. Formal verification can provide strong guarantees but requires precise specifications, which are difficult and costly to write manually. To address this challenge, we present Doc2Spec, a multi-agent framework that uses LLMs to automatically induce a specification grammar from natural-language rules and then generates formal specifications guided by the induced grammar. The grammar captures essential domain knowledge, constrains the specification space, and enforces consistent representations, thereby improving the reliability and quality of generated specifications. Evaluated on seven benchmarks across three programming languages, Doc2Spec outperforms a baseline without grammar induction and achieves competitive results against a technique with a manually crafted grammar, demonstrating the effectiveness of automated grammar induction for formalizing natural-language rules.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04892v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] A Causal Perspective for Enhancing Jailbreak Attack and Defense</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04893</link><description>arXiv:2602.04893v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Uncovering the mechanisms behind "jailbreaks" in large language models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing their safety and reliability, yet these mechanisms remain poorly understood. Existing studies predominantly analyze jailbreak prompts by probing latent representations, often overlooking the causal relationships between interpretable prompt features and jailbreak occurrences. In this work, we propose Causal Analyst, a framework that integrates LLMs into data-driven causal discovery to identify the direct causes of jailbreaks and leverage them for both attack and defense. We introduce a comprehensive dataset comprising 35k jailbreak attempts across seven LLMs, systematically constructed from 100 attack templates and 50 harmful queries, annotated with 37 meticulously designed human-readable prompt features. By jointly training LLM-based prompt encoding and GNN-based causal graph learning, we reconstruct causal pathways linking prompt features to jailbreak responses. Our analysis reveals that specific features, such as "Positive Character" and "Number of Task Steps", act as direct causal drivers of jailbreaks. We demonstrate the practical utility of these insights through two applications: (1) a Jailbreaking Enhancer that targets identified causal features to significantly boost attack success rates on public benchmarks, and (2) a Guardrail Advisor that utilizes the learned causal graph to extract true malicious intent from obfuscated queries. Extensive experiments, including baseline comparisons and causal structure validation, confirm the robustness of our causal analysis and its superiority over non-causal approaches. Our results suggest that analyzing jailbreak features from a causal perspective is an effective and interpretable approach for improving LLM reliability. Our code is available at https://github.com/Master-PLC/Causal-Analyst.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04893v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Extracting Recurring Vulnerabilities from Black-Box LLM-Generated Software</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04894</link><description>arXiv:2602.04894v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: LLMs are increasingly used for code generation, but their outputs often follow recurring templates that can induce predictable vulnerabilities. We study \emph{vulnerability persistence} in LLM-generated software and introduce \emph{Feature--Security Table (FSTab)} with two components. First, FSTab enables a black-box attack that predicts likely backend vulnerabilities from observable frontend features and knowledge of the source LLM, without access to backend code or source code. Second, FSTab provides a model-centric evaluation that quantifies how consistently a given model reproduces the same vulnerabilities across programs, semantics-preserving rephrasings, and application domains. We evaluate FSTab on state-of-the-art code LLMs, including GPT-5.2, Claude-4.5 Opus, and Gemini-3 Pro, across diverse application domains. Our results show strong cross-domain transfer: even when the target domain is excluded from training, FSTab achieves up to 94\% attack success and 93\% vulnerability coverage on Internal Tools (Claude-4.5 Opus). These findings expose an underexplored attack surface in LLM-generated software and highlight the security risks of code generation. Our code is available at: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/FSTab-024E.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04894v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Internalizing LLM Reasoning via Discovery and Replay of Latent Actions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04925</link><description>arXiv:2602.04925v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The internalization of chain-of-thought processes into hidden states has emerged as a highly efficient paradigm for scaling test-time compute. However, existing activation steering methods rely on static control vectors that fail to adapt to the non-stationary evolution of complex reasoning tasks. To address this limitation, we propose STIR (Self-Distilled Tools for Internal Reasoning), a framework that reformulates reasoning enhancement as a dynamic latent trajectory control problem. STIR introduces a synergistic three-stage pipeline: (1) differential intrinsic action induction harvests latent reasoning successes to crystallize steering primitives; (2) sparse control basis construction curates a compact, geometrically diverse tool library; and (3) value-modulated trajectory intervention dynamically injects context-specific impulses via anchor-based gating. Extensive experiments on six arithmetic and logical benchmarks across four representative models demonstrate that STIR improves average accuracy by 1.9% to 7.5% while reducing average token consumption by up to 35% compared to vanilla decoding. These findings demonstrate that the benefits of explicit chain-of-thought can be realized through dynamic latent trajectory control, internalizing the reasoning process to bypass the explicit generation while achieving superior fidelity. Our code is available at https://github.com/sznnzs/LLM-Latent-Action.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04925v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] E-Globe: Scalable $\epsilon$-Global Verification of Neural Networks via Tight Upper Bounds and Pattern-Aware Branching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05068</link><description>arXiv:2602.05068v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Neural networks achieve strong empirical performance, but robustness concerns still hinder deployment in safety-critical applications. Formal verification provides robustness guarantees, but current methods face a scalability-completeness trade-off. We propose a hybrid verifier in a branch-and-bound (BaB) framework that efficiently tightens both upper and lower bounds until an $\epsilon-$global optimum is reached or early stop is triggered. The key is an exact nonlinear program with complementarity constraints (NLP-CC) for upper bounding that preserves the ReLU input-output graph, so any feasible solution yields a valid counterexample and enables rapid pruning of unsafe subproblems. We further accelerate verification with (i) warm-started NLP solves requiring minimal constraint-matrix updates and (ii) pattern-aligned strong branching that prioritizes splits most effective at tightening relaxations. We also provide conditions under which NLP-CC upper bounds are tight. Experiments on MNIST and CIFAR-10 show markedly tighter upper bounds than PGD across perturbation radii spanning up to three orders of magnitude, fast per-node solves in practice, and substantial end-to-end speedups over MIP-based verification, amplified by warm-starting, GPU batching, and pattern-aligned branching.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05068v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] EGSS: Entropy-guided Stepwise Scaling for Reliable Software Engineering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05242</link><description>arXiv:2602.05242v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Agentic Test-Time Scaling (TTS) has delivered state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on complex software engineering tasks such as code generation and bug fixing. However, its practical adoption remains limited due to significant computational overhead, primarily driven by two key challenges: (1) the high cost associated with deploying excessively large ensembles, and (2) the lack of a reliable mechanism for selecting the optimal candidate solution, ultimately constraining the performance gains that can be realized. To address these challenges, we propose Entropy-Guided Stepwise Scaling (EGSS), a novel TTS framework that dynamically balances efficiency and effectiveness through entropy-guided adaptive search and robust test-suite augmentation. Extensive experiments on SWE-Bench-Verified demonstrate that EGSS consistently boosts performance by 5-10% across all evaluated models. Specifically, it increases the resolved ratio of Kimi-K2-Intruct from 63.2% to 72.2%, and GLM-4.6 from 65.8% to 74.6%. Furthermore, when paired with GLM-4.6, EGSS achieves a new state-of-the-art among open-source large language models. In addition to these accuracy improvements, EGSS reduces inference-time token usage by over 28% compared to existing TTS methods, achieving simultaneous gains in both effectiveness and computational efficiency.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05242v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Spider-Sense: Intrinsic Risk Sensing for Efficient Agent Defense with Hierarchical Adaptive Screening</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05386</link><description>arXiv:2602.05386v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: As large language models (LLMs) evolve into autonomous agents, their real-world applicability has expanded significantly, accompanied by new security challenges. Most existing agent defense mechanisms adopt a mandatory checking paradigm, in which security validation is forcibly triggered at predefined stages of the agent lifecycle. In this work, we argue that effective agent security should be intrinsic and selective rather than architecturally decoupled and mandatory. We propose Spider-Sense framework, an event-driven defense framework based on Intrinsic Risk Sensing (IRS), which allows agents to maintain latent vigilance and trigger defenses only upon risk perception. Once triggered, the Spider-Sense invokes a hierarchical defence mechanism that trades off efficiency and precision: it resolves known patterns via lightweight similarity matching while escalating ambiguous cases to deep internal reasoning, thereby eliminating reliance on external models. To facilitate rigorous evaluation, we introduce S$^2$Bench, a lifecycle-aware benchmark featuring realistic tool execution and multi-stage attacks. Extensive experiments demonstrate that Spider-Sense achieves competitive or superior defense performance, attaining the lowest Attack Success Rate (ASR) and False Positive Rate (FPR), with only a marginal latency overhead of 8.3\%.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05386v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] LinguistAgent: A Reflective Multi-Model Platform for Automated Linguistic Annotation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05493</link><description>arXiv:2602.05493v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Data annotation remains a significant bottleneck in the Humanities and Social Sciences, particularly for complex semantic tasks such as metaphor identification. While Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise, a significant gap remains between the theoretical capability of LLMs and their practical utility for researchers. This paper introduces LinguistAgent, an integrated, user-friendly platform that leverages a reflective multi-model architecture to automate linguistic annotation. The system implements a dual-agent workflow, comprising an Annotator and a Reviewer, to simulate a professional peer-review process. LinguistAgent supports comparative experiments across three paradigms: Prompt Engineering (Zero/Few-shot), Retrieval-Augmented Generation, and Fine-tuning. We demonstrate LinguistAgent's efficacy using the task of metaphor identification as an example, providing real-time token-level evaluation (Precision, Recall, and $F_1$ score) against human gold standards. The application and codes are released on https://github.com/Bingru-Li/LinguistAgent.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05493v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Capture the Flags: Family-Based Evaluation of Agentic LLMs via Semantics-Preserving Transformations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05523</link><description>arXiv:2602.05523v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Agentic large language models (LLMs) are increasingly evaluated on cybersecurity tasks using capture-the-flag (CTF) benchmarks. However, existing pointwise benchmarks have limited ability to shed light on the robustness and generalisation abilities of agents across alternative versions of the source code. We introduce CTF challenge families, whereby a single CTF is used as the basis for generating a family of semantically-equivalent challenges via semantics-preserving program transformations. This enables controlled evaluation of agent robustness to source code transformations while keeping the underlying exploit strategy fixed. We introduce a new tool, Evolve-CTF, that generates CTF families from Python challenges using a range of transformations. Using Evolve-CTF to derive families from Cybench and Intercode challenges, we evaluate 13 agentic LLM configurations with tool access. We find that models are remarkably robust to intrusive renaming and code insertion-based transformations, but that composed transformations and deeper obfuscation affect performance by requiring more sophisticated use of tools. We also find that enabling explicit reasoning has little effect on solution success rates across challenge families. Our work contributes a valuable technique and tool for future LLM evaluations, and a large dataset characterising the capabilities of current state-of-the-art models in this domain.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05523v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Automated Customization of LLMs for Enterprise Code Repositories Using Semantic Scopes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05780</link><description>arXiv:2602.05780v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Code completion (CC) is a task frequently used by developers when working in collaboration with LLM-based programming assistants. Despite the increased performance of LLMs on public benchmarks, out of the box LLMs still have a hard time generating code that aligns with a private code repository not previously seen by the model's training data. Customizing code LLMs to a private repository provides a way to improve the model performance. In this paper we present our approach for automated LLM customization based on semantic scopes in the code. We evaluate LLMs on real industry cases with two private enterprise code repositories with two customization strategies: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) and supervised Fine-Tuning (FT). Our mechanism for ingesting the repository's data and formulating the training data pairs with semantic scopes helps models to learn the underlying patterns specific to the repository, providing more precise code to developers and helping to boost their productivity. The code completions of moderately sized customized models can be significantly better than those of uncustomized models of much larger capacity. We also include an analysis of customization on two public benchmarks and present opportunities for future work.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05780v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] DARWIN: Dynamic Agentically Rewriting Self-Improving Network</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05848</link><description>arXiv:2602.05848v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: DARWIN is an evolutionary GPT model, utilizing a genetic-algorithm like optimization structure with several independent GPT agents being trained individually using unique training code. Each iteration, the GPT models are prompted to modify the training code of one another in an attempt to improve their performance in a mutation-like manner, and the best GPT agents are then benchmarked and selected for the next iteration by genetic algorithm. For demonstration purposes and due to budget and time constraints, OpenAI API is used to prompt training code improvements and the nanoGPT framework is used as the training code. DARWIN also utilizes persistent JSON-based memory files to track previous reasoning and changes to code to correlate with improvement to model performance. and a bidirectional interface for HITL intervention allowing the model to request upgrades such as additional datasets, training scripts, and restructuring of file hierarchies. In experiments, DARWIN achieved a 1.26 percent improvement in model FLOPS utilization (MFU) and a 2.07 percent improvement to perplexity in 5 iterations of training over baseline configurations, demonstrating promising capabilities as a foundation for scaling evolutionary GPT training.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05848v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Dr. Kernel: Reinforcement Learning Done Right for Triton Kernel Generations</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05885</link><description>arXiv:2602.05885v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: High-quality kernel is critical for scalable AI systems, and enabling LLMs to generate such code would advance AI development. However, training LLMs for this task requires sufficient data, a robust environment, and the process is often vulnerable to reward hacking and lazy optimization. In these cases, models may hack training rewards and prioritize trivial correctness over meaningful speedup. In this paper, we systematically study reinforcement learning (RL) for kernel generation. We first design KernelGYM, a robust distributed GPU environment that supports reward hacking check, data collection from multi-turn interactions and long-term RL training. Building on KernelGYM, we investigate effective multi-turn RL methods and identify a biased policy gradient issue caused by self-inclusion in GRPO. To solve this, we propose Turn-level Reinforce-Leave-One-Out (TRLOO) to provide unbiased advantage estimation for multi-turn RL. To alleviate lazy optimization, we incorporate mismatch correction for training stability and introduce Profiling-based Rewards (PR) and Profiling-based Rejection Sampling (PRS) to overcome the issue. The trained model, Dr.Kernel-14B, reaches performance competitive with Claude-4.5-Sonnet in Kernelbench. Finally, we study sequential test-time scaling for Dr.Kernel-14B. On the KernelBench Level-2 subset, 31.6% of the generated kernels achieve at least a 1.2x speedup over the Torch reference, surpassing Claude-4.5-Sonnet (26.7%) and GPT-5 (28.6%). When selecting the best candidate across all turns, this 1.2x speedup rate further increases to 47.8%. All resources, including environment, training code, models, and dataset, are included in https://www.github.com/hkust-nlp/KernelGYM.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05885v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] CommCP: Efficient Multi-Agent Coordination via LLM-Based Communication with Conformal Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06038</link><description>arXiv:2602.06038v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: To complete assignments provided by humans in natural language, robots must interpret commands, generate and answer relevant questions for scene understanding, and manipulate target objects. Real-world deployments often require multiple heterogeneous robots with different manipulation capabilities to handle different assignments cooperatively. Beyond the need for specialized manipulation skills, effective information gathering is important in completing these assignments. To address this component of the problem, we formalize the information-gathering process in a fully cooperative setting as an underexplored multi-agent multi-task Embodied Question Answering (MM-EQA) problem, which is a novel extension of canonical Embodied Question Answering (EQA), where effective communication is crucial for coordinating efforts without redundancy. To address this problem, we propose CommCP, a novel LLM-based decentralized communication framework designed for MM-EQA. Our framework employs conformal prediction to calibrate the generated messages, thereby minimizing receiver distractions and enhancing communication reliability. To evaluate our framework, we introduce an MM-EQA benchmark featuring diverse, photo-realistic household scenarios with embodied questions. Experimental results demonstrate that CommCP significantly enhances the task success rate and exploration efficiency over baselines. The experiment videos, code, and dataset are available on our project website: https://comm-cp.github.io.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06038v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Robust Answers, Fragile Logic: Probing the Decoupling Hypothesis in LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.17406</link><description>arXiv:2505.17406v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has become a cornerstone for complex reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs), the faithfulness of the generated reasoning remains an open question. We investigate the Decoupling Hypothesis: that correct answers often mask fragile, post-hoc rationalizations that are not causally tied to the model's prediction. To systematically verify this, we introduce MATCHA, a novel Answer-Conditioned Probing framework. Unlike standard evaluations that focus on final output accuracy, MATCHA isolates the reasoning phase by conditioning generation on the model's predicted answer, allowing us to stress-test the stability of the rationale itself. Our experiments reveal a critical vulnerability: under imperceptible input perturbations, LLMs frequently maintain the correct answer while generating inconsistent or nonsensical reasoning - effectively being ``Right for the Wrong Reasons''. Using LLM judges to quantify this robustness gap, we find that multi-step and commonsense tasks are significantly more susceptible to this decoupling than logical tasks. Furthermore, we demonstrate that adversarial examples generated by MATCHA transfer non-trivially to black-box models. Our findings expose the illusion of CoT robustness and underscore the need for future architectures that enforce genuine answer-reasoning consistency rather than mere surface-level accuracy.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2505.17406v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Verifying the Verifiers: Unveiling Pitfalls and Potentials in Fact Verifiers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.13342</link><description>arXiv:2506.13342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fact verification is essential for ensuring the reliability of LLM applications. In this study, we evaluate 12 pre-trained LLMs and one specialized fact-verifier, including frontier LLMs and open-weight reasoning LLMs, using a collection of examples from 14 fact-checking benchmarks. We share three findings intended to guide future development of more robust fact verifiers. First, we highlight the importance of addressing annotation errors and ambiguity in datasets, demonstrating that approximately 16\% of ambiguous or incorrectly labeled data substantially influences model rankings. Neglecting this issue may result in misleading conclusions during comparative evaluations, and we suggest using a systematic pipeline utilizing LLM-as-a-judge to help identify these issues at scale. Second, we discover that frontier LLMs with few-shot in-context examples, often overlooked in previous works, achieve top-tier performance. We therefore recommend that future studies include comparisons with these simple yet highly effective baselines. Lastly, despite their effectiveness, frontier LLMs incur substantial costs, motivating the development of small, fine-tuned fact verifiers. We show that these small models still have room for improvement, particularly on instances that require complex reasoning. Encouragingly, we demonstrate that augmenting training with synthetic multi-hop reasoning data significantly enhances their capabilities in such instances. We release our code, model, and dataset at https://github.com/just1nseo/verifying-the-verifiers.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2506.13342v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] How Catastrophic is Your LLM? Certifying Risk in Conversation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.03969</link><description>arXiv:2510.03969v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) can produce catastrophic responses in conversational settings that pose serious risks to public safety and security. Existing evaluations often fail to fully reveal these vulnerabilities because they rely on fixed attack prompt sequences, lack statistical guarantees, and do not scale to the vast space of multi-turn conversations. In this work, we propose C$^3$LLM, a novel, principled statistical Certification framework for Catastrophic risks in multi-turn Conversation for LLMs that bounds the probability of an LLM generating catastrophic responses under multi-turn conversation distributions with statistical guarantees. We model multi-turn conversations as probability distributions over query sequences, represented by a Markov process on a query graph whose edges encode semantic similarity to capture realistic conversational flow, and quantify catastrophic risks using confidence intervals. We define several inexpensive and practical distributions--random node, graph path, and adaptive with rejection. Our results demonstrate that these distributions can reveal substantial catastrophic risks in frontier models, with certified lower bounds as high as 70% for the worst model, highlighting the urgent need for improved safety training strategies in frontier LLMs.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.03969v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] DeepAgent: A General Reasoning Agent with Scalable Toolsets</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21618</link><description>arXiv:2510.21618v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large reasoning models have demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities, yet real-world tasks often require external tools and long-horizon interactions. Existing agent frameworks typically follow predefined workflows, which limit autonomous and global task completion. In this paper, we introduce DeepAgent, an end-to-end deep reasoning agent that performs autonomous thinking, tool discovery, and action execution within a single, coherent reasoning process. To manage long-horizon interactions, we introduce an autonomous memory folding mechanism that compresses past interactions into structured episodic, working, and tool memories, reducing error accumulation while preserving critical information. To teach general-purpose tool use efficiently and stably, we develop an end-to-end reinforcement learning strategy, namely ToolPO, that leverages LLM-simulated APIs and applies tool-call advantage attribution to assign fine-grained credit to the tool invocation tokens. Extensive experiments on eight benchmarks, including general tool-use tasks (ToolBench, API-Bank, TMDB, Spotify, ToolHop) and downstream applications (ALFWorld, WebShop, GAIA, HLE), demonstrate that DeepAgent consistently outperforms baselines across both labeled-tool and open-set tool retrieval scenarios. The code and demo are available at https://github.com/RUC-NLPIR/DeepAgent.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.21618v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] The Why Behind the Action: Unveiling Internal Drivers via Agentic Attribution</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.15075</link><description>arXiv:2601.15075v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents are widely used in real-world applications such as customer service, web navigation, and software engineering. As these systems become more autonomous and are deployed at scale, understanding why an agent takes a particular action becomes increasingly important for accountability and governance. However, existing research predominantly focuses on \textit{failure attribution} to localize explicit errors in unsuccessful trajectories, which is insufficient for explaining \textbf{the reason behind agent behaviors}. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel framework for \textbf{general agentic attribution}, designed to identify the internal factors driving agent actions regardless of the task outcome. Our framework operates hierarchically to manage the complexity of agent interactions. Specifically, at the \textit{component level}, we employ temporal likelihood dynamics to identify critical interaction steps; then at the \textit{sentence level}, we refine this localization using perturbation-based analysis to isolate the specific textual evidence. We validate our framework across a diverse suite of agentic scenarios, including standard tool use and subtle reliability risks like memory-induced bias. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed framework reliably pinpoints pivotal historical events and sentences behind the agent behavior, offering a critical step toward safer and more accountable agentic systems. Codes are available at https://github.com/AI45Lab/AgentDoG.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.15075v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] A Study of Adaptive Modeling Towards Robust Generalization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02780</link><description>arXiv:2602.02780v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) increasingly support reasoning over biomolecular structures, but most existing approaches remain modality-specific and rely on either sequence-style encodings or fixed-length connector tokens for structural inputs. These designs can under-expose explicit geometric cues and impose rigid fusion bottlenecks, leading to over-compression and poor token allocation as structural complexity grows. We present a unified all-atom framework that grounds language reasoning in geometric information while adaptively scaling structural tokens. The method first constructs variable-size structural patches on molecular graphs using an instruction-conditioned gating policy, enabling complexity-aware allocation of query tokens. It then refines the resulting patch tokens via cross-attention with modality embeddings and injects geometry-informed tokens into the language model to improve structure grounding and reduce structural hallucinations. Across diverse all-atom benchmarks, the proposed approach yields consistent gains in heterogeneous structure-grounded reasoning. An anonymized implementation is provided in the supplementary material.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.02780v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Vision-R1: Incentivizing Reasoning Capability in Multimodal Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.06749</link><description>arXiv:2503.06749v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: DeepSeek-R1-Zero has successfully demonstrated the emergence of reasoning capabilities in LLMs purely through Reinforcement Learning (RL). Inspired by this breakthrough, we explore how RL can be utilized to enhance the reasoning capability of MLLMs. However, direct training with RL struggles to activate complex reasoning capabilities such as questioning and reflection in MLLMs, due to the absence of substantial high-quality multimodal reasoning data. To address this issue, we propose the reasoning MLLM, Vision-R1, to improve multimodal reasoning capability. Specifically, we first construct a high-quality multimodal CoT dataset without human annotations by leveraging an existing MLLM and DeepSeek-R1 through modality bridging and data filtering to obtain a 200K multimodal CoT dataset, Vision-R1-cold dataset. It serves as cold-start initialization data for Vision-R1. To mitigate the optimization challenges caused by overthinking after cold start, we propose Progressive Thinking Suppression Training (PTST) strategy and employ Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) with the hard formatting result reward function to gradually refine the model's ability to learn correct and complex reasoning processes on a 10K multimodal math dataset. Comprehensive experiments show our model achieves an average improvement of $\sim$6% across various multimodal math reasoning benchmarks. Vision-R1-7B achieves a 73.5% accuracy on the widely used MathVista benchmark, which is only 0.4% lower than the leading reasoning model, OpenAI O1. Scaling up the amount of multimodal math data in the RL training, Vision-R1-32B and Vison-R1-72B achieves 76.4% and 78.2% MathVista benchmark scores, respectively. The datasets and code will be released in: https://github.com/Osilly/Vision-R1 .</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2503.06749v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] SelfReflect: Can LLMs Communicate Their Internal Answer Distribution?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.20295</link><description>arXiv:2505.20295v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The common approach to communicate a large language model's (LLM) uncertainty is to add a percentage number or a hedging word to its response. But is this all we can do? Instead of generating a single answer and then hedging it, an LLM that is fully transparent to the user needs to be able to reflect on its internal belief distribution and output a summary of all options it deems possible, and how likely they are. To test whether LLMs possess this capability, we develop the SelfReflect metric, an information-theoretic distance between a given summary and a distribution over answers. In interventional and human studies, we find that SelfReflect indicates even slight deviations, yielding a fine measure of faithfulness between a summary string and an LLM's actual internal distribution over answers. With SelfReflect, we make a resounding negative observation: modern LLMs are, across the board, incapable of revealing what they are uncertain about, neither through reasoning, nor chains-of-thoughts, nor explicit finetuning. However, we do find that LLMs are able to generate faithful summaries of their uncertainties if we help them by sampling multiple outputs and feeding them back into the context. This simple approach shines a light at the universal way of communicating LLM uncertainties whose future development the SelfReflect score enables. To support the development of this universal form of LLM uncertainties, we publish the code that implements our metric for arbitrary LLMs under https://github.com/apple/ml-selfreflect .</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2505.20295v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Dissecting the SWE-Bench Leaderboards: Profiling Submitters and Architectures of LLM- and Agent-Based Repair Systems</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.17208</link><description>arXiv:2506.17208v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: The rapid progress in Automated Program Repair (APR) has been driven by advances in AI, particularly large language models (LLMs) and agent-based systems. SWE-Bench is a recent benchmark designed to evaluate LLM-based repair systems using real issues and pull requests mined from 12 popular open-source Python repositories. Its public leaderboards -- SWE-Bench Lite and SWE-Bench Verified -- have become central platforms for tracking progress and comparing solutions. However, because the submission process does not require detailed documentation, the architectural design and origin of many solutions remain unclear. In this paper, we present the first comprehensive study of all submissions to the SWE-Bench Lite (79 entries) and Verified (99 entries) leaderboards, analyzing 80 unique approaches across dimensions such as submitter type, product availability, LLM usage, and system architecture. Our findings reveal the dominance of proprietary LLMs (especially Claude 3.5), the presence of both agentic and non-agentic designs, and a contributor base spanning from individual developers to large tech companies.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2506.17208v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] STACK: Adversarial Attacks on LLM Safeguard Pipelines</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.24068</link><description>arXiv:2506.24068v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Frontier AI developers are relying on layers of safeguards to protect against catastrophic misuse of AI systems. Anthropic and OpenAI guard their latest Opus 4 model and GPT-5 models using such defense pipelines, and other frontier developers including Google DeepMind pledge to soon deploy similar defenses. However, the security of such pipelines is unclear, with limited prior work evaluating or attacking these pipelines. We address this gap by developing and red-teaming an open-source defense pipeline. First, we find that a novel few-shot-prompted input and output classifier outperforms state-of-the-art open-weight safeguard model ShieldGemma across three attacks and two datasets, reducing the attack success rate (ASR) to 0% on the catastrophic misuse dataset ClearHarm. Second, we introduce a STaged AttaCK (STACK) procedure that achieves 71% ASR on ClearHarm in a black-box attack against the few-shot-prompted classifier pipeline. Finally, we also evaluate STACK in a transfer setting, achieving 33% ASR, providing initial evidence that it is feasible to design attacks with no access to the target pipeline. We conclude by suggesting specific mitigations that developers could use to thwart staged attacks.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2506.24068v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] CellForge: Agentic Design of Virtual Cell Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02276</link><description>arXiv:2508.02276v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Virtual cell modeling aims to predict cellular responses to diverse perturbations but faces challenges from biological complexity, multimodal data heterogeneity, and the need for interdisciplinary expertise. We introduce CellForge, a multi-agent framework that autonomously designs and synthesizes neural network architectures tailored to specific single-cell datasets and perturbation tasks. Given raw multi-omics data and task descriptions, CellForge discovers candidate architectures through collaborative reasoning among specialized agents, then generates executable implementations. Our core contribution is the framework itself: showing that multi-agent collaboration mechanisms - rather than manual human design or single-LLM prompting - can autonomously produce executable, high-quality computational methods. This approach goes beyond conventional hyperparameter tuning by enabling entirely new architectural components such as trajectory-aware encoders and perturbation diffusion modules to emerge from agentic deliberation. We evaluate CellForge on six datasets spanning gene knockouts, drug treatments, and cytokine stimulations across multiple modalities (scRNA-seq, scATAC-seq, CITE-seq). The results demonstrate that the models generated by CellForge are highly competitive with established baselines, while revealing systematic patterns of architectural innovation. CellForge highlights the scientific value of multi-agent frameworks: collaboration among specialized agents enables genuine methodological innovation and executable solutions that single agents or human experts cannot achieve. This represents a paradigm shift toward autonomous scientific method development in computational biology. Code is available at https://github.com/gersteinlab/CellForge.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2508.02276v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Real-Time Detection of Hallucinated Entities in Long-Form Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2509.03531</link><description>arXiv:2509.03531v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models are now routinely used in high-stakes applications where hallucinations can cause serious harm, such as medical consultations or legal advice. Existing hallucination detection methods, however, are impractical for real-world use, as they are either limited to short factual queries or require costly external verification. We present a cheap, scalable method for real-time identification of hallucinated tokens in long-form generations, and scale it effectively to 70B parameter models. Our approach targets entity-level hallucinations-e.g., fabricated names, dates, citations-rather than claim-level, thereby naturally mapping to token-level labels and enabling streaming detection. We develop an annotation methodology that leverages web search to annotate model responses with grounded labels indicating which tokens correspond to fabricated entities. This dataset enables us to train effective hallucination classifiers with simple and efficient methods such as linear probes. Evaluating across four model families, our classifiers consistently outperform baselines on long-form responses, including more expensive methods such as semantic entropy (e.g., AUC 0.90 vs 0.71 for Llama-3.3-70B), and are also an improvement in short-form question-answering settings. Despite being trained only to detect hallucinated entities, our probes effectively detect incorrect answers in mathematical reasoning tasks, indicating generalization beyond entities. While our annotation methodology is expensive, we find that annotated responses from one model can be used to train effective classifiers on other models; accordingly, we publicly release our datasets to facilitate reuse. Overall, our work suggests a promising new approach for scalable, real-world hallucination detection.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2509.03531v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] VibeCodeHPC: An Agent-Based Iterative Prompting Auto-Tuner for HPC Code Generation Using LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00031</link><description>arXiv:2510.00031v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose VibeCodeHPC, an automatic tuning system for HPC programs based on multi-agent LLMs for code generation. VibeCodeHPC tunes programs through multi-agent role allocation and iterative prompt refinement. We describe the system configuration with four roles: Project Manager (PM), System Engineer (SE), Programmer (PG), and Continuous Delivery (CD). We introduce dynamic agent deployment and activity monitoring functions to facilitate effective multi-agent collaboration. In our case study, we convert and optimize CPU-based matrix-matrix multiplication code written in C to GPU code using CUDA. The multi-agent configuration of VibeCodeHPC achieved higher-quality code generation per unit time compared to a solo-agent configuration. Additionally, the dynamic agent deployment and activity monitoring capabilities facilitated more effective identification of requirement violations and other issues.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00031v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] VisMem: Latent Vision Memory Unlocks Potential of Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11007</link><description>arXiv:2511.11007v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable success of Vision-Language Models (VLMs), their performance on a range of complex visual tasks is often hindered by a "visual processing bottleneck": a propensity to lose grounding in visual evidence and exhibit a deficit in contextualized visual experience during prolonged generation. Drawing inspiration from human cognitive memory theory, which distinguishes short-term visually-dominant memory and long-term semantically-dominant memory, we propose VisMem, a cognitively-aligned framework that equips VLMs with dynamic latent vision memories, a short-term module for fine-grained perceptual retention and a long-term module for abstract semantic consolidation. These memories are seamlessly invoked during inference, allowing VLMs to maintain both perceptual fidelity and semantic consistency across thinking and generation. Extensive experiments across diverse visual benchmarks for understanding, reasoning, and generation reveal that VisMem delivers a significant average performance boost of 11.0% relative to the vanilla model and outperforms all counterparts, establishing a new paradigm for latent-space memory enhancement. The code will be available: https://github.com/YU-deep/VisMem.git.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2511.11007v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] CARL: Focusing Agentic Reinforcement Learning on Critical Actions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04949</link><description>arXiv:2512.04949v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Agents capable of accomplishing complex tasks through multiple interactions with the environment have emerged as a popular research direction. However, in such multi-step settings, the conventional group-level policy optimization algorithm becomes suboptimal because of its underlying assumption that each action holds equal contribution, which deviates significantly from reality. Our analysis reveals that only a small fraction of actions are critical in determining the final outcome. Building on this insight, we propose CARL, a critical-action-focused reinforcement learning algorithm tailored for long-horizon agentic reasoning. CARL leverages entropy as a heuristic proxy for action criticality and achieves focused training by assigning rewards to high-criticality actions while excluding low-criticality actions from model updates, avoiding noisy credit assignment and redundant computation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CARL achieves both stronger performance and higher efficiency across diverse evaluation settings. The source code will be publicly available.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04949v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Learning to Discover at Test Time</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.16175</link><description>arXiv:2601.16175v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: How can we use AI to discover a new state of the art for a scientific problem? Prior work in test-time scaling, such as AlphaEvolve, performs search by prompting a frozen LLM. We perform reinforcement learning at test time, so the LLM can continue to train, but now with experience specific to the test problem. This form of continual learning is quite special, because its goal is to produce one great solution rather than many good ones on average, and to solve this very problem rather than generalize to other problems. Therefore, our learning objective and search subroutine are designed to prioritize the most promising solutions. We call this method Test-Time Training to Discover (TTT-Discover). Following prior work, we focus on problems with continuous rewards. We report results for every problem we attempted, across mathematics, GPU kernel engineering, algorithm design, and biology. TTT-Discover sets the new state of the art in almost all of them: (i) Erd\H{o}s' minimum overlap problem and an autocorrelation inequality; (ii) a GPUMode kernel competition (up to $2\times$ faster than prior art); (iii) past AtCoder algorithm competitions; and (iv) denoising problem in single-cell analysis. Our solutions are reviewed by experts or the organizers. All our results are achieved with an open model, OpenAI gpt-oss-120b, and can be reproduced with our publicly available code, in contrast to previous best results that required closed frontier models. Our test-time training runs are performed using Tinker, an API by Thinking Machines, with a cost of only a few hundred dollars per problem.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.16175v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] STELLAR: Structure-guided LLM Assertion Retrieval and Generation for Formal Verification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19903</link><description>arXiv:2601.19903v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Formal Verification (FV) relies on high-quality SystemVerilog Assertions (SVAs), but the manual writing process is slow and error-prone. Existing LLM-based approaches either generate assertions from scratch or ignore structural patterns in hardware designs and expert-crafted assertions. This paper presents STELLAR, the first framework that guides LLM-based SVA generation with structural similarity. STELLAR represents RTL blocks as AST structural fingerprints, retrieves structurally relevant (RTL, SVA) pairs from a knowledge base, and integrates them into structure-guided prompts. Experiments show that STELLAR achieves superior syntax correctness, stylistic alignment, and functional correctness, highlighting structure-aware retrieval as a promising direction for industrial FV.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.19903v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] SWE-Replay: Efficient Test-Time Scaling for Software Engineering Agents</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.22129</link><description>arXiv:2601.22129v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Test-time scaling has been widely adopted to enhance the capabilities of Large Language Model (LLM) agents in software engineering (SWE) tasks. However, the standard approach of repeatedly sampling trajectories from scratch is computationally expensive. While recent methods have attempted to mitigate costs using specialized value agents, they can suffer from model miscalibration and fail to generalize to modern agents that synthesize custom bash scripts as tools. In this paper, we introduce SWE-Replay, the first efficient and generalizable test-time scaling technique for modern agents without reliance on potentially noisy value estimates. SWE-Replay optimizes the scaling process by recycling trajectories from prior trials, dynamically choosing to either explore from scratch or exploit archived experience by branching at critical intermediate steps. This selection of intermediate steps is driven by the potential and reasoning significance of repository exploration, rather than external LLM-based quality estimates. Our evaluation shows that, on SWE-Bench Verified, SWE-Replay consistently outperforms naive scaling, reducing costs by up to 17.4% while maintaining or even improving performance by up to 3.8%. Further evaluation on SWE-Bench Pro and Multilingual validates the generalizability of SWE-Replay, establishing it as a robust foundation for efficient test-time scaling of software engineering agents.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.22129v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Joint Continual Learning of Local Language Models and Cloud Offloading Decisions with Budget Constraints</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.00166</link><description>arXiv:2602.00166v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Locally deployed Small Language Models (SLMs) must continually support diverse tasks under strict memory and computation constraints, making selective reliance on cloud Large Language Models (LLMs) unavoidable. Regulating cloud assistance during continual learning is challenging, as naive reward-based reinforcement learning often yields unstable offloading behavior and exacerbates catastrophic forgetting as task distributions shift. We propose DA-GRPO, a dual-advantage extension of Group Relative Policy Optimization that incorporates cloud-usage constraints directly into advantage computation, avoiding fixed reward shaping and external routing models. This design enables the local model to jointly learn task competence and collaboration behavior, allowing cloud requests to emerge naturally during post-training while respecting a prescribed assistance budget. Experiments on mathematical reasoning and code generation benchmarks show that DA-GRPO improves post-switch accuracy, substantially reduces forgetting, and maintains stable cloud usage compared to prior collaborative and routing-based approaches.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.00166v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI 2026] Prompt Augmentation Scales up GRPO Training on Mathematical Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03190</link><description>arXiv:2602.03190v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reinforcement learning algorithms such as group-relative policy optimization (GRPO) have demonstrated strong potential for improving the mathematical reasoning capabilities of large language models. However, prior work has consistently observed an entropy collapse phenomenon during reinforcement post-training, characterized by a monotonic decrease in policy entropy that ultimately leads to training instability and collapse. As a result, most existing approaches restrict training to short horizons (typically 5-20 epochs), limiting sustained exploration and hindering further policy improvement. In addition, nearly all prior work relies on a single, fixed reasoning prompt or template during training. In this work, we introduce prompt augmentation, a training strategy that instructs the model to generate reasoning traces under diverse templates and formats, thereby increasing rollout diversity. We show that, without a KL regularization term, prompt augmentation enables stable scaling of training duration under a fixed dataset and allows the model to tolerate low-entropy regimes without premature collapse. Empirically, a Qwen2.5-Math-1.5B model trained with prompt augmentation on the MATH Level 3-5 dataset achieves state-of-the-art performance, reaching 45.2 per-benchmark accuracy and 51.8 per-question accuracy on standard mathematical reasoning benchmarks, including AIME24, AMC, MATH500, Minerva, and OlympiadBench. The code and model checkpoints are available at https://github.com/wenquanlu/prompt-augmentation-GRPO.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.03190v2</guid></item><item><title>[TSE 2026] The Power of Small LLMs: A Multi-Agent for Code Generation via Dynamic Precaution Tuning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TSE.2025.3632508</link><description>Authors: Junfeng Zhang, Jinzhi Liao, Jiuyang Tang, Xiang Zhao 0002
Venue: IEEE Trans. Software Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tse</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tse/ZhangLTZ26</guid></item><item><title>[TSE 2026] Shield Broken: Black-Box Adversarial Attacks on LLM-Based Vulnerability Detectors.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TSE.2025.3638998</link><description>Authors: Yuan Jiang, Shan Huang, Christoph Treude, Xiaohong Su, Tiantian Wang 0001
Venue: IEEE Trans. Software Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tse</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tse/JiangHTSW26</guid></item><item><title>[TOSEM 2026] PonziHunter: Hunting Ethereum Ponzi Contract via Static Analysis and Contrastive Learning on the Bytecode Level</title><link>https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3735971?af=R</link><description>ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology, Volume 35, Issue 2, Page 1-21, February 2026. &lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Association for Computing Machinery: ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology: Table of Contents</author><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:18:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3735971?af=R</guid></item><item><title>[TOSEM 2026] Abundant Modalities Offer More Nutrients: Multi-Modal-Based Function-Level Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3731557?af=R</link><description>ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology, Volume 35, Issue 2, Page 1-31, February 2026. &lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Association for Computing Machinery: ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology: Table of Contents</author><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 02:02:29 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3731557?af=R</guid></item><item><title>[TDSC 2025] HgtJIT: Just-in-Time Vulnerability Detection Based on Heterogeneous Graph Transformer.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TDSC.2025.3586669</link><description>Authors: Xiaobing Sun 0001, Mingxuan Zhou, Sicong Cao, Xiaoxue Wu 0001, Lili Bo, Di Wu 0050, Bin Li 0006, Yang Xiang 0001
Venue: IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput.
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tdsc</author><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tdsc/SunZCWBWLX25</guid></item><item><title>[TDSC 2025] Tacco: A Framework for Ensuring the Security of Real-World TEEs via Formal Verification.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TDSC.2025.3594594</link><description>Authors: Jilin Hu, Yongwang Zhao, Shuangquan Pan, Zuohua Ding, Kui Ren 0001
Venue: IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput.
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tdsc</author><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tdsc/HuZPDR25</guid></item><item><title>[TDSC 2025] Real-World Code Vulnerability Detection Framework: From Data Preprocessing to Multi-Feature Fusion Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TDSC.2025.3601228</link><description>Authors: Jixian Zhang, Qingfeng Du, Sheng Li, Zhongda Lu, Ting He, Chengwei Liu
Venue: IEEE Trans. Dependable Secur. Comput.
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tdsc</author><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tdsc/ZhangDLLHL25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Autonomous Vulnerability Analysis, Triaging, and Repair: A Historical Perspective.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3748270</link><description>Authors: Giovanni Vigna
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Vigna25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] SyzSpec: Specification Generation for Linux Kernel Fuzzing via Under-Constrained Symbolic Execution.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3744811</link><description>Authors: Yu Hao 0006, Juefei Pu, Xingyu Li, Zhiyun Qian, Ardalan Amiri Sani
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/0006PLQS25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Protocols to Code: Formal Verification of a Secure Next-Generation Internet Router.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765104</link><description>Authors: Joo C. Pereira, Tobias Klenze, Sofia Giampietro, Markus Limbeck, Dionysios Spiliopoulos, Felix A. Wolf, Marco Eilers, Christoph Sprenger 0001, David A. Basin, Peter Mller 0001, Adrian Perrig
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/PereiraKGLSWE0B25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Security-Aware Sensor Fusion with MATE: the Multi-Agent Trust Estimator.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765193</link><description>Authors: R. Spencer Hallyburton, Miroslav Pajic
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/HallyburtonP25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] ZVDetector: State-Guided Vulnerability Detection System for Zigbee Devices.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765035</link><description>Authors: Hai Lin, Chenglong Li 0006, Jiahai Yang 0001, Zhiliang Wang, Jiaqi Bai
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Lin00WB25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Empirical Security Analysis of Software-based Fault Isolation through Controlled Fault Injection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765027</link><description>Authors: Nils Bars, Lukas Bernhard, Moritz Schloegel, Thorsten Holz
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/BarsBSH25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Security Analysis of Privately Verifiable Privacy Pass.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765172</link><description>Authors: Konrad Hanff, Anja Lehmann, Cavit zbay
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/HanffLO25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Give LLMs a Security Course: Securing Retrieval-Augmented Code Generation via Knowledge Injection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765049</link><description>Authors: Bo Lin 0011, Shangwen Wang, Yihao Qin, Liqian Chen, Xiaoguang Mao
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/LinWQCM25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Augmenting Search-based Program Synthesis with Local Inference Rules to Improve Black-box Deobfuscation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765134</link><description>Authors: Vidal Attias, Nicolas Bellec 0001, Grgoire Menguy, Sbastien Bardin, Jean-Yves Marion
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Attias0MBM25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Poster: Leveraging Large Language Models to Effectively and Efficiently Identify Vulnerability Patches for WordPress Plugins.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3760720</link><description>Authors: Xue Leng, Hai Zhang, Tiantian Zhu 0001, Jianguo Sun
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/LengZZS25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] Poster: LogCraft: Crafting CVE-Aware Synthetic Worlds (Logs).</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3760736</link><description>Authors: Kai-Xian Wong, Chan-Jien Tan, Yi-Ting Huang, Ying-Ren Guo, Yu-Zih Jheng, Guo-Wei Wong, Meng Chang Chen
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/WongTHGJWC25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] AI-Augmented Static Analysis: Bridging Heuristics and Completeness for Practical Reverse Engineering.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765565</link><description>Authors: Monika Santra
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Santra25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS 2025] LAMPS '25: ACM CCS Workshop on Large AI Systems and Models with Privacy and Security Analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3767670</link><description>Authors: Kwok-Yan Lam, Xiaoning Liu 0002, Derui Wang, Bo Li 0026, Wenyuan Xu 0001, Jieshan Chen, Minhui Xue 0001, Xingliang Yuan, Guangdong Bai, Shuo Wang 0012
Venue: CCS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Lam0W0XC0YBW25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Malicious LLM-Based Conversational AI Makes Users Reveal Personal Information.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zhan</link><description>Authors: Xiao Zhan, Juan Carlos Carrillo, William Seymour, Jose Such
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ZhanCSS25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] HateBench: Benchmarking Hate Speech Detectors on LLM-Generated Content and Hate Campaigns.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/shen</link><description>Authors: Xinyue Shen 0001, Yixin Wu 0001, Yiting Qu, Michael Backes 0001, Savvas Zannettou, Yang Zhang 0016
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/00010Q0Z025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Mind the Inconspicuous: Revealing the Hidden Weakness in Aligned LLMs' Refusal Boundaries.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/yu-jiahao</link><description>Authors: Jiahao Yu 0001, Haozheng Luo, Jerry Yao-Chieh Hu, Yan Chen 0004, Wenbo Guo 0002, Han Liu 0001, Xinyu Xing 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/0001LHC00025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Game of Arrows: On the (In-)Security of Weight Obfuscation for On-Device TEE-Shielded LLM Partition Algorithms.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/wang-pengli</link><description>Authors: Pengli Wang, Bingyou Dong, Yifeng Cai, Zheng Zhang, Junlin Liu, Huanran Xue, Ye Wu, Yao Zhang, Ziqi Zhang
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/WangDCZLXWZZ25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Activation Approximations Can Incur Safety Vulnerabilities in Aligned LLMs: Comprehensive Analysis and Defense.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zhang-jiawen</link><description>Authors: Jiawen Zhang 0005, Kejia Chen 0007, Lipeng He, Jian Lou 0001, Dan Li 0032, Zunlei Feng, Mingli Song, Jian Liu 0012, Kui Ren 0001, Xiaohu Yang 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/00050H0LFS00025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] LLMxCPG: Context-Aware Vulnerability Detection Through Code Property Graph-Guided Large Language Models.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/lekssays</link><description>Authors: Ahmed Lekssays, Hamza Mouhcine, Khang Tran, Ting Yu 0001, Issa Khalil
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/LekssaysMT0K25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Unlocking the Power of Differentially Private Zeroth-order Optimization for Fine-tuning LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/bao-ergute</link><description>Authors: Ergute Bao, Yangfan Jiang 0001, Fei Wei, Xiaokui Xiao, Zitao Li, Yaliang Li, Bolin Ding
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Bao0WXLLD25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Depth Gives a False Sense of Privacy: LLM Internal States Inversion.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/dong-tian</link><description>Authors: Tian Dong, Yan Meng 0001, Shaofeng Li 0001, Guoxing Chen, Zhen Liu 0008, Haojin Zhu
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Dong00C0Z25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Evaluating LLM-based Personal Information Extraction and Countermeasures.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/liu-yupei</link><description>Authors: Yupei Liu, Yuqi Jia, Jinyuan Jia 0001, Neil Zhenqiang Gong
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/LiuJ0G25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Synthetic Artifact Auditing: Tracing LLM-Generated Synthetic Data Usage in Downstream Applications.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/wu-yixin-auditing</link><description>Authors: Yixin Wu 0001, Ziqing Yang 0002, Yun Shen, Michael Backes 0001, Yang Zhang 0016
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/00010S0025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] When LLMs Go Online: The Emerging Threat of Web-Enabled LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/kim-hanna</link><description>Authors: Hanna Kim, Minkyoo Song, Seung Ho Na, Seungwon Shin 0001, Kimin Lee
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/KimSN0L25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] zkGPT: An Efficient Non-interactive Zero-knowledge Proof Framework for LLM Inference.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/qu-zkgpt</link><description>Authors: Wenjie Qu 0001, Yijun Sun, Xuanming Liu, Tao Lu, Yanpei Guo, Kai Chen, Jiaheng Zhang
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/0001SLLGCZ25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] TwinBreak: Jailbreaking LLM Security Alignments based on Twin Prompts.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/krauss</link><description>Authors: Torsten Krau, Hamid Dashtbani, Alexandra Dmitrienko
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/KraussDD25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Exploiting Task-Level Vulnerabilities: An Automatic Jailbreak Attack and Defense Benchmarking for LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zhang-lan</link><description>Authors: Lan Zhang 0002, Xinben Gao, Liuyi Yao, Jinke Song, Yaliang Li
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/0002GYSL25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] PAPILLON: Efficient and Stealthy Fuzz Testing-Powered Jailbreaks for LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/gong-xueluan</link><description>Authors: Xueluan Gong, Mingzhe Li, Yilin Zhang, Fengyuan Ran, Chen Chen, Yanjiao Chen, Qian Wang 0002, Kwok-Yan Lam
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/GongLZRCC0L25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Great, Now Write an Article About That: The Crescendo Multi-Turn LLM Jailbreak Attack.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/russinovich</link><description>Authors: Mark Russinovich, Ahmed Salem 0001, Ronen Eldan
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Russinovich0E25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] SelfDefend: LLMs Can Defend Themselves against Jailbreaking in a Practical Manner.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/wang-xunguang</link><description>Authors: Xunguang Wang, Daoyuan Wu, Zhenlan Ji, Zongjie Li, Pingchuan Ma 0004, Shuai Wang 0011, Yingjiu Li, Yang Liu 0003, Ning Liu, Juergen Rahmel
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/WangWJL00L0LR25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Confusing Value with Enumeration: Studying the Use of CVEs in Academia.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/schloegel</link><description>Authors: Moritz Schloegel, Daniel Klischies, Simon Koch 0001, David Klein 0001, Lukas Gerlach 0001, Malte Wessels, Leon Trampert, Martin Johns, Mathy Vanhoef, Michael Schwarz 0001, Thorsten Holz, Jo Van Bulck
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/SchloegelK000WT25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] We Have a Package for You! A Comprehensive Analysis of Package Hallucinations by Code Generating LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/spracklen</link><description>Authors: Joseph Spracklen, Raveen Wijewickrama, A. H. M. Nazmus Sakib, Anindya Maiti, Bimal Viswanath, Murtuza Jadliwala
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/SpracklenWSMV25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Make Agent Defeat Agent: Automatic Detection of Taint-Style Vulnerabilities in LLM-based Agents.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/liu-fengyu</link><description>Authors: Fengyu Liu, Yuan Zhang 0009, Jiaqi Luo, Jiarun Dai, Tian Chen, Letian Yuan, Zhengmin Yu, Youkun Shi, Ke Li, Chengyuan Zhou, Hao Chen 0003, Min Yang 0002
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Liu0LDCYYSLZ0025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Machine Against the RAG: Jamming Retrieval-Augmented Generation with Blocker Documents.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/shafran</link><description>Authors: Avital Shafran, Roei Schuster, Vitaly Shmatikov
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ShafranSS25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Topic-FlipRAG: Topic-Orientated Adversarial Opinion Manipulation Attacks to Retrieval-Augmented Generation Models.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/gong-yuyang</link><description>Authors: Yuyang Gong, Zhuo Chen, Jiawei Liu 0002, Miaokun Chen, Fengchang Yu, Wei Lu 0019, XiaoFeng Wang 0001, Xiaozhong Liu
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/GongC0CY00L25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] PoisonedRAG: Knowledge Corruption Attacks to Retrieval-Augmented Generation of Large Language Models.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zou-poisonedrag</link><description>Authors: Wei Zou, Runpeng Geng, Binghui Wang, Jinyuan Jia 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ZouGW025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] TracLLM: A Generic Framework for Attributing Long Context LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/wang-yanting</link><description>Authors: Yanting Wang 0001, Wei Zou, Runpeng Geng, Jinyuan Jia 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/WangZG025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Logs In, Patches Out: Automated Vulnerability Repair via Tree-of-Thought LLM Analysis.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/kim-youngjoon</link><description>Authors: Youngjoon Kim 0001, Sunguk Shin 0001, Hyoungshick Kim, Jiwon Yoon 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Kim0KY25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] APPATCH: Automated Adaptive Prompting Large Language Models for Real-World Software Vulnerability Patching.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/nong</link><description>Authors: Yu Nong, Haoran Yang, Long Cheng 0005, Hongxin Hu, Haipeng Cai
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/NongY0HC25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Whispering Under the Eaves: Protecting User Privacy Against Commercial and LLM-powered Automatic Speech Recognition Systems.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/jin-weifei</link><description>Authors: Weifei Jin, Yuxin Cao, Junjie Su, Derui Wang, Yedi Zhang, Minhui Xue 0001, Jie Hao 0001, Jin Song Dong 0001, Yixian Yang
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/JinCSWZ00DY25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] A Thorough Security Analysis of BLE Proximity Tracking Protocols.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/liu-xiaofeng</link><description>Authors: Xiaofeng Liu 0013, Chaoshun Zuo, Qinsheng Hou, Pengcheng Ren, Jianliang Wu 0002, Qingchuan Zhao, Shanqing Guo
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/0013ZHR0ZG25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] SCASE: Automated Secret Recovery via Side-Channel-Assisted Symbolic Execution.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/weber</link><description>Authors: Daniel Weber 0007, Lukas Gerlach 0001, Leon Trampert, Youheng L, Jo Van Bulck, Michael Schwarz 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/00070TLB025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] EchoLLM: LLM-Augmented Acoustic Eavesdropping Attack on Bone Conduction Headphones with mmWave Radar.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/yao-xin</link><description>Authors: Xin Yao 0002, Kecheng Huang, Yimin Chen 0004, Jiawei Guo, Jie Tang, Ming Zhao 0007
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/0002H0GT025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Exploring User Security and Privacy Attitudes and Concerns Toward the Use of General-Purpose LLM Chatbots for Mental Health.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/kwesi</link><description>Authors: Jabari Kwesi, Jiaxun Cao, Riya Manchanda, Pardis Emami Naeini
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/KwesiCMN25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] ELFuzz: Efficient Input Generation via LLM-driven Synthesis Over Fuzzer Space.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/chen-chuyang</link><description>Authors: Chuyang Chen 0001, Brendan Dolan-Gavitt, Zhiqiang Lin 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ChenDC25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Hybrid Language Processor Fuzzing via LLM-Based Constraint Solving.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/yang-yupeng</link><description>Authors: Yupeng Yang, Shenglong Yao, Jizhou Chen, Wenke Lee
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/YangYCL25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Evaluating Privacy Policies under Modern Privacy Laws At Scale: An LLM-Based Automated Approach.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/xie</link><description>Authors: Qinge Xie, Karthik Ramakrishnan, Frank Li 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/XieR025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] From Alarms to Real Bugs: Multi-target Multi-step Directed Greybox Fuzzing for Static Analysis Result Verification.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/bao-andrew</link><description>Authors: Andrew Bao, Wenjia Zhao, Yanhao Wang, Yueqiang Cheng, Stephen McCamant, Pen-Chung Yew
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/BaoZWCMY25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Low-Cost and Comprehensive Non-textual Input Fuzzing with LLM-Synthesized Input Generators.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zhang-kunpeng</link><description>Authors: Kunpeng Zhang, Zongjie Li, Daoyuan Wu, Shuai Wang 0011, Xin Xia 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ZhangLW0025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] A Comprehensive Formal Security Analysis of OPC UA.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/diemunsch</link><description>Authors: Vincent Diemunsch, Lucca Hirschi, Steve Kremer
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/DiemunschHK25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Unsafe LLM-Based Search: Quantitative Analysis and Mitigation of Safety Risks in AI Web Search.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/luo-zeren</link><description>Authors: Zeren Luo, Zifan Peng, Yule Liu, Zhen Sun 0001, Mingchen Li, Jingyi Zheng, Xinlei He 0001
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/LuoPL0LZ025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Cloak, Honey, Trap: Proactive Defenses Against LLM Agents.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/ayzenshteyn</link><description>Authors: Daniel Ayzenshteyn, Roy Weiss, Yisroel Mirsky
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/AyzenshteynWM25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] SOFT: Selective Data Obfuscation for Protecting LLM Fine-tuning against Membership Inference Attacks.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/zhang-kaiyuan</link><description>Authors: Kaiyuan Zhang 0002, Siyuan Cheng 0005, Hanxi Guo, Yuetian Chen, Zian Su, Shengwei An, Yuntao Du 0002, Charles Fleming, Ashish Kundu, Xiangyu Zhang 0001, Ninghui Li
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/00020GCSA0FK0L25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Effective PII Extraction from LLMs through Augmented Few-Shot Learning.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/cheng-shuai</link><description>Authors: Shuai Cheng, Shu Meng, Haitao Xu 0002, Haoran Zhang, Shuai Hao 0001, Chuan Yue, Wenrui Ma, Meng Han, Fan Zhang 0010, Zhao Li 0007
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/ChengM0ZHYMHZL25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] PrivacyXray: Detecting Privacy Breaches in LLMs through Semantic Consistency and Probability Certainty.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/he-jinwen</link><description>Authors: Jinwen He, Yiyang Lu, Zijin Lin, Kai Chen 0012, Yue Zhao 0018
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/HeLL0025</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] ZIPPER: Static Taint Analysis for PHP Applications with Precision and Efficiency.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/wang-xinyi</link><description>Authors: Xinyi Wang 0013, Yeting Li, Jie Lu 0009, Shizhe Cui, Chenghang Shi, Qin Mai, Yunpei Zhang, Yang Xiao 0011, Feng Li 0045, Wei Huo
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/WangLLCSMZ00H25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec 2025] Effective Directed Fuzzing with Hierarchical Scheduling for Web Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/lin-zihan</link><description>Authors: Zihan Lin, Yuan Zhang 0009, Jiarun Dai, Xinyou Huang, Bocheng Xiang, Guangliang Yang 0001, Letian Yuan, Lei Zhang 0096, Tian Chen, Min Yang 0002
Venue: USENIX Security Symposium
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Lin0DHX0Y0C025</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] GPTVD: vulnerability detection and analysis method based on LLM's chain of thoughts.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00550-4</link><description>Authors: Yinan Chen, Yuan Huang, Xiangping Chen, Pengfei Shen, Lei Yun
Venue: Autom. Softw. Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/ChenHCSY26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] HMF: Enhancing reentrancy vulnerability detection and repair with a hybrid model framework.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00546-0</link><description>Authors: Mengliang Li, Qiang Shen, Xiaoxue Ren, Han Fu, Zhuo Li 0014, Jianling Sun
Venue: Autom. Softw. Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/LiSRFLS26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Graph neural networks for precise bug localization through structural program analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00556-y</link><description>Authors: Leila Yousofvand, Seyfollah Soleimani, Vahid Rafe, Amin Nikanjam
Venue: Autom. Softw. Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/YousofvandSRN26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] ByteEye: A smart contract vulnerability detection framework at bytecode level with graph neural networks.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00559-9</link><description>Authors: Jinni Yang, Shuang Liu 0007, Surong Dai, Yaozheng Fang, Kunpeng Xie, Ye Lu 0004
Venue: Autom. Softw. Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/YangLDFXL26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] SPVR: syntax-to-prompt vulnerability repair based on large language models.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00579-5</link><description>Authors: Ruoke Wang, Zongjie Li, Cuiyun Gao, Chaozheng Wang, Yang Xiao, Xuan Wang
Venue: Autom. Softw. Eng.
Year: 2026</description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/WangLGWXW26</guid></item><item><title>[SOSP 2025] KNighter: Transforming Static Analysis with LLM-Synthesized Checkers.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3731569.3764827</link><description>Authors: Chenyuan Yang, Zijie Zhao, Zichen Xie, Haoyu Li, Lingming Zhang 0001
Venue: SOSP
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/sosp</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/sosp/YangZXLZ25</guid></item><item><title>[ACL 2025] Learning Auxiliary Tasks Improves Reference-Free Hallucination Detection in Open-Domain Long-Form Generation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.18653/v1/2025.acl-short.93</link><description>Authors: Chengwei Qin, Wenxuan Zhou, Karthik Abinav Sankararaman, Nanshu Wang, Tengyu Xu, Alexander Radovic, Eryk Helenowski, Arya Talebzadeh, Aditya Tayade, Sinong Wang, Shafiq Joty, Han Fang, Hao Ma 0001
Venue: ACL (2)
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acl</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acl/QinZSWXRHTTWJF025</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] AriGraph: Learning Knowledge Graph World Models with Episodic Memory for LLM Agents.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/2</link><description>Authors: Petr Anokhin, Nikita Semenov, Artyom Y. Sorokin, Dmitry Evseev, Andrey Kravchenko, Mikhail Burtsev 0001, Evgeny Burnaev
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/AnokhinSSEK0B25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] Relational Decomposition for Program Synthesis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/504</link><description>Authors: Cline Hocquette, Andrew Cropper
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/HocquetteC25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] POLO: An LLM-Powered Project-Level Code Performance Optimization Framework.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/814</link><description>Authors: Jiameng Bai, Ruoyi Xu, Sai Wu, Dingyu Yang, Junbo Zhao 0002, Gang Chen 0001
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/BaiXWY0025</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] APIMig: A Project-Level Cross-Multi-Version API Migration Framework Based on Evolution Knowledge Graph.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/829</link><description>Authors: Li Kuang, Qi Xie, Haiyang Yang, Yang Yang, Xiang Wei, HaoYue Kang, Yingjie Xia
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/KuangXYYWKX25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] Can We Translate Code Better with LLMs and Call Graph Analysis?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/848</link><description>Authors: Yang Luo
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/Luo25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] SecV: LLM-based Secure Verilog Generation with Clue-Guided Exploration on Hardware-CWE Knowledge Graph.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/895</link><description>Authors: Fanghao Fan, Yingjie Xia, Li Kuang
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/FanXK25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] Learn to Think: Bootstrapping LLM Logic Through Graph Representation Learning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/896</link><description>Authors: Hang Gao 0004, Chenhao Zhang, Tie Wang, Junsuo Zhao, Fengge Wu, Changwen Zheng, Huaping Liu 0001
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/0004ZWZWZ025</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] SRA-MCTS: Self-driven Reasoning Augmentation with Monte Carlo Tree Search for Code Generation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/965</link><description>Authors: Bin Xu, Yiguan Lin, Yinghao Li, Yang Gao
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/XuLLG25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] The Graph's Apprentice: Teaching an LLM Low-Level Knowledge for Circuit Quality Estimation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/1033</link><description>Authors: Reza Moravej, Saurabh Bodhe, Zhanguang Zhang, Didier Chtelat, Dimitrios Tsaras, Yingxue Zhang 0001, Hui-Ling Zhen, Jianye Hao, Mingxuan Yuan
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/MoravejBZCT0ZHY25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] AI-Assisted Triage and Decision Support of Head and Neck Cancer Screening and Diagnosis in Low-Resourced Settings.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/1087</link><description>Authors: Min Hun Lee, Sean Shao Wei Lam, Shaun Xin Hong Liew, Michael Dorosan, Nicholas Graves, Jonas Karlstrm, Hiang Khoon Tan, Walter Tsong Lee
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/LeeLLDGKTL25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI 2025] GE-Chat: A Graph Enhanced RAG Framework for Evidential Response Generation of LLMs.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/1256</link><description>Authors: Longchao Da, Parth Mitesh Shah, Kuanru Liou, Jiaxing Zhang 0002, Hua Wei 0001
Venue: IJCAI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/DaSLZ025</guid></item><item><title>[EuroS&amp;P 2025] Mitigating Information Leakage in Large Language Models: Evaluating the Impact of Code Obfuscation on Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/EuroSPW67616.2025.00007</link><description>Authors: Beng Glay, Cemal Yilmaz 0001
Venue: EuroS&amp;amp;P (Workshops)
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/eurosp</author><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/eurosp/GulayY25</guid></item><item><title>[EuroS&amp;P 2025] CFA-Bench: Cybersecurity Forensic Llm Agent Benchmark and Testing.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/EuroSPW67616.2025.00031</link><description>Authors: Francesco De Santis, Kai Huang, Rodolfo V. Valentim, Danilo Giordano, Marco Mellia, Zied Ben-Houidi, Dario Rossi 0001
Venue: EuroS&amp;amp;P (Workshops)
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/eurosp</author><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/eurosp/SantisHVGMBR25</guid></item><item><title>[S&amp;P 2025] Code Vulnerability Repair with Large Language Model Using Context-Aware Prompt Tuning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/SPW67851.2025.00040</link><description>Authors: Arshiya Khan, Guannan Liu, Xing Gao
Venue: SP (Workshops)
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/sp</author><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/sp/KhanLG25</guid></item><item><title>[OSDI 2025] Paralegal: Practical Static Analysis for Privacy Bugs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/osdi25/presentation/adam</link><description>Authors: Justus Adam, Carolyn Zech, Livia Zhu, Sreshtaa Rajesh, Nathan Harbison, Mithi Jethwa, Will Crichton, Shriram Krishnamurthi, Malte Schwarzkopf
Venue: OSDI
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/osdi</author><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/osdi/AdamZZRHJCKS25</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA 2025] TBFV4J: An Automated Testing-Based Formal Verification Tool for Java.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3731740</link><description>Authors: Ai Liu, Yang Liu 0003, Shaoying Liu
Venue: ISSTA Companion
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/LiuLL25</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA 2025] Revisiting the Combination of Static Analysis Error Traces and Dynamic Symbolic Execution: A Potential Approach for True Positive Confirmation (Registered Report).</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3731720</link><description>Authors: Yihua Xu, Chengyu Zhang 0001, Geguang Pu
Venue: ISSTA Companion
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/Xu0P25</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA 2025] A Preliminary Study of Large Language Models for Multilingual Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3731746</link><description>Authors: Junji Yu, Honglin Shu, Michael Fu, Dong Wang 0044, Chakkrit Tantithamthavorn, Yasutaka Kamei, Junjie Chen 0003
Venue: ISSTA Companion
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/YuSF0TK025</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Diffusion On Syntax Trees For Program Synthesis.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=wN3KaUXA5X</link><description>Authors: Shreyas Kapur, Erik Jenner, Stuart Russell 0001
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/KapurJ025</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] MathCoder2: Better Math Reasoning from Continued Pretraining on Model-translated Mathematical Code.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=1Iuw1jcIrf</link><description>Authors: Zimu Lu, Aojun Zhou, Ke Wang 0036, Houxing Ren, Weikang Shi, Junting Pan, Mingjie Zhan, Hongsheng Li 0001
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/LuZ0RSPZL25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] EditRoom: LLM-parameterized Graph Diffusion for Composable 3D Room Layout Editing.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=Y2Dh8rWwlb</link><description>Authors: Kaizhi Zheng, Xiaotong Chen, Xuehai He, Jing Gu, Linjie Li, Zhengyuan Yang, Kevin Lin, Jianfeng Wang, Lijuan Wang, Xin Eric Wang
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ZhengCHGLYLWWW25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] SWE-bench Multimodal: Do AI Systems Generalize to Visual Software Domains?</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=riTiq3i21b</link><description>Authors: John Yang 0002, Carlos E. Jimenez, Alex L. Zhang, Kilian Lieret, Joyce Yang, Xindi Wu, Ori Press, Niklas Muennighoff, Gabriel Synnaeve, Karthik R. Narasimhan, Diyi Yang, Sida Wang 0001, Ofir Press
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/YangJZLYWPMSNY025</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] GraphEval: A Lightweight Graph-Based LLM Framework for Idea Evaluation.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=5RUM1aIdok</link><description>Authors: Tao Feng, Yihang Sun, Jiaxuan You
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/FengSY25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] GraphRouter: A Graph-based Router for LLM Selections.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=eU39PDsZtT</link><description>Authors: Tao Feng, Yanzhen Shen, Jiaxuan You
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/FengSY25a</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Unveiling the Magic of Code Reasoning through Hypothesis Decomposition and Amendment.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=kN25ggeq1J</link><description>Authors: Yuze Zhao, Tianyun Ji, Wenjun Feng, Zhenya Huang, Qi Liu 0003, Zhiding Liu, Yixiao Ma, Kai Zhang 0038, Enhong Chen
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ZhaoJFH0LM0C25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] CodeMMLU: A Multi-Task Benchmark for Assessing Code Understanding &amp; Reasoning Capabilities of CodeLLMs.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=CahIEKCu5Q</link><description>Authors: Dung Manh Nguyen, Thang Chau Phan, Nam Le Hai, Tien-Thong Doan, Nam V. Nguyen 0001, Quang Pham, Nghi D. Q. Bui
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/NguyenPHDNPB25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Steering Large Language Models between Code Execution and Textual Reasoning.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=5X5Z7Ffrjb</link><description>Authors: Yongchao Chen, Harsh Jhamtani, Srinagesh Sharma, Chuchu Fan, Chi Wang
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ChenJSFW25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] RepoGraph: Enhancing AI Software Engineering with Repository-level Code Graph.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=dw9VUsSHGB</link><description>Authors: Siru Ouyang, Wenhao Yu 0002, Kaixin Ma, Zilin Xiao, Zhihan Zhang 0001, Mengzhao Jia, Jiawei Han 0001, Hongming Zhang 0009, Dong Yu 0001
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/Ouyang0MX0J00025</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Agent Security Bench (ASB): Formalizing and Benchmarking Attacks and Defenses in LLM-based Agents.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=V4y0CpX4hK</link><description>Authors: Hanrong Zhang, Jingyuan Huang, Kai Mei, Yifei Yao, Zhenting Wang, Chenlu Zhan, Hongwei Wang 0001, Yongfeng Zhang 0003
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ZhangHMYWZWZ25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Enhancing Graph Of Thought: Enhancing Prompts with LLM Rationales and Dynamic Temperature Control.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=l32IrJtpOP</link><description>Authors: Sunguk Shin 0001, Youngjoon Kim 0001
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ShinK25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] IRIS: LLM-Assisted Static Analysis for Detecting Security Vulnerabilities.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=9LdJDU7E91</link><description>Authors: Ziyang Li, Saikat Dutta 0001, Mayur Naik
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/Li0N25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] RefactorBench: Evaluating Stateful Reasoning in Language Agents Through Code.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=NiNIthntx7</link><description>Authors: Dhruv Gautam, Spandan Garg, Jinu Jang, Neel Sundaresan, Roshanak Zilouchian Moghaddam
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/GautamGJSM25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] CodePlan: Unlocking Reasoning Potential in Large Language Models by Scaling Code-form Planning.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=dCPF1wlqj8</link><description>Authors: Jiaxin Wen, Jian Guan 0002, Hongning Wang, Wei Wu 0014, Minlie Huang
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/Wen0W0H25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] Safety Layers in Aligned Large Language Models: The Key to LLM Security.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=kUH1yPMAn7</link><description>Authors: Shen Li, Liuyi Yao, Lan Zhang 0002, Yaliang Li
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/LiY0L25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] HaDeMiF: Hallucination Detection and Mitigation in Large Language Models.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=VwOYxPScxB</link><description>Authors: Xiaoling Zhou, Mingjie Zhang, Zhemg Lee, Wei Ye 0004, Shikun Zhang
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/ZhouZL0Z25</guid></item><item><title>[ICLR 2025] ChartMimic: Evaluating LMM's Cross-Modal Reasoning Capability via Chart-to-Code Generation.</title><link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=sGpCzsfd1K</link><description>Authors: Cheng Yang 0002, Chufan Shi, Yaxin Liu, Bo Shui, Junjie Wang 0011, Mohan Jing, Linran Xu, Xinyu Zhu, Siheng Li, Yuxiang Zhang, Gongye Liu, Xiaomei Nie, Deng Cai 0002, Yujiu Yang 0001
Venue: ICLR
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/iclr</author><pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/iclr/0002SLS0JXZLZLN25</guid></item><item><title>[ACSAC 2025] Learning to Unfix: Towards ML Robustness in Vulnerability Detection via Structure-Aware Code Generation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ACSACW65225.2024.00014</link><description>Authors: Muhammad Fakhrur Rozi, Takeshi Takahashi 0001
Venue: ACSAC Workshops
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acsac</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acsac/Rozi024</guid></item><item><title>[ACSAC 2025] AdVul: Adversarial Attack against ML-based Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ACSACW65225.2024.00018</link><description>Authors: Marina Katoh, Weiping Pei, Youye Xie
Venue: ACSAC Workshops
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acsac</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acsac/KatohPX24</guid></item><item><title>[ACSAC 2025] Software Vulnerability Detection Using LLM: Does Additional Information Help?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ACSACW65225.2024.00031</link><description>Authors: Samiha Shimmi, Yash Saini, Mark Schaefer, Hamed Okhravi, Mona Rahimi
Venue: ACSAC Workshops
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acsac</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acsac/ShimmiSSOR24</guid></item><item><title>[ACSAC 2025] Automated Vulnerability Detection in Smart Contracts using Control Flow Graphs and Machine Learning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ACSACW65225.2024.00037</link><description>Authors: Charles Lohest, Samy Bettaieb, Axel Legay
Venue: ACSAC Workshops
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acsac</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acsac/LohestBL24</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS 2025] Generating API Parameter Security Rules with LLM for API Misuse Detection.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/generating-api-parameter-security-rules-with-llm-for-api-misuse-detection/</link><description>Authors: Jinghua Liu, Yi Yang 0100, Kai Chen 0012, Miaoqian Lin
Venue: NDSS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/LiuY0L25</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS 2025] From Large to Mammoth: A Comparative Evaluation of Large Language Models in Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/from-large-to-mammoth-a-comparative-evaluation-of-large-language-models-in-vulnerability-detection/</link><description>Authors: Jie Lin, David Mohaisen
Venue: NDSS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/LinM25</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS 2025] PropertyGPT: LLM-driven Formal Verification of Smart Contracts through Retrieval-Augmented Property Generation.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/propertygpt-llm-driven-formal-verification-of-smart-contracts-through-retrieval-augmented-property-generation/</link><description>Authors: Ye Liu 0012, Yue Xue, Daoyuan Wu, Yuqiang Sun 0001, Yi Li 0008, Miaolei Shi, Yang Liu 0003
Venue: NDSS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/0012XW00S025</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS 2025] Uncovering the iceberg from the tip: Generating API Specifications for Bug Detection via Specification Propagation Analysis.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/uncovering-the-iceberg-from-the-tip-generating-api-specifications-for-bug-detection-via-specification-propagation-analysis/</link><description>Authors: Miaoqian Lin, Kai Chen 0012, Yi Yang 0100, Jinghua Liu
Venue: NDSS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/Lin0YL25</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS 2025] You Can Rand but You Can't Hide: A Holistic Security Analysis of Google Fuchsia's (and gVisor's) Network Stack.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/you-can-rand-but-you-cant-hide-a-holistic-security-analysis-of-google-fuchsias-and-gvisors-network-stack/</link><description>Authors: Inon Kaplan, Ron Even, Amit Klein 0001
Venue: NDSS
Year: 2025</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/KaplanE025</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] SG-Nav: Online 3D Scene Graph Prompting for LLM-based Zero-shot Object Navigation.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/098491b37deebbe6c007e69815729e09-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Hang Yin, Xiuwei Xu, Zhenyu Wu, Jie Zhou 0001, Jiwen Lu
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/YinXWZL24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] Can Graph Learning Improve Planning in LLM-based Agents?</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/098d1bd3eb6156a4c2f834563cdcf617-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Xixi Wu, Yifei Shen, Caihua Shan, Kaitao Song, Siwei Wang, Bohang Zhang, Jiarui Feng, Hong Cheng 0001, Wei Chen, Yun Xiong, Dongsheng Li
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/WuSSSWZFCCXL24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] LLMs as Zero-shot Graph Learners: Alignment of GNN Representations with LLM Token Embeddings.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/0b77d3a82b59e9d9899370b378087faf-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Duo Wang, Yuan Zuo, Fengzhi Li, Junjie Wu 0002
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/WangZL024</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] HYSYNTH: Context-Free LLM Approximation for Guiding Program Synthesis.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/1c9c85bae6161d52182d0fe2f3640512-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Shraddha Barke, Emmanuel Anaya Gonzalez, Saketh Ram Kasibatla, Taylor Berg-Kirkpatrick, Nadia Polikarpova
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/BarkeGKBP24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] FVEL: Interactive Formal Verification Environment with Large Language Models via Theorem Proving.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/62c6d7893b13a13c659cb815852dd00d-Abstract-Datasets_and_Benchmarks_Track.html</link><description>Authors: Xiaohan Lin, Qingxing Cao, Yinya Huang, Haiming Wang, Jianqiao Lu, Zhengying Liu, Linqi Song, Xiaodan Liang
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/LinCHWLLSL24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] NYU CTF Bench: A Scalable Open-Source Benchmark Dataset for Evaluating LLMs in Offensive Security.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/69d97a6493fbf016fff0a751f253ad18-Abstract-Datasets_and_Benchmarks_Track.html</link><description>Authors: Minghao Shao, Sofija Jancheska, Meet Udeshi, Brendan Dolan-Gavitt, Haoran Xi, Kimberly Milner, Boyuan Chen 0004, Max Yin, Siddharth Garg, Prashanth Krishnamurthy, Farshad Khorrami, Ramesh Karri, Muhammad Shafique 0001
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/ShaoJUDxM0YGKKK24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] SemCoder: Training Code Language Models with Comprehensive Semantics Reasoning.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/6efcc7fd8efeee29a050a79c843c90e0-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Yangruibo Ding, Jinjun Peng, Marcus J. Min, Gail E. Kaiser, Junfeng Yang, Baishakhi Ray
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/DingPMKYR24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] GraphVis: Boosting LLMs with Visual Knowledge Graph Integration.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/7cb04f510593c9ba30da398f5e0a7e7b-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Yihe Deng, Chenchen Ye 0001, Zijie Huang 0002, Mingyu Derek Ma, Yiwen Kou, Wei Wang 0010
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/Deng00MK024</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] LogiCity: Advancing Neuro-Symbolic AI with Abstract Urban Simulation.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/8196be81e68289d7a9ece21ed7f5750a-Abstract-Datasets_and_Benchmarks_Track.html</link><description>Authors: Bowen Li 0007, Zhaoyu Li, Qiwei Du, Jinqi Luo, Wenshan Wang, Yaqi Xie 0001, Simon Stepputtis, Chen Wang 0033, Katia P. Sycara, Pradeep Ravikumar, Alexander G. Gray, Xujie Si, Sebastian A. Scherer
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/LiLDLWXSWSRGSS24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] WorldCoder, a Model-Based LLM Agent: Building World Models by Writing Code and Interacting with the Environment.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/820c61a0cd419163ccbd2c33b268816e-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Hao Tang 0008, Darren Key, Kevin Ellis
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/0008KE24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] SWT-Bench: Testing and Validating Real-World Bug-Fixes with Code Agents.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/94f093b41fc2666376fb1f667fe282f3-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Niels Mndler, Mark Niklas Mller, Jingxuan He, Martin T. Vechev
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/MundlerMHV24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] HaloScope: Harnessing Unlabeled LLM Generations for Hallucination Detection.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/ba92705991cfbbcedc26e27e833ebbae-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Xuefeng Du, Chaowei Xiao, Sharon Li 0001
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/DuX024</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] RedCode: Risky Code Execution and Generation Benchmark for Code Agents.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/bfd082c452dffb450d5a5202b0419205-Abstract-Datasets_and_Benchmarks_Track.html</link><description>Authors: Chengquan Guo, Xun Liu, Chulin Xie, Andy Zhou, Yi Zeng 0005, Zinan Lin 0001, Dawn Song, Bo Li 0026
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/GuoLXZZ0SL24</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] Hallo3D: Multi-Modal Hallucination Detection and Mitigation for Consistent 3D Content Generation.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/d75660d6eb0ce31360c768fef85301dd-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Hongbo Wang, Jie Cao 0002, Jin Liu, Xiaoqiang Zhou, Huaibo Huang, Ran He 0001
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/Wang0LZH024</guid></item><item><title>[NeurIPS 2025] Suitable is the Best: Task-Oriented Knowledge Fusion in Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>http://papers.nips.cc/paper_files/paper/2024/hash/db7a81128155d6f14970c12d0b5e7a4c-Abstract-Conference.html</link><description>Authors: Jingjing Wang, Minhuan Huang, Yuanping Nie, Xiang Li 0078, Qianjin Du, Wei Kong, Huan Deng, Xiaohui Kuang
Venue: NeurIPS
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/nips</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/nips/WangHN0DKDK24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Language-Agnostic Static Analysis of Probabilistic Programs.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695031</link><description>Authors: Markus Bck, Michael Schrder 0005, Jrgen Cito
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/Bock0C24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] GPP: A Graph-Powered Prioritizer for Code Review Requests.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3694990</link><description>Authors: Lanxin Yang, Jinwei Xu, He Zhang 0001, Fanghao Wu, Jun Lyu, Yue Li 0047, Alberto Bacchelli
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/YangX0WLLB24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Effective Vulnerable Function Identification based on CVE Description Empowered by Large Language Models.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695013</link><description>Authors: Yulun Wu, Ming Wen 0001, Zeliang Yu, Xiaochen Guo, Hai Jin 0001
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/Wu0YG024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Program Synthesis Meets Visual What-Comes-Next Puzzles.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695015</link><description>Authors: Sumit Lahiri, Pankaj Kumar Kalita, Akshay Kumar Chittora, Varun Vankudre, Subhajit Roy 0001
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LahiriKCV024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] GraphCoder: Enhancing Repository-Level Code Completion via Coarse-to-fine Retrieval Based on Code Context Graph.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695054</link><description>Authors: Wei Liu 0189, Ailun Yu, Daoguang Zan, Bo Shen, Wei Zhang 0004, Haiyan Zhao 0001, Zhi Jin 0001, Qianxiang Wang
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LiuYZS00JW24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Snopy: Bridging Sample Denoising with Causal Graph Learning for Effective Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695057</link><description>Authors: Sicong Cao, Xiaobing Sun 0001, Xiaoxue Wu 0001, David Lo 0001, Lili Bo, Bin Li 0006, Xiaolei Liu 0001, Xingwei Lin, Wei Liu 0010
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/Cao000B00L024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Three Heads Are Better Than One: Suggesting Move Method Refactoring Opportunities with Inter-class Code Entity Dependency Enhanced Hybrid Hypergraph Neural Network.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695068</link><description>Authors: Di Cui, Jiaqi Wang, Qiangqiang Wang, Peng Ji, Minglang Qiao, Yutong Zhao, Jingzhao Hu, Luqiao Wang, Qingshan Li
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/CuiWWJQZHWL24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] AdvSCanner: Generating Adversarial Smart Contracts to Exploit Reentrancy Vulnerabilities Using LLM and Static Analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695482</link><description>Authors: Yin Wu, Xiaofei Xie, Chenyang Peng, Dijun Liu, Hao Wu 0100, Ming Fan 0002, Ting Liu 0002, Haijun Wang 0002
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WuXPLW00W24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Compositional Security Analysis of Dynamic Component-based Systems.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695499</link><description>Authors: Narges Khakpour, Charilaos Skandylas
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/KhakpourS24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] HITS: High-coverage LLM-based Unit Test Generation via Method Slicing.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695501</link><description>Authors: Zejun Wang, Kaibo Liu, Ge Li 0001, Zhi Jin 0001
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangL0J24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] TypeFSL: Type Prediction from Binaries via Inter-procedural Data-flow Analysis and Few-shot Learning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695502</link><description>Authors: Zirui Song, Yutong Zhou, Shuaike Dong, Ke Zhang 0039, Kehuan Zhang
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/SongZDZZ24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Coding-PTMs: How to Find Optimal Code Pre-trained Models for Code Embedding in Vulnerability Detection?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695539</link><description>Authors: Yu Zhao, Lina Gong, Zhiqiu Huang, Yongwei Wang, Mingqiang Wei, Fei Wu 0001
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/ZhaoGHWW024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] STASE: Static Analysis Guided Symbolic Execution for UEFI Vulnerability Signature Generation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695543</link><description>Authors: Md Shafiuzzaman, Achintya Desai, Laboni Sarker, Tevfik Bultan
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/ShafiuzzamanDSB24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Understanding Developer-Analyzer Interactions in Code Reviews.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695257</link><description>Authors: Martin Schf, Berk irisci, Linghui Luo, Muhammad Numair Mansur, Omer Tripp, Daniel Sanchez, Qiang Zhou 0009, Muhammad Bilal Zafar
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/SchafCLMTSZZ24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] DeployFix: Dynamic Repair of Software Deployment Failures via Constraint Solving.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695268</link><description>Authors: Haoyu Liao, Jianmei Guo, Bo Huang 0002, Yujie Han, Dingyu Yang, Kai Shi 0006, Jonathan Ding, Guoyao Xu, Guodong Yang, Liping Zhang 0013
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LiaoG0HY0DXYZ24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Experience Report on Applying Program Analysis Techniques for Mainframe Application Understanding.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695270</link><description>Authors: Shivali Agarwal, Hiroaki Nakamura, Rami Katan
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/AgarwalNK24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Enhancing Compositional Static Analysis with Dynamic Analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695599</link><description>Authors: Dino Distefano, Matteo Marescotti, Cons T. hs, Sopot Cela, Gabriela Cunha Sampaio, Radu Grigore, kos Hajdu, Timotej Kapus, Ke Mao, Thibault Suzanne
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/DistefanoMACSGH24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Unity Is Strength: Collaborative LLM-Based Agents for Code Reviewer Recommendation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695291</link><description>Authors: Luqiao Wang, Yangtao Zhou, Huiying Zhuang, Qingshan Li, Di Cui, Yutong Zhao, Lu Wang 0014
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangZZLCZ024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Oracle-Guided Vulnerability Diversity and Exploit Synthesis of Smart Contracts Using LLMs.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695292</link><description>Authors: Mojtaba Eshghie, Cyrille Artho
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/EshghieA24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] ContractTinker: LLM-Empowered Vulnerability Repair for Real-World Smart Contracts.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695349</link><description>Authors: Che Wang, Jiashuo Zhang 0001, Jianbo Gao 0003, Libin Xia, Zhi Guan, Zhong Chen 0001
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangZGXG024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] Bridging Gaps in LLM Code Translation: Reducing Errors with Call Graphs and Bridged Debuggers.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695322</link><description>Authors: Yang Luo, Richard Yu, Fajun Zhang, Ling Liang, Yongqiang Xiong
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LuoYZLX24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE 2025] RepoGenix: Dual Context-Aided Repository-Level Code Completion with Language Models.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695331</link><description>Authors: Ming Liang, Xiaoheng Xie, Gehao Zhang, Xunjin Zheng, Peng Di, Wei Jiang 0011, Hongwei Chen, Chengpeng Wang 0001, Gang Fan
Venue: ASE
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LiangXZZD0CWF24</guid></item><item><title>[RAID 2024] Large-Scale Security Analysis of Real-World Backend Deployments Speaking IoT-Focused Protocols.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3678890.3678899</link><description>Authors: Carlotta Tagliaro, Martina Komsic, Andrea Continella, Kevin Borgolte, Martina Lindorfer
Venue: RAID
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/raid</author><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/raid/TagliaroKCBL24</guid></item><item><title>[RAID 2024] A Comprehensive, Automated Security Analysis of the Uptane Automotive Over-the-Air Update Framework.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3678890.3678927</link><description>Authors: Robert Lorch, Daniel Larraz, Cesare Tinelli, Omar Chowdhury
Venue: RAID
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/raid</author><pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/raid/LorchLTC24</guid></item><item><title>[FM 2024] Learning Branching-Time Properties in CTL and ATL via Constraint Solving.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-031-71162-6_16</link><description>Authors: Benjamin Bordais, Daniel Neider, Rajarshi Roy 0002
Venue: FM (1)
Year: 2024</description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/fm</author><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/fm/BordaisNR24</guid></item></channel></rss>