<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>My Customized Papers</title><link>https://github.com/your_username/your_repo</link><description>Aggregated research papers</description><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:02:38 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>rfeed v1.1.1</generator><docs>https://github.com/svpino/rfeed/blob/master/README.md</docs><item><title>[C&amp;S] Folded-tag: Enhancing memory safety with efficient hardware-supported memory tagging</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167404825005115?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: April 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Computers &amp; Security, Volume 163&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Sumin Yang, Hongjoo Jin, Wonsuk Choi, Dong Hoon Lee&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Computers &amp; Security</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:02:38 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167404825005115</guid></item><item><title>[SCP] Securing LLM code generation: Leveraging prompt engineering to mitigate vulnerabilities across models and languages</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167642326000110?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: June 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Science of Computer Programming, Volume 251&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Shaykhah S. Aldosari, Layla S. Aldawsari&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Science of Computer Programming</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:01:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0167642326000110</guid></item><item><title>[JSS] RLV: LLM-based vulnerability detection by retrieving and refining contextual information</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016412122500425X?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: May 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Journal of Systems and Software, Volume 235&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Fangcheng Qiu, Zhongxin Liu, Bingde Hu, Zhengong Cai, Lingfeng Bao, Xinyu Wang&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Journal of Systems and Software</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:01:57 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S016412122500425X</guid></item><item><title>[IST] COTVD: A function-level vulnerability detection framework using chain-of-thought reasoning with large language models</title><link>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000327?dgcid=rss_sd_all</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Publication date: May 2026&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Source:&lt;/b&gt; Information and Software Technology, Volume 193&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author(s): Yinan Chen, Xiangping Chen, Yuan Huang, Changlin Yang, Lei Yun&lt;/p&gt;</description><author>ScienceDirect Publication: Information and Software Technology</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 17:01:56 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0950584926000327</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] Extracting Recurring Vulnerabilities from Black-Box LLM-Generated Software</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04894</link><description>arXiv:2602.04894v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: LLMs are increasingly used for code generation, but their outputs often follow recurring templates that can induce predictable vulnerabilities. We study \emph{vulnerability persistence} in LLM-generated software and introduce \emph{Feature--Security Table (FSTab)} with two components. First, FSTab enables a black-box attack that predicts likely backend vulnerabilities from observable frontend features and knowledge of the source LLM, without access to backend code or source code. Second, FSTab provides a model-centric evaluation that quantifies how consistently a given model reproduces the same vulnerabilities across programs, semantics-preserving rephrasings, and application domains. We evaluate FSTab on state-of-the-art code LLMs, including GPT-5.2, Claude-4.5 Opus, and Gemini-3 Pro, across diverse application domains. Our results show strong cross-domain transfer: even when the target domain is excluded from training, FSTab achieves up to 94\% attack success and 93\% vulnerability coverage on Internal Tools (Claude-4.5 Opus). These findings expose an underexplored attack surface in LLM-generated software and highlight the security risks of code generation. Our code is available at: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/FSTab-024E.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04894v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] SynAT: Enhancing Security Knowledge Bases via Automatic Synthesizing Attack Tree from Crowd Discussions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05329</link><description>arXiv:2602.05329v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Cyber attacks have become a serious threat to the security of software systems. Many organizations have built their security knowledge bases to safeguard against attacks and vulnerabilities. However, due to the time lag in the official release of security information, these security knowledge bases may not be well maintained, and using them to protect software systems against emergent security risks can be challenging. On the other hand, the security posts on online knowledge-sharing platforms contain many crowd security discussions and the knowledge in those posts can be used to enhance the security knowledge bases. This paper proposes SynAT, an automatic approach to synthesize attack trees from crowd security posts. Given a security post, SynAT first utilize the Large Language Model (LLM) and prompt learning to restrict the scope of sentences that may contain attack information; then it utilizes a transition-based event and relation extraction model to extract the events and relations simultaneously from the scope; finally, it applies heuristic rules to synthesize the attack trees with the extracted events and relations. An experimental evaluation is conducted on 5,070 Stack Overflow security posts, and the results show that SynAT outperforms all baselines in both event and relation extraction, and achieves the highest tree similarity in attack tree synthesis. Furthermore, SynAT has been applied to enhance HUAWEI's security knowledge base as well as public security knowledge bases CVE and CAPEC, which demonstrates SynAT's practicality.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05329v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] Interpreting Manifolds and Graph Neural Embeddings from Internet of Things Traffic Flows</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05817</link><description>arXiv:2602.05817v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: The rapid expansion of Internet of Things (IoT) ecosystems has led to increasingly complex and heterogeneous network topologies. Traditional network monitoring and visualization tools rely on aggregated metrics or static representations, which fail to capture the evolving relationships and structural dependencies between devices. Although Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) offer a powerful way to learn from relational data, their internal representations often remain opaque and difficult to interpret for security-critical operations. Consequently, this work introduces an interpretable pipeline that generates directly visualizable low-dimensional representations by mapping high-dimensional embeddings onto a latent manifold. This projection enables the interpretable monitoring and interoperability of evolving network states, while integrated feature attribution techniques decode the specific characteristics shaping the manifold structure. The framework achieves a classification F1-score of 0.830 for intrusion detection while also highlighting phenomena such as concept drift. Ultimately, the presented approach bridges the gap between high-dimensional GNN embeddings and human-understandable network behavior, offering new insights for network administrators and security analysts.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05817v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] Persistent Human Feedback, LLMs, and Static Analyzers for Secure Code Generation and Vulnerability Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05868</link><description>arXiv:2602.05868v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing literature heavily relies on static analysis tools to evaluate LLMs for secure code generation and vulnerability detection. We reviewed 1,080 LLM-generated code samples, built a human-validated ground-truth, and compared the outputs of two widely used static security tools, CodeQL and Semgrep, against this corpus. While 61% of the samples were genuinely secure, Semgrep and CodeQL classified 60% and 80% as secure, respectively. Despite the apparent agreement in aggregate statistics, per-sample analysis reveals substantial discrepancies: only 65% of Semgrep's and 61% of CodeQL's reports correctly matched the ground truth. These results question the reliability of static analysis tools as sole evaluators of code security and underscore the need for expert feedback. Building on this insight, we propose a conceptual framework that persistently stores human feedback in a dynamic retrieval-augmented generation pipeline, enabling LLMs to reuse past feedback for secure code generation and vulnerability detection.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05868v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] A Causal Perspective for Enhancing Jailbreak Attack and Defense</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04893</link><description>arXiv:2602.04893v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Uncovering the mechanisms behind "jailbreaks" in large language models (LLMs) is crucial for enhancing their safety and reliability, yet these mechanisms remain poorly understood. Existing studies predominantly analyze jailbreak prompts by probing latent representations, often overlooking the causal relationships between interpretable prompt features and jailbreak occurrences. In this work, we propose Causal Analyst, a framework that integrates LLMs into data-driven causal discovery to identify the direct causes of jailbreaks and leverage them for both attack and defense. We introduce a comprehensive dataset comprising 35k jailbreak attempts across seven LLMs, systematically constructed from 100 attack templates and 50 harmful queries, annotated with 37 meticulously designed human-readable prompt features. By jointly training LLM-based prompt encoding and GNN-based causal graph learning, we reconstruct causal pathways linking prompt features to jailbreak responses. Our analysis reveals that specific features, such as "Positive Character" and "Number of Task Steps", act as direct causal drivers of jailbreaks. We demonstrate the practical utility of these insights through two applications: (1) a Jailbreaking Enhancer that targets identified causal features to significantly boost attack success rates on public benchmarks, and (2) a Guardrail Advisor that utilizes the learned causal graph to extract true malicious intent from obfuscated queries. Extensive experiments, including baseline comparisons and causal structure validation, confirm the robustness of our causal analysis and its superiority over non-causal approaches. Our results suggest that analyzing jailbreak features from a causal perspective is an effective and interpretable approach for improving LLM reliability. Our code is available at https://github.com/Master-PLC/Causal-Analyst.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04893v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] TxRay: Agentic Postmortem of Live Blockchain Attacks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.01317</link><description>arXiv:2602.01317v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Decentralized Finance (DeFi) has turned blockchains into financial infrastructure, allowing anyone to trade, lend, and build protocols without intermediaries, but this openness exposes pools of value controlled by code. Within five years, the DeFi ecosystem has lost over 15.75B USD to reported exploits. Many exploits arise from permissionless opportunities that any participant can trigger using only public state and standard interfaces, which we call Anyone-Can-Take (ACT) opportunities. Despite on-chain transparency, postmortem analysis remains slow and manual: investigations start from limited evidence, sometimes only a single transaction hash, and must reconstruct the exploit lifecycle by recovering related transactions, contract code, and state dependencies.
  We present TxRay, a Large Language Model (LLM) agentic postmortem system that uses tool calls to reconstruct live ACT attacks from limited evidence. Starting from one or more seed transactions, TxRay recovers the exploit lifecycle, derives an evidence-backed root cause, and generates a runnable, self-contained Proof of Concept (PoC) that deterministically reproduces the incident. TxRay self-checks postmortems by encoding incident-specific semantic oracles as executable assertions.
  To evaluate PoC correctness and quality, we develop PoCEvaluator, an independent agentic execution-and-review evaluator. On 114 incidents from DeFiHackLabs, TxRay produces an expert-aligned root cause and an executable PoC for 105 incidents, achieving 92.11% end-to-end reproduction. Under PoCEvaluator, 98.1% of TxRay PoCs avoid hard-coding attacker addresses, a +22.9pp lift over DeFiHackLabs. In a live deployment, TxRay delivers validated root causes in 40 minutes and PoCs in 59 minutes at median latency. TxRay's oracle-validated PoCs enable attack imitation, improving coverage by 15.6% and 65.5% over STING and APE.</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.01317v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CR] Pattern Enhanced Multi-Turn Jailbreaking: Exploiting Structural Vulnerabilities in Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.08859</link><description>arXiv:2510.08859v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) remain vulnerable to multi-turn jailbreaking attacks that exploit conversational context to bypass safety constraints gradually. These attacks target different harm categories through distinct conversational approaches. Existing multi-turn methods often rely on heuristic or ad hoc exploration strategies, providing limited insight into underlying model weaknesses. The relationship between conversation patterns and model vulnerabilities across harm categories remains poorly understood. We propose Pattern Enhanced Chain of Attack (PE-CoA), a framework of five conversation patterns to construct multi-turn jailbreaks through natural dialogue. Evaluating PE-CoA on twelve LLMs spanning ten harm categories, we achieve state-of-the-art performance, uncovering pattern-specific vulnerabilities and LLM behavioral characteristics: models exhibit distinct weakness profiles, defense to one pattern does not generalize to others, and model families share similar failure modes. These findings highlight limitations of safety training and indicate the need for pattern-aware defenses. Code available on: https://github.com/Ragib-Amin-Nihal/PE-CoA</description><author>cs.CR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.08859v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Reducing the Costs of Proof Synthesis on Rust Systems by Scaling Up a Seed Training Set</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04910</link><description>arXiv:2602.04910v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are widely used for code generation. However, the correctness of code generated by LLMs remains a concern. A potential remedy to this concern is to have LLMs generate formal correctness proofs along with such code. However, compared with code generation, code-proof generation requires much higher reasoning capability and has much less existing data to learn from. In this paper, we present VeruSyn, a data synthesis pipeline for Verus, a state-of-the-art verification tool for system software written in Rust. Through self-synthesis and tutorial-based synthesis, VeruSyn achieves much larger scale and Verus-feature coverage than previous data-synthesis techniques designed for Verus; VeruSyn also supplements its dataset with long-chain-of-thought (CoT) data through agent trajectory synthesis. With VeruSyn, we synthesize the largest set of Verus verified programs: 6.9 million Rust programs, each with a formal specification and a proof that it meets that specification. This dataset lets us create a fine-tuned Qwen2.5-Coder-32B-Instruct model with appealing cost-proof tradeoff compared with state-of-the-art commercial models like Claude Sonnet 4.5. It also significantly outperforms models like o4-mini and previously proposed research models.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04910v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] EGSS: Entropy-guided Stepwise Scaling for Reliable Software Engineering</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05242</link><description>arXiv:2602.05242v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Agentic Test-Time Scaling (TTS) has delivered state-of-the-art (SOTA) performance on complex software engineering tasks such as code generation and bug fixing. However, its practical adoption remains limited due to significant computational overhead, primarily driven by two key challenges: (1) the high cost associated with deploying excessively large ensembles, and (2) the lack of a reliable mechanism for selecting the optimal candidate solution, ultimately constraining the performance gains that can be realized. To address these challenges, we propose Entropy-Guided Stepwise Scaling (EGSS), a novel TTS framework that dynamically balances efficiency and effectiveness through entropy-guided adaptive search and robust test-suite augmentation. Extensive experiments on SWE-Bench-Verified demonstrate that EGSS consistently boosts performance by 5-10% across all evaluated models. Specifically, it increases the resolved ratio of Kimi-K2-Intruct from 63.2% to 72.2%, and GLM-4.6 from 65.8% to 74.6%. Furthermore, when paired with GLM-4.6, EGSS achieves a new state-of-the-art among open-source large language models. In addition to these accuracy improvements, EGSS reduces inference-time token usage by over 28% compared to existing TTS methods, achieving simultaneous gains in both effectiveness and computational efficiency.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05242v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] PatchGuru: Patch Oracle Inference from Natural Language Artifacts with Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05270</link><description>arXiv:2602.05270v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As software systems evolve, patches may unintentionally alter program behavior. Validating patches against their intended semantics is difficult due to incomplete regression tests and informal, non-executable natural language (NL) descriptions of patch intent. We present PatchGuru, the first automated technique that infers executable patch specifications from real-world pull requests (PRs). Given a PR, PatchGuru uses large language models (LLMs) to extract developer intent from NL artifacts and synthesizes patch oracles: under-approximate yet practical specifications expressed as runtime assertions in comparison programs that integrate pre- and post-patch versions. Patch oracles focus on patch-relevant behaviors, enable automated validation, and support cross-version properties. PatchGuru iteratively refines inferred oracles by comparing pre- and post-patch behaviors, identifies violations, filters inconsistencies via self-review, and generates bug reports. We evaluate PatchGuru on 400 recent PRs from four widely used open-source Python projects. PatchGuru reports 39 warnings with a precision of 0.62, yielding 24 confirmed true positives, including 12 previously unknown bugs, 11 of which were subsequently fixed by developers. Compared to the state-of-the-art technique Testora, PatchGuru detects 17 more bugs (24 vs. 7) while improving precision from 0.32 to 0.62. PatchGuru incurs an average cost of 8.9 minutes and USD 0.07 per PR. These results suggest that PatchGuru complements code review and regression testing by providing executable documentation and automated validation of patch intent.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05270v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Can We Classify Flaky Tests Using Only Test Code? An LLM-Based Empirical Study</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05465</link><description>arXiv:2602.05465v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Flaky tests yield inconsistent results when they are repeatedly executed on the same code revision. They interfere with automated quality assurance of code changes and hinder efficient software testing. Previous work evaluated approaches to train machine learning models to classify flaky tests based on identifiers in the test code. However, the resulting classifiers have been shown to lack generalizability, hindering their applicability in practical environments. Recently, pre-trained Large Language Models (LLMs) have shown the capability to generalize across various tasks. Thus, they represent a promising approach to address the generalizability problem of previous approaches. In this study, we evaluated three LLMs (two general-purpose models, one code-specific model) using three prompting techniques on two benchmark datasets from prior studies on flaky test classification. Furthermore, we manually investigated 50 samples from the given datasets to determine whether classifying flaky tests based only on test code is feasible for humans. Our findings indicate that LLMs struggle to classify flaky tests given only the test code. The results of our best prompt-model combination were only marginally better than random guessing. In our manual analysis, we found that the test code does not necessarily contain sufficient information for a flakiness classification. Our findings motivate future work to evaluate LLMs for flakiness classification with additional context, for example, using retrieval-augmented generation or agentic AI.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05465v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] A Dual-Loop Agent Framework for Automated Vulnerability Reproduction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05721</link><description>arXiv:2602.05721v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Automated vulnerability reproduction from CVE descriptions requires generating executable Proof-of-Concept (PoC) exploits and validating them in target environments. This process is critical in software security research and practice, yet remains time-consuming and demands specialized expertise when performed manually. While LLM agents show promise for automating this task, existing approaches often conflate exploring attack directions with fixing implementation details, which leads to unproductive debugging loops when reproduction fails. To address this, we propose Cve2PoC, an LLM-based dual-loop agent framework following a plan-execute-evaluate paradigm. The Strategic Planner analyzes vulnerability semantics and target code to produce structured attack plans. The Tactical Executor generates PoC code and validates it through progressive verification. The Adaptive Refiner evaluates execution results and routes failures to different loops: the \textit{Tactical Loop} for code-level refinement, while the \textit{Strategic Loop} for attack strategy replanning. This dual-loop design enables the framework to escape ineffective debugging by matching remediation to failure type. Evaluation on two benchmarks covering 617 real-world vulnerabilities demonstrates that Cve2PoC achieves 82.9\% and 54.3\% reproduction success rates on SecBench.js and PatchEval, respectively, outperforming the best baseline by 11.3\% and 20.4\%. Human evaluation confirms that generated PoCs achieve comparable code quality to human-written exploits in readability and reusability.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05721v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Automated Customization of LLMs for Enterprise Code Repositories Using Semantic Scopes</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05780</link><description>arXiv:2602.05780v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Code completion (CC) is a task frequently used by developers when working in collaboration with LLM-based programming assistants. Despite the increased performance of LLMs on public benchmarks, out of the box LLMs still have a hard time generating code that aligns with a private code repository not previously seen by the model's training data. Customizing code LLMs to a private repository provides a way to improve the model performance. In this paper we present our approach for automated LLM customization based on semantic scopes in the code. We evaluate LLMs on real industry cases with two private enterprise code repositories with two customization strategies: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) and supervised Fine-Tuning (FT). Our mechanism for ingesting the repository's data and formulating the training data pairs with semantic scopes helps models to learn the underlying patterns specific to the repository, providing more precise code to developers and helping to boost their productivity. The code completions of moderately sized customized models can be significantly better than those of uncustomized models of much larger capacity. We also include an analysis of customization on two public benchmarks and present opportunities for future work.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05780v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Doc2Spec: Synthesizing Formal Programming Specifications from Natural Language via Grammar Induction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04892</link><description>arXiv:2602.04892v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Ensuring that API implementations and usage comply with natural language programming rules is critical for software correctness, security, and reliability. Formal verification can provide strong guarantees but requires precise specifications, which are difficult and costly to write manually. To address this challenge, we present Doc2Spec, a multi-agent framework that uses LLMs to automatically induce a specification grammar from natural-language rules and then generates formal specifications guided by the induced grammar. The grammar captures essential domain knowledge, constrains the specification space, and enforces consistent representations, thereby improving the reliability and quality of generated specifications. Evaluated on seven benchmarks across three programming languages, Doc2Spec outperforms a baseline without grammar induction and achieves competitive results against a technique with a manually crafted grammar, demonstrating the effectiveness of automated grammar induction for formalizing natural-language rules.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04892v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Multi-View Adaptive Contrastive Learning for Information Retrieval Based Fault Localization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2409.12519</link><description>arXiv:2409.12519v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Most studies focused on information retrieval-based techniques for fault localization, which built representations for bug reports and source code files and matched their semantic vectors through similarity measurement. However, such approaches often ignore some useful information that might help improve localization performance, such as 1) the interaction relationship between bug reports and source code files; 2) the similarity relationship between bug reports; and 3) the co-citation relationship between source code files. In this paper, we propose a novel approach named Multi-View Adaptive Contrastive Learning for Information Retrieval Fault Localization (MACL-IRFL) to learn the above-mentioned relationships for software fault localization. Specifically, we first generate data augmentations from report-code interaction view, report-report similarity view and code-code co-citation view separately, and adopt graph neural network to aggregate the information of bug reports or source code files from the three views in the embedding process. Moreover, we perform contrastive learning across these views. Our design of contrastive learning task will force the bug report representations to encode information shared by report-report and report-code views,and the source code file representations shared by code-code and report-code views, thereby alleviating the noise from auxiliary information. Finally, to evaluate the performance of our approach, we conduct extensive experiments on five open-source Java projects. The results show that our model can improve over the best baseline up to 28.93%, 25.57% and 20.35% on Accuracy@1, MAP and MRR, respectively.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2409.12519v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] LEANCODE: Understanding Models Better for Code Simplification of Pre-trained Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.14759</link><description>arXiv:2505.14759v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Models for code often entail significant computational complexity, which grows significantly with the length of the input code sequence. We propose LeanCode for code simplification to reduce training and prediction time, leveraging code contexts in utilizing attention scores to represent the tokens' importance. We advocate for the selective removal of tokens based on the average context-aware attention scores rather than average scores across all inputs. LeanCode uses the attention scores of `CLS' tokens within the encoder for classification tasks, such as code search. It also employs the encoder-decoder attention scores to determine token significance for sequence-to-sequence tasks like code summarization. Our evaluation shows LeanCode's superiority over the SOTAs DietCode and Slimcode, with improvements of 60% and 16% for code search, and 29% and 27% for code summarization, respectively.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2505.14759v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Code Clone Detection via an AlphaFold-Inspired Framework</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2507.15226</link><description>arXiv:2507.15226v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Code clone detection plays a critical role in software maintenance and vulnerability analysis. Substantial methods have been proposed to detect code clones. However, they struggle to extract high-level program semantics directly from a single linear token sequence, leading to unsatisfactory detection performance. A similar single-sequence challenge has been successfully addressed in protein structure prediction by AlphaFold. Motivated by the successful resolution of the shared single-sequence challenge by AlphaFold, as well as the sequential similarities between proteins and code, we leverage AlphaFold for code clone detection. In particular, we propose AlphaCC, which represents code fragments as token sequences and adapts AlphaFold's sequence-to-structure modeling capability to infer code semantics. The pipeline of AlphaCC goes through three steps. First, AlphaCC transforms each input code fragment into a token sequence and, motivated by AlphaFold's use of multiple sequence alignment (MSA), novelly uses a retrieval-augmentation strategy to construct an MSA from lexically similar token sequences. Second, AlphaCC adopts a modified attention-based encoder based on AlphaFold to model dependencies within and across token sequences. Finally, unlike AlphaFold's protein structure prediction task, AlphaCC computes similarity scores between token sequences through a late interaction strategy and performs binary classification to determine code clone pairs. Comprehensive evaluations on three datasets, particularly two semantic clone detection datasets, show that AlphaCC consistently outperforms all baselines, demonstrating strong semantic understanding. AlphaCC further achieves strong performance on instances where tool-dependent methods fail, highlighting its tool-independence. Moreover, AlphaCC maintains competitive efficiency, enabling practical usage in large-scale clone detection tasks.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2507.15226v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] VibeCodeHPC: An Agent-Based Iterative Prompting Auto-Tuner for HPC Code Generation Using LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00031</link><description>arXiv:2510.00031v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose VibeCodeHPC, an automatic tuning system for HPC programs based on multi-agent LLMs for code generation. VibeCodeHPC tunes programs through multi-agent role allocation and iterative prompt refinement. We describe the system configuration with four roles: Project Manager (PM), System Engineer (SE), Programmer (PG), and Continuous Delivery (CD). We introduce dynamic agent deployment and activity monitoring functions to facilitate effective multi-agent collaboration. In our case study, we convert and optimize CPU-based matrix-matrix multiplication code written in C to GPU code using CUDA. The multi-agent configuration of VibeCodeHPC achieved higher-quality code generation per unit time compared to a solo-agent configuration. Additionally, the dynamic agent deployment and activity monitoring capabilities facilitated more effective identification of requirement violations and other issues.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00031v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] Fine-tuned LLM-based Code Migration Framework</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13515</link><description>arXiv:2512.13515v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: The study presents the outcomes of research and experimental validation in the domain of automated codebase migration, with a focus on addressing challenges in transitioning SQL-based systems. The proposed method for migration essentially appears as a framework that leverages the best aspects of traditional software engineering techniques and provides an iterative, scalable, precise and efficient solution for modern database transformations. The central piece of the approach is the integration of a fine-tuned Large Language Model to address critical issues in SQL code conversion, such as syntax mapping, resolving discrepancies between Oracle PL/SQL and PostgreSQL, and optimising database elements such as stored procedures, triggers, views, and overall database logic. Thus, the method involves a trade-off between fine-tuning and prompt engineering. Special attention is given to a fine-tuning approach, which enhances the adaptability and compatibility with migration requirements across the entire database. According to the achieved results, fine-tuning plays a very important role. The study employs targeted evaluation methodologies along with computational metrics to measure the success of iterative conversion cycles. Core innovations include automated SQL feature detection, semi-supervised error analysis and integration of Subject Matter Experts feedback within a systematic migration workflow. The methodology achieves significant reductions in Syntax Error Rates, enhances feature alignment throughout migration iterations, and leverages dataset sampling to ensure continual improvement. By embedding GAI into the migration process, the framework facilitates precise feature mapping, semi-automated error resolution, and data-driven optimisation loops, improving workflow efficiency.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2512.13515v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-SE] ProOPF: Benchmarking and Improving LLMs for Professional-Grade Power Systems Optimization Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03070</link><description>arXiv:2602.03070v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Growing renewable penetration introduces substantial uncertainty into power system operations, necessitating frequent adaptation of dispatch objectives and constraints and challenging expertise-intensive, near-real-time modeling workflows. Large Language Models (LLMs) provide a promising avenue for automating this process by translating natural-language (NL) operational requirements into executable optimization models via semantic reasoning and code synthesis. Yet existing LLM datasets and benchmarks for optimization modeling primarily target coarse-grained cross-domain generalization, offering limited, rigorous evaluation in power-system settings, particularly for Optimal Power Flow (OPF). We therefore introduce \textbf{ProOPF-D} and \textbf{ProOPF-B}, a dataset and benchmark for professional-grade OPF modeling: ProOPF-D contains 12K instances pairing NL requests with parameter adjustments and structural extensions to a canonical OPF, together with executable implementations; ProOPF-B provides 121 expert-annotated test cases with ground-truth code, enabling end-to-end evaluation under both concrete and abstract OPF modeling regimes.</description><author>cs.SE updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.03070v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-PL] Opportunistically Parallel Lambda Calculus</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2405.11361</link><description>arXiv:2405.11361v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Scripting languages are widely used to compose external calls such as native libraries and network services. In such scripts, execution time is often dominated by waiting for these external calls, rendering traditional single-language optimizations ineffective. To address this, we propose a novel opportunistic evaluation strategy for scripting languages based on a core lambda calculus that automatically dispatches independent external calls in parallel and streams their results. We prove that our approach is confluent, ensuring that it preserves the programmer's original intent, and that it eventually executes every external call. We implement this approach in a scripting language called Opal. We demonstrate the versatility and performance of Opal, focusing on programs that invoke heavy external computation through the use of large language models (LLMs) and other APIs. Across five scripts, we compare to several state-of-the-art baselines and show that opportunistic evaluation improves total running time (up to $6.2\times$) and latency (up to $12.7\times$) compared to standard sequential Python, while performing very close (between $1.3\%$ and $18.5\%$ running time overhead) to hand-tuned manually optimized asynchronous Rust. For Tree-of-Thoughts, a prominent LLM reasoning approach, we achieve a $6.2\times$ performance improvement over the authors' own implementation.</description><author>cs.PL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2405.11361v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Understanding LLM Evaluator Behavior: A Structured Multi-Evaluator Framework for Merchant Risk Assessment</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05110</link><description>arXiv:2602.05110v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large Language Models (LLMs) are increasingly used as evaluators of reasoning quality, yet their reliability and bias in payments-risk settings remain poorly understood. We introduce a structured multi-evaluator framework for assessing LLM reasoning in Merchant Category Code (MCC)-based merchant risk assessment, combining a five-criterion rubric with Monte-Carlo scoring to evaluate rationale quality and evaluator stability. Five frontier LLMs generate and cross-evaluate MCC risk rationales under attributed and anonymized conditions. To establish a judge-independent reference, we introduce a consensus-deviation metric that eliminates circularity by comparing each judge's score to the mean of all other judges, yielding a theoretically grounded measure of self-evaluation and cross-model deviation. Results reveal substantial heterogeneity: GPT-5.1 and Claude 4.5 Sonnet show negative self-evaluation bias (-0.33, -0.31), while Gemini-2.5 Pro and Grok 4 display positive bias (+0.77, +0.71), with bias attenuating by 25.8 percent under anonymization. Evaluation by 26 payment-industry experts shows LLM judges assign scores averaging +0.46 points above human consensus, and that the negative bias of GPT-5.1 and Claude 4.5 Sonnet reflects closer alignment with human judgment. Ground-truth validation using payment-network data shows four models exhibit statistically significant alignment (Spearman rho = 0.56 to 0.77), confirming that the framework captures genuine quality. Overall, the framework provides a replicable basis for evaluating LLM-as-a-judge systems in payment-risk workflows and highlights the need for bias-aware protocols in operational financial settings.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05110v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Aspect-Aware MOOC Recommendation in a Heterogeneous Network</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05297</link><description>arXiv:2602.05297v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: MOOC recommendation systems have received increasing attention to help learners navigate and select preferred learning content. Traditional methods such as collaborative filtering and content-based filtering suffer from data sparsity and over-specialization. To alleviate these limitations, graph-based approaches have been proposed; however, they still rely heavily on manually predefined metapaths, which often capture only superficial structural relationships and impose substantial burdens on domain experts as well as significant engineering costs. To overcome these limitations, we propose AMR (Aspect-aware MOOC Recommendation), a novel framework that models path-specific multiple aspects by embedding the semantic content of nodes within each metapath. AMR automatically discovers metapaths through bi-directional walks, derives aspect-aware path representations using a bi-LSTM-based encoder, and incorporates these representations as edge features in the learner-learner and KC-KC subgraphs to achieve fine-grained semantically informed KC recommendations. Extensive experiments on the large-scale MOOCCube and PEEK datasets show that AMR consistently outperforms state-of-the-art graph neural network baselines across key metrics such as HR@K and nDCG@K. Further analysis confirms that AMR effectively captures rich path-specific aspect information, allowing more accurate recommendations than those methods that rely solely on predefined metapaths. The code will be available upon accepted.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05297v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] ProAct: Agentic Lookahead in Interactive Environments</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05327</link><description>arXiv:2602.05327v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Existing Large Language Model (LLM) agents struggle in interactive environments requiring long-horizon planning, primarily due to compounding errors when simulating future states. To address this, we propose ProAct, a framework that enables agents to internalize accurate lookahead reasoning through a two-stage training paradigm. First, we introduce Grounded LookAhead Distillation (GLAD), where the agent undergoes supervised fine-tuning on trajectories derived from environment-based search. By compressing complex search trees into concise, causal reasoning chains, the agent learns the logic of foresight without the computational overhead of inference-time search. Second, to further refine decision accuracy, we propose the Monte-Carlo Critic (MC-Critic), a plug-and-play auxiliary value estimator designed to enhance policy-gradient algorithms like PPO and GRPO. By leveraging lightweight environment rollouts to calibrate value estimates, MC-Critic provides a low-variance signal that facilitates stable policy optimization without relying on expensive model-based value approximation. Experiments on both stochastic (e.g., 2048) and deterministic (e.g., Sokoban) environments demonstrate that ProAct significantly improves planning accuracy. Notably, a 4B parameter model trained with ProAct outperforms all open-source baselines and rivals state-of-the-art closed-source models, while demonstrating robust generalization to unseen environments. The codes and models are available at https://github.com/GreatX3/ProAct</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05327v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Refine and Purify: Orthogonal Basis Optimization with Null-Space Denoising for Conditional Representation Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05464</link><description>arXiv:2602.05464v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Conditional representation learning aims to extract criterion-specific features for customized tasks. Recent studies project universal features onto the conditional feature subspace spanned by an LLM-generated text basis to obtain conditional representations. However, such methods face two key limitations: sensitivity to subspace basis and vulnerability to inter-subspace interference. To address these challenges, we propose OD-CRL, a novel framework integrating Adaptive Orthogonal Basis Optimization (AOBO) and Null-Space Denoising Projection (NSDP). Specifically, AOBO constructs orthogonal semantic bases via singular value decomposition with a curvature-based truncation. NSDP suppresses non-target semantic interference by projecting embeddings onto the null space of irrelevant subspaces. Extensive experiments conducted across customized clustering, customized classification, and customized retrieval tasks demonstrate that OD-CRL achieves a new state-of-the-art performance with superior generalization.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05464v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Generative Ontology: When Structured Knowledge Learns to Create</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05636</link><description>arXiv:2602.05636v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Traditional ontologies excel at describing domain structure but cannot generate novel artifacts. Large language models generate fluently but produce outputs that lack structural validity, hallucinating mechanisms without components, goals without end conditions. We introduce Generative Ontology, a framework that synthesizes these complementary strengths: ontology provides the grammar; the LLM provides the creativity.
  Generative Ontology encodes domain knowledge as executable Pydantic schemas that constrain LLM generation via DSPy signatures. A multi-agent pipeline assigns specialized roles to different ontology domains: a Mechanics Architect designs game systems, a Theme Weaver integrates narrative, a Balance Critic identifies exploits. Each agent carrying a professional "anxiety" that prevents shallow, agreeable outputs. Retrieval-augmented generation grounds novel designs in precedents from existing exemplars, while iterative validation ensures coherence between mechanisms and components.
  We demonstrate the framework through GameGrammar, a system for generating complete tabletop game designs. Given a thematic prompt ("bioluminescent fungi competing in a cave ecosystem"), the pipeline produces structurally complete, playable game specifications with mechanisms, components, victory conditions, and setup instructions. These outputs satisfy ontological constraints while remaining genuinely creative.
  The pattern generalizes beyond games. Any domain with expert vocabulary, validity constraints, and accumulated exemplars (music composition, software architecture, culinary arts) is a candidate for Generative Ontology. We argue that constraints do not limit creativity but enable it: just as grammar makes poetry possible, ontology makes structured generation possible.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05636v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Nonlinearity as Rank: Generative Low-Rank Adapter with Radial Basis Functions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05709</link><description>arXiv:2602.05709v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Low-rank adaptation (LoRA) approximates the update of a pretrained weight matrix using the product of two low-rank matrices. However, standard LoRA follows an explicit-rank paradigm, where increasing model capacity requires adding more rows or columns (i.e., basis vectors) to the low-rank matrices, leading to substantial parameter growth. In this paper, we find that these basis vectors exhibit significant parameter redundancy and can be compactly represented by lightweight nonlinear functions. Therefore, we propose Generative Low-Rank Adapter (GenLoRA), which replaces explicit basis vector storage with nonlinear basis vector generation. Specifically, GenLoRA maintains a latent vector for each low-rank matrix and employs a set of lightweight radial basis functions (RBFs) to synthesize the basis vectors. Each RBF requires far fewer parameters than an explicit basis vector, enabling higher parameter efficiency in GenLoRA. Extensive experiments across multiple datasets and architectures show that GenLoRA attains higher effective LoRA ranks under smaller parameter budgets, resulting in superior fine-tuning performance. The code is available at https://anonymous.4open.science/r/GenLoRA-1519.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05709v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Speech Emotion Recognition Leveraging OpenAI's Whisper Representations and Attentive Pooling Methods</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06000</link><description>arXiv:2602.06000v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Speech Emotion Recognition (SER) research has faced limitations due to the lack of standard and sufficiently large datasets. Recent studies have leveraged pre-trained models to extract features for downstream tasks such as SER. This work explores the capabilities of Whisper, a pre-trained ASR system, in speech emotion recognition by proposing two attention-based pooling methods, Multi-head Attentive Average Pooling and QKV Pooling, designed to efficiently reduce the dimensionality of Whisper representations while preserving emotional features. We experiment on English and Persian, using the IEMOCAP and ShEMO datasets respectively, with Whisper Tiny and Small. Our multi-head QKV architecture achieves state-of-the-art results on the ShEMO dataset, with a 2.47% improvement in unweighted accuracy. We further compare the performance of different Whisper encoder layers and find that intermediate layers often perform better for SER on the Persian dataset, providing a lightweight and efficient alternative to much larger models such as HuBERT X-Large. Our findings highlight the potential of Whisper as a representation extractor for SER and demonstrate the effectiveness of attention-based pooling for dimension reduction.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06000v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] AgenticPay: A Multi-Agent LLM Negotiation System for Buyer-Seller Transactions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06008</link><description>arXiv:2602.06008v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based agents are increasingly expected to negotiate, coordinate, and transact autonomously, yet existing benchmarks lack principled settings for evaluating language-mediated economic interaction among multiple agents. We introduce AgenticPay, a benchmark and simulation framework for multi-agent buyer-seller negotiation driven by natural language. AgenticPay models markets in which buyers and sellers possess private constraints and product-dependent valuations, and must reach agreements through multi-round linguistic negotiation rather than numeric bidding alone. The framework supports a diverse suite of over 110 tasks ranging from bilateral bargaining to many-to-many markets, with structured action extraction and metrics for feasibility, efficiency, and welfare. Benchmarking state-of-the-art proprietary and open-weight LLMs reveals substantial gaps in negotiation performance and highlights challenges in long-horizon strategic reasoning, establishing AgenticPay as a foundation for studying agentic commerce and language-based market interaction. Code and dataset are available at the link: https://github.com/SafeRL-Lab/AgenticPay.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06008v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] DyTopo: Dynamic Topology Routing for Multi-Agent Reasoning via Semantic Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06039</link><description>arXiv:2602.06039v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multi-agent systems built from prompted large language models can improve multi-round reasoning, yet most existing pipelines rely on fixed, trajectory-wide communication patterns that are poorly matched to the stage-dependent needs of iterative problem solving. We introduce DyTopo, a manager-guided multi-agent framework that reconstructs a sparse directed communication graph at each round. Conditioned on the manager's round goal, each agent outputs lightweight natural-language query (need) and \key (offer) descriptors; DyTopo embeds these descriptors and performs semantic matching, routing private messages only along the induced edges. Across code generation and mathematical reasoning benchmarks and four LLM backbones, DyTopo consistently outperforms over the strongest baseline (avg. +6.2). Beyond accuracy, DyTopo yields an interpretable coordination trace via the evolving graphs, enabling qualitative inspection of how communication pathways reconfigure across rounds.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06039v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Denoising diffusion networks for normative modeling in neuroimaging</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04886</link><description>arXiv:2602.04886v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Normative modeling estimates reference distributions of biological measures conditional on covariates, enabling centiles and clinically interpretable deviation scores to be derived. Most neuroimaging pipelines fit one model per imaging-derived phenotype (IDP), which scales well but discards multivariate dependence that may encode coordinated patterns. We propose denoising diffusion probabilistic models (DDPMs) as a unified conditional density estimator for tabular IDPs, from which univariate centiles and deviation scores are derived by sampling. We utilise two denoiser backbones: (i) a feature-wise linear modulation (FiLM) conditioned multilayer perceptron (MLP) and (ii) a tabular transformer with feature self-attention and intersample attention (SAINT), conditioning covariates through learned embeddings. We evaluate on a synthetic benchmark with heteroscedastic and multimodal age effects and on UK Biobank FreeSurfer phenotypes, scaling from dimension of 2 to 200. Our evaluation suite includes centile calibration (absolute centile error, empirical coverage, and the probability integral transform), distributional fidelity (Kolmogorov-Smirnov tests), multivariate dependence diagnostics, and nearest-neighbour memorisation analysis. For low dimensions, diffusion models deliver well-calibrated per-IDP outputs comparable to traditional baselines while jointly modeling realistic dependence structure. At higher dimensions, the transformer backbone remains substantially better calibrated than the MLP and better preserves higher-order dependence, enabling scalable joint normative models that remain compatible with standard per-IDP pipelines. These results support diffusion-based normative modeling as a practical route to calibrated multivariate deviation profiles in neuroimaging.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04886v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Physics as the Inductive Bias for Causal Discovery</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04907</link><description>arXiv:2602.04907v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Causal discovery is often a data-driven paradigm to analyze complex real-world systems. In parallel, physics-based models such as ordinary differential equations (ODEs) provide mechanistic structure for many dynamical processes. Integrating these paradigms potentially allows physical knowledge to act as an inductive bias, improving identifiability, stability, and robustness of causal discovery in dynamical systems. However, such integration remains challenging: real dynamical systems often exhibit feedback, cyclic interactions, and non-stationary data trend, while many widely used causal discovery methods are formulated under acyclicity or equilibrium-based assumptions. In this work, we propose an integrative causal discovery framework for dynamical systems that leverages partial physical knowledge as an inductive bias. Specifically, we model system evolution as a stochastic differential equation (SDE), where the drift term encodes known ODE dynamics and the diffusion term corresponds to unknown causal couplings beyond the prescribed physics. We develop a scalable sparsity-inducing MLE algorithm that exploits causal graph structure for efficient parameter estimation. Under mild conditions, we establish guarantees to recover the causal graph. Experiments on dynamical systems with diverse causal structures show that our approach improves causal graph recovery and produces more stable, physically consistent estimates than purely data-driven state-of-the-art baselines.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04907v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Internalizing LLM Reasoning via Discovery and Replay of Latent Actions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04925</link><description>arXiv:2602.04925v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: The internalization of chain-of-thought processes into hidden states has emerged as a highly efficient paradigm for scaling test-time compute. However, existing activation steering methods rely on static control vectors that fail to adapt to the non-stationary evolution of complex reasoning tasks. To address this limitation, we propose STIR (Self-Distilled Tools for Internal Reasoning), a framework that reformulates reasoning enhancement as a dynamic latent trajectory control problem. STIR introduces a synergistic three-stage pipeline: (1) differential intrinsic action induction harvests latent reasoning successes to crystallize steering primitives; (2) sparse control basis construction curates a compact, geometrically diverse tool library; and (3) value-modulated trajectory intervention dynamically injects context-specific impulses via anchor-based gating. Extensive experiments on six arithmetic and logical benchmarks across four representative models demonstrate that STIR improves average accuracy by 1.9% to 7.5% while reducing average token consumption by up to 35% compared to vanilla decoding. These findings demonstrate that the benefits of explicit chain-of-thought can be realized through dynamic latent trajectory control, internalizing the reasoning process to bypass the explicit generation while achieving superior fidelity. Our code is available at https://github.com/sznnzs/LLM-Latent-Action.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04925v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Data-Centric Interpretability for LLM-based Multi-Agent Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05183</link><description>arXiv:2602.05183v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) are increasingly trained in complex Reinforcement Learning, multi-agent environments, making it difficult to understand how behavior changes over training. Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) have recently shown to be useful for data-centric interpretability. In this work, we analyze large-scale reinforcement learning training runs from the sophisticated environment of Full-Press Diplomacy by applying pretrained SAEs, alongside LLM-summarizer methods. We introduce Meta-Autointerp, a method for grouping SAE features into interpretable hypotheses about training dynamics. We discover fine-grained behaviors including role-playing patterns, degenerate outputs, language switching, alongside high-level strategic behaviors and environment-specific bugs. Through automated evaluation, we validate that 90% of discovered SAE Meta-Features are significant, and find a surprising reward hacking behavior. However, through two user studies, we find that even subjectively interesting and seemingly helpful SAE features may be worse than useless to humans, along with most LLM generated hypotheses. However, a subset of SAE-derived hypotheses are predictively useful for downstream tasks. We further provide validation by augmenting an untrained agent's system prompt, improving the score by +14.2%. Overall, we show that SAEs and LLM-summarizer provide complementary views into agent behavior, and together our framework forms a practical starting point for future data-centric interpretability work on ensuring trustworthy LLM behavior throughout training.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05183v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] LMMRec: LLM-driven Motivation-aware Multimodal Recommendation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05474</link><description>arXiv:2602.05474v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Motivation-based recommendation systems uncover user behavior drivers. Motivation modeling, crucial for decision-making and content preference, explains recommendation generation. Existing methods often treat motivation as latent variables from interaction data, neglecting heterogeneous information like review text. In multimodal motivation fusion, two challenges arise: 1) achieving stable cross-modal alignment amid noise, and 2) identifying features reflecting the same underlying motivation across modalities. To address these, we propose LLM-driven Motivation-aware Multimodal Recommendation (LMMRec), a model-agnostic framework leveraging large language models for deep semantic priors and motivation understanding. LMMRec uses chain-of-thought prompting to extract fine-grained user and item motivations from text. A dual-encoder architecture models textual and interaction-based motivations for cross-modal alignment, while Motivation Coordination Strategy and Interaction-Text Correspondence Method mitigate noise and semantic drift through contrastive learning and momentum updates. Experiments on three datasets show LMMRec achieves up to a 4.98\% performance improvement.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05474v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] LinguistAgent: A Reflective Multi-Model Platform for Automated Linguistic Annotation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05493</link><description>arXiv:2602.05493v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Data annotation remains a significant bottleneck in the Humanities and Social Sciences, particularly for complex semantic tasks such as metaphor identification. While Large Language Models (LLMs) show promise, a significant gap remains between the theoretical capability of LLMs and their practical utility for researchers. This paper introduces LinguistAgent, an integrated, user-friendly platform that leverages a reflective multi-model architecture to automate linguistic annotation. The system implements a dual-agent workflow, comprising an Annotator and a Reviewer, to simulate a professional peer-review process. LinguistAgent supports comparative experiments across three paradigms: Prompt Engineering (Zero/Few-shot), Retrieval-Augmented Generation, and Fine-tuning. We demonstrate LinguistAgent's efficacy using the task of metaphor identification as an example, providing real-time token-level evaluation (Precision, Recall, and $F_1$ score) against human gold standards. The application and codes are released on https://github.com/Bingru-Li/LinguistAgent.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05493v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] AI Agent Systems for Supply Chains: Structured Decision Prompts and Memory Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05524</link><description>arXiv:2602.05524v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: This study investigates large language model (LLM) -based multi-agent systems (MASs) as a promising approach to inventory management, which is a key component of supply chain management. Although these systems have gained considerable attention for their potential to address the challenges associated with typical inventory management methods, key uncertainties regarding their effectiveness persist. Specifically, it is unclear whether LLM-based MASs can consistently derive optimal ordering policies and adapt to diverse supply chain scenarios. To address these questions, we examine an LLM-based MAS with a fixed-ordering strategy prompt that encodes the stepwise processes of the problem setting and a safe-stock strategy commonly used in inventory management. Our empirical results demonstrate that, even without detailed prompt adjustments, an LLM-based MAS can determine optimal ordering decisions in a restricted scenario. To enhance adaptability, we propose a novel agent called AIM-RM, which leverages similar historical experiences through similarity matching. Our results show that AIM-RM outperforms benchmark methods across various supply chain scenarios, highlighting its robustness and adaptability.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05524v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Neural Implicit 3D Cardiac Shape Reconstruction from Sparse CT Angiography Slices Mimicking 2D Transthoracic Echocardiography Views</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05884</link><description>arXiv:2602.05884v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Accurate 3D representations of cardiac structures allow quantitative analysis of anatomy and function. In this work, we propose a method for reconstructing complete 3D cardiac shapes from segmentations of sparse planes in CT angiography (CTA) for application in 2D transthoracic echocardiography (TTE). Our method uses a neural implicit function to reconstruct the 3D shape of the cardiac chambers and left-ventricle myocardium from sparse CTA planes. To investigate the feasibility of achieving 3D reconstruction from 2D TTE, we select planes that mimic the standard apical 2D TTE views. During training, a multi-layer perceptron learns shape priors from 3D segmentations of the target structures in CTA. At test time, the network reconstructs 3D cardiac shapes from segmentations of TTE-mimicking CTA planes by jointly optimizing the latent code and the rigid transforms that map the observed planes into 3D space. For each heart, we simulate four realistic apical views, and we compare reconstructed multi-class volumes with the reference CTA volumes. On a held-out set of CTA segmentations, our approach achieves an average Dice coefficient of 0.86 $\pm$ 0.04 across all structures. Our method also achieves markedly lower volume errors than the clinical standard, Simpson's biplane rule: 4.88 $\pm$ 4.26 mL vs. 8.14 $\pm$ 6.04 mL, respectively, for the left ventricle; and 6.40 $\pm$ 7.37 mL vs. 37.76 $\pm$ 22.96 mL, respectively, for the left atrium. This suggests that our approach offers a viable route to more accurate 3D chamber quantification in 2D transthoracic echocardiography.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05884v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] RISE-Video: Can Video Generators Decode Implicit World Rules?</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05986</link><description>arXiv:2602.05986v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: While generative video models have achieved remarkable visual fidelity, their capacity to internalize and reason over implicit world rules remains a critical yet under-explored frontier. To bridge this gap, we present RISE-Video, a pioneering reasoning-oriented benchmark for Text-Image-to-Video (TI2V) synthesis that shifts the evaluative focus from surface-level aesthetics to deep cognitive reasoning. RISE-Video comprises 467 meticulously human-annotated samples spanning eight rigorous categories, providing a structured testbed for probing model intelligence across diverse dimensions, ranging from commonsense and spatial dynamics to specialized subject domains. Our framework introduces a multi-dimensional evaluation protocol consisting of four metrics: \textit{Reasoning Alignment}, \textit{Temporal Consistency}, \textit{Physical Rationality}, and \textit{Visual Quality}. To further support scalable evaluation, we propose an automated pipeline leveraging Large Multimodal Models (LMMs) to emulate human-centric assessment. Extensive experiments on 11 state-of-the-art TI2V models reveal pervasive deficiencies in simulating complex scenarios under implicit constraints, offering critical insights for the advancement of future world-simulating generative models.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05986v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] CommCP: Efficient Multi-Agent Coordination via LLM-Based Communication with Conformal Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06038</link><description>arXiv:2602.06038v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: To complete assignments provided by humans in natural language, robots must interpret commands, generate and answer relevant questions for scene understanding, and manipulate target objects. Real-world deployments often require multiple heterogeneous robots with different manipulation capabilities to handle different assignments cooperatively. Beyond the need for specialized manipulation skills, effective information gathering is important in completing these assignments. To address this component of the problem, we formalize the information-gathering process in a fully cooperative setting as an underexplored multi-agent multi-task Embodied Question Answering (MM-EQA) problem, which is a novel extension of canonical Embodied Question Answering (EQA), where effective communication is crucial for coordinating efforts without redundancy. To address this problem, we propose CommCP, a novel LLM-based decentralized communication framework designed for MM-EQA. Our framework employs conformal prediction to calibrate the generated messages, thereby minimizing receiver distractions and enhancing communication reliability. To evaluate our framework, we introduce an MM-EQA benchmark featuring diverse, photo-realistic household scenarios with embodied questions. Experimental results demonstrate that CommCP significantly enhances the task success rate and exploration efficiency over baselines. The experiment videos, code, and dataset are available on our project website: https://comm-cp.github.io.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06038v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Robust Answers, Fragile Logic: Probing the Decoupling Hypothesis in LLM Reasoning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.17406</link><description>arXiv:2505.17406v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: While Chain-of-Thought (CoT) prompting has become a cornerstone for complex reasoning in Large Language Models (LLMs), the faithfulness of the generated reasoning remains an open question. We investigate the Decoupling Hypothesis: that correct answers often mask fragile, post-hoc rationalizations that are not causally tied to the model's prediction. To systematically verify this, we introduce MATCHA, a novel Answer-Conditioned Probing framework. Unlike standard evaluations that focus on final output accuracy, MATCHA isolates the reasoning phase by conditioning generation on the model's predicted answer, allowing us to stress-test the stability of the rationale itself. Our experiments reveal a critical vulnerability: under imperceptible input perturbations, LLMs frequently maintain the correct answer while generating inconsistent or nonsensical reasoning - effectively being ``Right for the Wrong Reasons''. Using LLM judges to quantify this robustness gap, we find that multi-step and commonsense tasks are significantly more susceptible to this decoupling than logical tasks. Furthermore, we demonstrate that adversarial examples generated by MATCHA transfer non-trivially to black-box models. Our findings expose the illusion of CoT robustness and underscore the need for future architectures that enforce genuine answer-reasoning consistency rather than mere surface-level accuracy.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2505.17406v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Verifying the Verifiers: Unveiling Pitfalls and Potentials in Fact Verifiers</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2506.13342</link><description>arXiv:2506.13342v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Fact verification is essential for ensuring the reliability of LLM applications. In this study, we evaluate 12 pre-trained LLMs and one specialized fact-verifier, including frontier LLMs and open-weight reasoning LLMs, using a collection of examples from 14 fact-checking benchmarks. We share three findings intended to guide future development of more robust fact verifiers. First, we highlight the importance of addressing annotation errors and ambiguity in datasets, demonstrating that approximately 16\% of ambiguous or incorrectly labeled data substantially influences model rankings. Neglecting this issue may result in misleading conclusions during comparative evaluations, and we suggest using a systematic pipeline utilizing LLM-as-a-judge to help identify these issues at scale. Second, we discover that frontier LLMs with few-shot in-context examples, often overlooked in previous works, achieve top-tier performance. We therefore recommend that future studies include comparisons with these simple yet highly effective baselines. Lastly, despite their effectiveness, frontier LLMs incur substantial costs, motivating the development of small, fine-tuned fact verifiers. We show that these small models still have room for improvement, particularly on instances that require complex reasoning. Encouragingly, we demonstrate that augmenting training with synthetic multi-hop reasoning data significantly enhances their capabilities in such instances. We release our code, model, and dataset at https://github.com/just1nseo/verifying-the-verifiers.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2506.13342v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] DeepAgent: A General Reasoning Agent with Scalable Toolsets</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.21618</link><description>arXiv:2510.21618v3 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large reasoning models have demonstrated strong problem-solving abilities, yet real-world tasks often require external tools and long-horizon interactions. Existing agent frameworks typically follow predefined workflows, which limit autonomous and global task completion. In this paper, we introduce DeepAgent, an end-to-end deep reasoning agent that performs autonomous thinking, tool discovery, and action execution within a single, coherent reasoning process. To manage long-horizon interactions, we introduce an autonomous memory folding mechanism that compresses past interactions into structured episodic, working, and tool memories, reducing error accumulation while preserving critical information. To teach general-purpose tool use efficiently and stably, we develop an end-to-end reinforcement learning strategy, namely ToolPO, that leverages LLM-simulated APIs and applies tool-call advantage attribution to assign fine-grained credit to the tool invocation tokens. Extensive experiments on eight benchmarks, including general tool-use tasks (ToolBench, API-Bank, TMDB, Spotify, ToolHop) and downstream applications (ALFWorld, WebShop, GAIA, HLE), demonstrate that DeepAgent consistently outperforms baselines across both labeled-tool and open-set tool retrieval scenarios. The code and demo are available at https://github.com/RUC-NLPIR/DeepAgent.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.21618v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] The Why Behind the Action: Unveiling Internal Drivers via Agentic Attribution</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.15075</link><description>arXiv:2601.15075v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large Language Model (LLM)-based agents are widely used in real-world applications such as customer service, web navigation, and software engineering. As these systems become more autonomous and are deployed at scale, understanding why an agent takes a particular action becomes increasingly important for accountability and governance. However, existing research predominantly focuses on \textit{failure attribution} to localize explicit errors in unsuccessful trajectories, which is insufficient for explaining \textbf{the reason behind agent behaviors}. To bridge this gap, we propose a novel framework for \textbf{general agentic attribution}, designed to identify the internal factors driving agent actions regardless of the task outcome. Our framework operates hierarchically to manage the complexity of agent interactions. Specifically, at the \textit{component level}, we employ temporal likelihood dynamics to identify critical interaction steps; then at the \textit{sentence level}, we refine this localization using perturbation-based analysis to isolate the specific textual evidence. We validate our framework across a diverse suite of agentic scenarios, including standard tool use and subtle reliability risks like memory-induced bias. Experimental results demonstrate that the proposed framework reliably pinpoints pivotal historical events and sentences behind the agent behavior, offering a critical step toward safer and more accountable agentic systems. Codes are available at https://github.com/AI45Lab/AgentDoG.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.15075v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] A Study of Adaptive Modeling Towards Robust Generalization</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.02780</link><description>arXiv:2602.02780v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) increasingly support reasoning over biomolecular structures, but most existing approaches remain modality-specific and rely on either sequence-style encodings or fixed-length connector tokens for structural inputs. These designs can under-expose explicit geometric cues and impose rigid fusion bottlenecks, leading to over-compression and poor token allocation as structural complexity grows. We present a unified all-atom framework that grounds language reasoning in geometric information while adaptively scaling structural tokens. The method first constructs variable-size structural patches on molecular graphs using an instruction-conditioned gating policy, enabling complexity-aware allocation of query tokens. It then refines the resulting patch tokens via cross-attention with modality embeddings and injects geometry-informed tokens into the language model to improve structure grounding and reduce structural hallucinations. Across diverse all-atom benchmarks, the proposed approach yields consistent gains in heterogeneous structure-grounded reasoning. An anonymized implementation is provided in the supplementary material.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.02780v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] WAVE: Weighted Autoregressive Varying Gate for Time Series Forecasting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2410.03159</link><description>arXiv:2410.03159v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose a Weighted Autoregressive Varying gatE (WAVE) attention mechanism equipped with both Autoregressive (AR) and Moving-average (MA) components. It can adapt to various attention mechanisms, enhancing and decoupling their ability to capture long-range and local temporal patterns in time series data. In this paper, we first demonstrate that, for the time series forecasting (TSF) task, the previously overlooked decoder-only autoregressive Transformer model can achieve results comparable to the best baselines when appropriate tokenization and training methods are applied. Moreover, inspired by the ARMA model from statistics and recent advances in linear attention, we introduce the full ARMA structure into existing autoregressive attention mechanisms. By using an indirect MA weight generation method, we incorporate the MA term while maintaining the time complexity and parameter size of the underlying efficient attention models. We further explore how indirect parameter generation can produce implicit MA weights that align with the modeling requirements for local temporal impacts. Experimental results show that WAVE attention that incorporates the ARMA structure consistently improves the performance of various AR attentions on TSF tasks, achieving state-of-the-art results.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2410.03159v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Vision-R1: Incentivizing Reasoning Capability in Multimodal Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.06749</link><description>arXiv:2503.06749v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: DeepSeek-R1-Zero has successfully demonstrated the emergence of reasoning capabilities in LLMs purely through Reinforcement Learning (RL). Inspired by this breakthrough, we explore how RL can be utilized to enhance the reasoning capability of MLLMs. However, direct training with RL struggles to activate complex reasoning capabilities such as questioning and reflection in MLLMs, due to the absence of substantial high-quality multimodal reasoning data. To address this issue, we propose the reasoning MLLM, Vision-R1, to improve multimodal reasoning capability. Specifically, we first construct a high-quality multimodal CoT dataset without human annotations by leveraging an existing MLLM and DeepSeek-R1 through modality bridging and data filtering to obtain a 200K multimodal CoT dataset, Vision-R1-cold dataset. It serves as cold-start initialization data for Vision-R1. To mitigate the optimization challenges caused by overthinking after cold start, we propose Progressive Thinking Suppression Training (PTST) strategy and employ Group Relative Policy Optimization (GRPO) with the hard formatting result reward function to gradually refine the model's ability to learn correct and complex reasoning processes on a 10K multimodal math dataset. Comprehensive experiments show our model achieves an average improvement of $\sim$6% across various multimodal math reasoning benchmarks. Vision-R1-7B achieves a 73.5% accuracy on the widely used MathVista benchmark, which is only 0.4% lower than the leading reasoning model, OpenAI O1. Scaling up the amount of multimodal math data in the RL training, Vision-R1-32B and Vison-R1-72B achieves 76.4% and 78.2% MathVista benchmark scores, respectively. The datasets and code will be released in: https://github.com/Osilly/Vision-R1 .</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2503.06749v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Guided Diffusion Sampling on Function Spaces with Applications to PDEs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2505.17004</link><description>arXiv:2505.17004v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We propose a general framework for conditional sampling in PDE-based inverse problems, targeting the recovery of whole solutions from extremely sparse or noisy measurements. This is accomplished by a function-space diffusion model and plug-and-play guidance for conditioning. Our method first trains an unconditional, discretization-agnostic denoising model using neural operator architectures. At inference, we refine the samples to satisfy sparse observation data via a gradient-based guidance mechanism. Through rigorous mathematical analysis, we extend Tweedie's formula to infinite-dimensional Banach spaces, providing the theoretical foundation for our posterior sampling approach. Our method (FunDPS) accurately captures posterior distributions in function spaces under minimal supervision and severe data scarcity. Across five PDE tasks with only 3% observation, our method achieves an average 32% accuracy improvement over state-of-the-art fixed-resolution diffusion baselines while reducing sampling steps by 4x. Furthermore, multi-resolution fine-tuning ensures strong cross-resolution generalizability. To the best of our knowledge, this is the first diffusion-based framework to operate independently of discretization, offering a practical and flexible solution for forward and inverse problems in the context of PDEs. Code is available at https://github.com/neuraloperator/FunDPS</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2505.17004v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] CellForge: Agentic Design of Virtual Cell Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.02276</link><description>arXiv:2508.02276v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Virtual cell modeling aims to predict cellular responses to diverse perturbations but faces challenges from biological complexity, multimodal data heterogeneity, and the need for interdisciplinary expertise. We introduce CellForge, a multi-agent framework that autonomously designs and synthesizes neural network architectures tailored to specific single-cell datasets and perturbation tasks. Given raw multi-omics data and task descriptions, CellForge discovers candidate architectures through collaborative reasoning among specialized agents, then generates executable implementations. Our core contribution is the framework itself: showing that multi-agent collaboration mechanisms - rather than manual human design or single-LLM prompting - can autonomously produce executable, high-quality computational methods. This approach goes beyond conventional hyperparameter tuning by enabling entirely new architectural components such as trajectory-aware encoders and perturbation diffusion modules to emerge from agentic deliberation. We evaluate CellForge on six datasets spanning gene knockouts, drug treatments, and cytokine stimulations across multiple modalities (scRNA-seq, scATAC-seq, CITE-seq). The results demonstrate that the models generated by CellForge are highly competitive with established baselines, while revealing systematic patterns of architectural innovation. CellForge highlights the scientific value of multi-agent frameworks: collaboration among specialized agents enables genuine methodological innovation and executable solutions that single agents or human experts cannot achieve. This represents a paradigm shift toward autonomous scientific method development in computational biology. Code is available at https://github.com/gersteinlab/CellForge.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2508.02276v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Breaking the MoE LLM Trilemma: Dynamic Expert Clustering with Structured Compression</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.02345</link><description>arXiv:2510.02345v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Mixture-of-Experts (MoE) Large Language Models (LLMs) face a trilemma of load imbalance, parameter redundancy, and communication overhead. We introduce a unified framework based on dynamic expert clustering and structured compression to address these issues cohesively. Our method employs an online clustering procedure that periodically regroups experts using a fused metric of parameter and activation similarity, which stabilizes expert utilization. To our knowledge, this is one of the first frameworks to leverage the semantic embedding capability of the router to dynamically reconfigure the model's architecture during training for substantial efficiency gains. Within each cluster, we decompose expert weights into a shared base matrix and extremely low-rank residual adapters, achieving up to fivefold parameter reduction per group while preserving specialization. This structure enables a two-stage hierarchical routing strategy: tokens are first assigned to a cluster, then to specific experts within it, drastically reducing the routing search space and the volume of all-to-all communication. Furthermore, a heterogeneous precision scheme, which stores shared bases in FP16 and residual factors in INT4, coupled with dynamic offloading of inactive clusters, reduces peak memory consumption to levels comparable to dense models. Evaluated on GLUE and WikiText-103, our framework matches the quality of standard MoE models while reducing total parameters by approximately 80%, improving throughput by 10% to 20%, and lowering expert load variance by a factor of over three. Our work demonstrates that structural reorganization is a principled path toward scalable, efficient, and memory-effective MoE LLMs. Code is available at https://github.com/szdtzpj/Breaking_the_moe_trilemma</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.02345v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Leveraging Whisper Embeddings for Audio-based Lyrics Matching</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.08176</link><description>arXiv:2510.08176v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Audio-based lyrics matching can be an appealing alternative to other content-based retrieval approaches, but existing methods often suffer from limited reproducibility and inconsistent baselines. In this work, we introduce WEALY, a fully reproducible pipeline that leverages Whisper decoder embeddings for lyrics matching tasks. WEALY establishes robust and transparent baselines, while also exploring multimodal extensions that integrate textual and acoustic features. Through extensive experiments on standard datasets, we demonstrate that WEALY achieves a performance comparable to state-of-the-art methods that lack reproducibility. In addition, we provide ablation studies and analyses on language robustness, loss functions, and embedding strategies. This work contributes a reliable benchmark for future research, and underscores the potential of speech technologies for music information retrieval tasks.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.08176v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] TempoPFN: Synthetic Pre-training of Linear RNNs for Zero-shot Time Series Forecasting</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.25502</link><description>arXiv:2510.25502v4 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Foundation models for zero-shot time series forecasting face challenges in efficient long-horizon prediction and reproducibility, with existing synthetic-only approaches underperforming on challenging benchmarks. This paper presents TempoPFN, a univariate time series foundation model based on linear Recurrent Neural Networks (RNNs) pre-trained exclusively on synthetic data. The model uses a GatedDeltaProduct architecture with state-weaving for fully parallelizable training across sequence lengths, eliminating the need for windowing or summarization techniques while maintaining robust temporal state-tracking. Our comprehensive synthetic data pipeline unifies diverse generators, including stochastic differential equations, Gaussian processes, and audio synthesis, with novel augmentations. In zero-shot evaluations on the Gift-Eval, fev-bench and Chronos-ZS benchmarks, TempoPFN achieves top-tier competitive performance, outperforming all existing synthetic-only approaches and surpassing the majority of models trained on real-world data, while being more efficient than existing baselines by leveraging fully parallelizable training and inference. We open-source our complete data generation pipeline and training code, providing a reproducible foundation for future research.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.25502v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] VisMem: Latent Vision Memory Unlocks Potential of Vision-Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2511.11007</link><description>arXiv:2511.11007v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Despite the remarkable success of Vision-Language Models (VLMs), their performance on a range of complex visual tasks is often hindered by a "visual processing bottleneck": a propensity to lose grounding in visual evidence and exhibit a deficit in contextualized visual experience during prolonged generation. Drawing inspiration from human cognitive memory theory, which distinguishes short-term visually-dominant memory and long-term semantically-dominant memory, we propose VisMem, a cognitively-aligned framework that equips VLMs with dynamic latent vision memories, a short-term module for fine-grained perceptual retention and a long-term module for abstract semantic consolidation. These memories are seamlessly invoked during inference, allowing VLMs to maintain both perceptual fidelity and semantic consistency across thinking and generation. Extensive experiments across diverse visual benchmarks for understanding, reasoning, and generation reveal that VisMem delivers a significant average performance boost of 11.0% relative to the vanilla model and outperforms all counterparts, establishing a new paradigm for latent-space memory enhancement. The code will be available: https://github.com/YU-deep/VisMem.git.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2511.11007v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] CARL: Focusing Agentic Reinforcement Learning on Critical Actions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.04949</link><description>arXiv:2512.04949v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Agents capable of accomplishing complex tasks through multiple interactions with the environment have emerged as a popular research direction. However, in such multi-step settings, the conventional group-level policy optimization algorithm becomes suboptimal because of its underlying assumption that each action holds equal contribution, which deviates significantly from reality. Our analysis reveals that only a small fraction of actions are critical in determining the final outcome. Building on this insight, we propose CARL, a critical-action-focused reinforcement learning algorithm tailored for long-horizon agentic reasoning. CARL leverages entropy as a heuristic proxy for action criticality and achieves focused training by assigning rewards to high-criticality actions while excluding low-criticality actions from model updates, avoiding noisy credit assignment and redundant computation. Extensive experiments demonstrate that CARL achieves both stronger performance and higher efficiency across diverse evaluation settings. The source code will be publicly available.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2512.04949v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Sparse Attention Post-Training for Mechanistic Interpretability</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.05865</link><description>arXiv:2512.05865v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: We introduce a simple post-training method that makes transformer attention sparse without sacrificing performance. Applying a flexible sparsity regularisation under a constrained-loss objective, we show on models up to 7B parameters that it is possible to retain the original pretraining loss while reducing attention connectivity to $\approx 0.4 \%$ of its edges. Unlike sparse-attention methods designed for computational efficiency, our approach leverages sparsity as a structural prior: it preserves capability while exposing a more organized and interpretable connectivity pattern. We find that this local sparsity cascades into global circuit simplification: task-specific circuits involve far fewer components (attention heads and MLPs) with up to 100x fewer edges connecting them. Additionally, using cross-layer transcoders, we show that sparse attention substantially simplifies attention attribution, enabling a unified view of feature-based and circuit-based perspectives. These results demonstrate that transformer attention can be made orders of magnitude sparser, suggesting that much of its computation is redundant and that sparsity may serve as a guiding principle for more structured and interpretable models.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2512.05865v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Improving Low-Resource Machine Translation via Round-Trip Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.12535</link><description>arXiv:2601.12535v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Low-resource machine translation (MT) has gained increasing attention as parallel data from low-resource language communities is collected, but many potential methods for improving low-resource MT remain unexplored. We investigate a self-supervised reinforcement-learning-based fine-tuning for translation in low-resource settings using round-trip bootstrapping with the No Language Left Behind (NLLB) family of models. Our approach translates English into a target low-resource language and then back into English, using a combination of chrF++ and BLEU as the reward function on the reconstructed English sentences. Using the NLLB-MD dataset, we evaluate both the 600M and 1.3B parameter NLLB models and observe consistent improvements for the following languages: Central Aymara, Friulian, Wolof and Russian. Qualitative inspection of translation outputs indicates increased fluency and semantic fidelity. We argue that our method can further benefit from scale, enabling models to increasingly leverage their pretrained knowledge and continue self-improving. The code is available on github: https://github.com/Copticoder/thesis-nllb-bootstrap-grpo.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.12535v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Stream-Voice-Anon: Enhancing Utility of Real-Time Speaker Anonymization via Neural Audio Codec and Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.13948</link><description>arXiv:2601.13948v3 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Protecting speaker identity is crucial for online voice applications, yet streaming speaker anonymization (SA) remains underexplored. Recent research has demonstrated that neural audio codec (NAC) provides superior speaker feature disentanglement and linguistic fidelity. NAC can also be used with causal language models (LM) to enhance linguistic fidelity and prompt control for streaming tasks. However, existing NAC-based online LM systems are designed for voice conversion (VC) rather than anonymization, lacking the techniques required for privacy protection. Building on these advances, we present Stream-Voice-Anon, which adapts modern causal LM-based NAC architectures specifically for streaming SA by integrating anonymization techniques. Our anonymization approach incorporates pseudo-speaker representation sampling, a speaker embedding mixing and diverse prompt selection strategies for LM conditioning that leverage the disentanglement properties of quantized content codes to prevent speaker information leakage. Additionally, we compare dynamic and fixed delay configurations to explore latency-privacy trade-offs in real-time scenarios. Under the VoicePrivacy 2024 Challenge protocol, Stream-Voice-Anon achieves substantial improvements in intelligibility (up to 46% relative WER reduction) and emotion preservation (up to 28% UAR relative) compared to the previous state-of-the-art streaming method DarkStream while maintaining comparable latency (180ms vs 200ms) and privacy protection against lazy-informed attackers, though showing 15% relative degradation against semi-informed attackers.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.13948v3</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Reflexis: Supporting Reflexivity and Rigor in Collaborative Qualitative Analysis through Design for Deliberation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.15445</link><description>arXiv:2601.15445v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Reflexive Thematic Analysis (RTA) is a critical method for generating deep interpretive insights. Yet its core tenets, including researcher reflexivity, tangible analytical evolution, and productive disagreement, are often poorly supported by software tools that prioritize speed and consensus over interpretive depth. To address this gap, we introduce Reflexis, a collaborative workspace that centers these practices. It supports reflexivity by integrating in-situ reflection prompts, makes code evolution transparent and tangible, and scaffolds collaborative interpretation by turning differences into productive, positionality-aware dialogue. Results from our paired-analyst study (N=12) indicate that Reflexis encouraged participants toward more granular reflection and reframed disagreements as productive conversations. The evaluation also surfaced key design tensions, including a desire for higher-level, networked memos and more user control over the timing of proactive alerts. Reflexis contributes a design framework for tools that prioritize rigor and transparency to support deep, collaborative interpretation in an age of automation.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.15445v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Learning to Discover at Test Time</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.16175</link><description>arXiv:2601.16175v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: How can we use AI to discover a new state of the art for a scientific problem? Prior work in test-time scaling, such as AlphaEvolve, performs search by prompting a frozen LLM. We perform reinforcement learning at test time, so the LLM can continue to train, but now with experience specific to the test problem. This form of continual learning is quite special, because its goal is to produce one great solution rather than many good ones on average, and to solve this very problem rather than generalize to other problems. Therefore, our learning objective and search subroutine are designed to prioritize the most promising solutions. We call this method Test-Time Training to Discover (TTT-Discover). Following prior work, we focus on problems with continuous rewards. We report results for every problem we attempted, across mathematics, GPU kernel engineering, algorithm design, and biology. TTT-Discover sets the new state of the art in almost all of them: (i) Erd\H{o}s' minimum overlap problem and an autocorrelation inequality; (ii) a GPUMode kernel competition (up to $2\times$ faster than prior art); (iii) past AtCoder algorithm competitions; and (iv) denoising problem in single-cell analysis. Our solutions are reviewed by experts or the organizers. All our results are achieved with an open model, OpenAI gpt-oss-120b, and can be reproduced with our publicly available code, in contrast to previous best results that required closed frontier models. Our test-time training runs are performed using Tinker, an API by Thinking Machines, with a cost of only a few hundred dollars per problem.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.16175v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] STELLAR: Structure-guided LLM Assertion Retrieval and Generation for Formal Verification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2601.19903</link><description>arXiv:2601.19903v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Formal Verification (FV) relies on high-quality SystemVerilog Assertions (SVAs), but the manual writing process is slow and error-prone. Existing LLM-based approaches either generate assertions from scratch or ignore structural patterns in hardware designs and expert-crafted assertions. This paper presents STELLAR, the first framework that guides LLM-based SVA generation with structural similarity. STELLAR represents RTL blocks as AST structural fingerprints, retrieves structurally relevant (RTL, SVA) pairs from a knowledge base, and integrates them into structure-guided prompts. Experiments show that STELLAR achieves superior syntax correctness, stylistic alignment, and functional correctness, highlighting structure-aware retrieval as a promising direction for industrial FV.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2601.19903v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Impact of LLMs news Sentiment Analysis on Stock Price Movement Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.00086</link><description>arXiv:2602.00086v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: This paper addresses stock price movement prediction by leveraging LLM-based news sentiment analysis. Earlier works have largely focused on proposing and assessing sentiment analysis models and stock movement prediction methods, however, separately. Although promising results have been achieved, a clear and in-depth understanding of the benefit of the news sentiment to this task, as well as a comprehensive assessment of different architecture types in this context, is still lacking. Herein, we conduct an evaluation study that compares 3 different LLMs, namely, DeBERTa, RoBERTa and FinBERT, for sentiment-driven stock prediction. Our results suggest that DeBERTa outperforms the other two models with an accuracy of 75% and that an ensemble model that combines the three models can increase the accuracy to about 80%. Also, we see that sentiment news features can benefit (slightly) some stock market prediction models, i.e., LSTM-, PatchTST- and tPatchGNN-based classifiers and PatchTST- and TimesNet-based regression tasks models.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.00086v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-AI] Sounding Highlights: Dual-Pathway Audio Encoders for Audio-Visual Video Highlight Detection</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.03891</link><description>arXiv:2602.03891v2 Announce Type: replace-cross 
Abstract: Audio-visual video highlight detection aims to automatically identify the most salient moments in videos by leveraging both visual and auditory cues. However, existing models often underutilize the audio modality, focusing on high-level semantic features while failing to fully leverage the rich, dynamic characteristics of sound. To address this limitation, we propose a novel framework, Dual-Pathway Audio Encoders for Video Highlight Detection (DAViHD). The dual-pathway audio encoder is composed of a semantic pathway for content understanding and a dynamic pathway that captures spectro-temporal dynamics. The semantic pathway extracts high-level information by identifying the content within the audio, such as speech, music, or specific sound events. The dynamic pathway employs a frequency-adaptive mechanism as time evolves to jointly model these dynamics, enabling it to identify transient acoustic events via salient spectral bands and rapid energy changes. We integrate the novel audio encoder into a full audio-visual framework and achieve new state-of-the-art performance on the large-scale MrHiSum benchmark. Our results demonstrate that a sophisticated, dual-faceted audio representation is key to advancing the field of highlight detection.</description><author>cs.AI updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.03891v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] SemPipes -- Optimizable Semantic Data Operators for Tabular Machine Learning Pipelines</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05134</link><description>arXiv:2602.05134v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Real-world machine learning on tabular data relies on complex data preparation pipelines for prediction, data integration, augmentation, and debugging. Designing these pipelines requires substantial domain expertise and engineering effort, motivating the question of how large language models (LLMs) can support tabular ML through code synthesis. We introduce SemPipes, a novel declarative programming model that integrates LLM-powered semantic data operators into tabular ML pipelines. Semantic operators specify data transformations in natural language while delegating execution to a runtime system. During training, SemPipes synthesizes custom operator implementations based on data characteristics, operator instructions, and pipeline context. This design enables the automatic optimization of data operations in a pipeline via LLM-based code synthesis guided by evolutionary search. We evaluate SemPipes across diverse tabular ML tasks and show that semantic operators substantially improve end-to-end predictive performance for both expert-designed and agent-generated pipelines, while reducing pipeline complexity. We implement SemPipes in Python and release it at https://github.com/deem-data/sempipes/tree/v1.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05134v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Detecting Misbehaviors of Large Vision-Language Models by Evidential Uncertainty Quantification</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05535</link><description>arXiv:2602.05535v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Large vision-language models (LVLMs) have shown substantial advances in multimodal understanding and generation. However, when presented with incompetent or adversarial inputs, they frequently produce unreliable or even harmful content, such as fact hallucinations or dangerous instructions. This misalignment with human expectations, referred to as \emph{misbehaviors} of LVLMs, raises serious concerns for deployment in critical applications. These misbehaviors are found to stem from epistemic uncertainty, specifically either conflicting internal knowledge or the absence of supporting information. However, existing uncertainty quantification methods, which typically capture only overall epistemic uncertainty, have shown limited effectiveness in identifying such issues. To address this gap, we propose Evidential Uncertainty Quantification (EUQ), a fine-grained method that captures both information conflict and ignorance for effective detection of LVLM misbehaviors. In particular, we interpret features from the model output head as either supporting (positive) or opposing (negative) evidence. Leveraging Evidence Theory, we model and aggregate this evidence to quantify internal conflict and knowledge gaps within a single forward pass. We extensively evaluate our method across four categories of misbehavior, including hallucinations, jailbreaks, adversarial vulnerabilities, and out-of-distribution (OOD) failures, using state-of-the-art LVLMs, and find that EUQ consistently outperforms strong baselines, showing that hallucinations correspond to high internal conflict and OOD failures to high ignorance. Furthermore, layer-wise evidential uncertainty dynamics analysis helps interpret the evolution of internal representations from a new perspective. The source code is available at https://github.com/HT86159/EUQ.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05535v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] EdgeMask-DG*: Learning Domain-Invariant Graph Structures via Adversarial Edge Masking</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05571</link><description>arXiv:2602.05571v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Structural shifts pose a significant challenge for graph neural networks, as graph topology acts as a covariate that can vary across domains. Existing domain generalization methods rely on fixed structural augmentations or training on globally perturbed graphs, mechanisms that do not pinpoint which specific edges encode domain-invariant information. We argue that domain-invariant structural information is not rigidly tied to a single topology but resides in the consensus across multiple graph structures derived from topology and feature similarity. To capture this, we first propose EdgeMask-DG, a novel min-max algorithm where an edge masker learns to find worst-case continuous masks subject to a sparsity constraint, compelling a task GNN to perform effectively under these adversarial structural perturbations. Building upon this, we introduce EdgeMask-DG*, an extension that applies this adversarial masking principle to an enriched graph. This enriched graph combines the original topology with feature-derived edges, allowing the model to discover invariances even when the original topology is noisy or domain-specific. EdgeMask-DG* is the first to systematically combine adaptive adversarial topology search with feature-enriched graphs. We provide a formal justification for our approach from a robust optimization perspective. We demonstrate that EdgeMask-DG* achieves new state-of-the-art performance on diverse graph domain generalization benchmarks, including citation networks, social networks, and temporal graphs. Notably, on the Cora OOD benchmark, EdgeMask-DG* lifts the worst-case domain accuracy to 78.0\%, a +3.8 pp improvement over the prior state of the art (74.2\%). The source code for our experiments can be found here: https://anonymous.4open.science/r/TMLR-EAEF/</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05571v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] OpenMAG: A Comprehensive Benchmark for Multimodal-Attributed Graph</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05576</link><description>arXiv:2602.05576v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Multimodal-Attributed Graph (MAG) learning has achieved remarkable success in modeling complex real-world systems by integrating graph topology with rich attributes from multiple modalities. With the rapid proliferation of novel MAG models capable of handling intricate cross-modal semantics and structural dependencies, establishing a rigorous and unified evaluation standard has become imperative. Although existing benchmarks have facilitated initial progress, they exhibit critical limitations in domain coverage, encoder flexibility, model diversity, and task scope, presenting significant challenges to fair evaluation. To bridge this gap, we present OpenMAG, a comprehensive benchmark that integrates 19 datasets across 6 domains and incorporates 16 encoders to support both static and trainable feature encoding. OpenMAG further implements a standardized library of 24 state-of-the-art models and supports 8 downstream tasks, enabling fair comparisons within a unified framework. Through systematic assessment of necessity, data quality, effectiveness, robustness, and efficiency, we derive 14 fundamental insights into MAG learning to guide future advancements. Our code is available at https://github.com/YUKI-N810/OpenMAG.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05576v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Empowering Time Series Analysis with Large-Scale Multimodal Pretraining</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05646</link><description>arXiv:2602.05646v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: While existing time series foundation models primarily rely on large-scale unimodal pretraining, they lack complementary modalities to enhance time series understanding. Building multimodal foundation models is a natural next step, but it faces key challenges: 1) lack of a unified multimodal pretraining paradigm and large-scale multimodal corpora for time series analysis; 2) how to effectively integrate heterogeneous modalities and enhance model generalization. To address these challenges, we take an early step toward multimodal foundation models for time series analysis. We first propose a multimodal pretraining paradigm that leverages time series with endogenous modalities (derived images and text) and exogenous knowledge (real-world news), providing a comprehensive multi-view perspective for time series analysis. To support this, we develop an automated data construction pipeline to curate MM-TS, the first large-scale multimodal time series dataset spanning six domains, with up to one billion points. Then we propose HORAI, a frequency-enhanced multimodal foundation model. It integrates two core components: the Frequency-enhanced Cross-Modality Encoder and the Time-Frequency Decoder, designed to effectively fuse multimodal features and enhance model generalization across modalities and domains. After pretraining on MM-TS, HORAI achieves state-of-the-art zero-shot performance on time series forecasting and anomaly detection tasks, demonstrating strong generalization.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05646v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] CFRecs: Counterfactual Recommendations on Real Estate User Listing Interaction Graphs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05861</link><description>arXiv:2602.05861v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Graph-structured data is ubiquitous and powerful in representing complex relationships in many online platforms. While graph neural networks (GNNs) are widely used to learn from such data, counterfactual graph learning has emerged as a promising approach to improve model interpretability. Counterfactual explanation research focuses on identifying a counterfactual graph that is similar to the original but leads to different predictions. These explanations optimize two objectives simultaneously: the sparsity of changes in the counterfactual graph and the validity of its predictions. Building on these qualitative optimization goals, this paper introduces CFRecs, a novel framework that transforms counterfactual explanations into actionable insights. CFRecs employs a two-stage architecture consisting of a graph neural network (GNN) and a graph variational auto-encoder (Graph-VAE) to strategically propose minimal yet high-impact changes in graph structure and node attributes to drive desirable outcomes in recommender systems. We apply CFRecs to Zillow's graph-structured data to deliver actionable recommendations for both home buyers and sellers with the goal of helping them navigate the competitive housing market and achieve their homeownership goals. Experimental results on Zillow's user-listing interaction data demonstrate the effectiveness of CFRecs, which also provides a fresh perspective on recommendations using counterfactual reasoning in graphs.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05861v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Breaking Symmetry Bottlenecks in GNN Readouts</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05950</link><description>arXiv:2602.05950v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Graph neural networks (GNNs) are widely used for learning on structured data, yet their ability to distinguish non-isomorphic graphs is fundamentally limited. These limitations are usually attributed to message passing; in this work we show that an independent bottleneck arises at the readout stage. Using finite-dimensional representation theory, we prove that all linear permutation-invariant readouts, including sum and mean pooling, factor through the Reynolds (group-averaging) operator and therefore project node embeddings onto the fixed subspace of the permutation action, erasing all non-trivial symmetry-aware components regardless of encoder expressivity. This yields both a new expressivity barrier and an interpretable characterization of what global pooling preserves or destroys. To overcome this collapse, we introduce projector-based invariant readouts that decompose node representations into symmetry-aware channels and summarize them with nonlinear invariant statistics, preserving permutation invariance while retaining information provably invisible to averaging. Empirically, swapping only the readout enables fixed encoders to separate WL-hard graph pairs and improves performance across multiple benchmarks, demonstrating that readout design is a decisive and under-appreciated factor in GNN expressivity.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05950v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Layer-wise LoRA fine-tuning: a similarity metric approach</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05988</link><description>arXiv:2602.05988v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Pre-training Large Language Models (LLMs) on web-scale datasets becomes fundamental for advancing general-purpose AI. In contrast, enhancing their predictive performance on downstream tasks typically involves adapting their knowledge through fine-tuning. Parameter-efficient fine-tuning techniques, such as Low-Rank Adaptation (LoRA), aim to reduce the computational cost of this process by freezing the pre-trained model and updating a smaller number of parameters. In comparison to full fine-tuning, these methods achieve over 99\% reduction in trainable parameter count, depending on the configuration. Unfortunately, such a reduction may prove insufficient as LLMs continue to grow in scale. In this work, we address the previous problem by systematically selecting only a few layers to fine-tune using LoRA or its variants. We argue that not all layers contribute equally to the model adaptation. Leveraging this, we identify the most relevant layers to fine-tune by measuring their contribution to changes in internal representations. Our method is orthogonal to and readily compatible with existing low-rank adaptation techniques. We reduce the trainable parameters in LoRA-based techniques by up to 50\%, while maintaining the predictive performance across different models and tasks. Specifically, on encoder-only architectures, this reduction in trainable parameters leads to a negligible predictive performance drop on the GLUE benchmark. On decoder-only architectures, we achieve a small drop or even improvements in the predictive performance on mathematical problem-solving capabilities and coding tasks. Finally, this effectiveness extends to multimodal models, for which we also observe competitive results relative to fine-tuning with LoRA modules in all layers. Code is available at: https://github.com/c2d-usp/Layer-wise-LoRA-with-CKA</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05988v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Beyond Independent Genes: Learning Module-Inductive Representations for Gene Perturbation Prediction</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04901</link><description>arXiv:2602.04901v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Predicting transcriptional responses to genetic perturbations is a central problem in functional genomics. In practice, perturbation responses are rarely gene-independent but instead manifest as coordinated, program-level transcriptional changes among functionally related genes. However, most existing methods do not explicitly model such coordination, due to gene-wise modeling paradigms and reliance on static biological priors that cannot capture dynamic program reorganization. To address these limitations, we propose scBIG, a module-inductive perturbation prediction framework that explicitly models coordinated gene programs. scBIG induces coherent gene programs from data via Gene-Relation Clustering, captures inter-program interactions through a Gene-Cluster-Aware Encoder, and preserves modular coordination using structure-aware alignment objectives. These structured representations are then modeled using conditional flow matching to enable flexible and generalizable perturbation prediction. Extensive experiments on multiple single-cell perturbation benchmarks show that scBIG consistently outperforms state-of-the-art methods, particularly on unseen and combinatorial perturbation settings, achieving an average improvement of 6.7% over the strongest baselines.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04901v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Pruning Minimal Reasoning Graphs for Efficient Retrieval-Augmented Generation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.04926</link><description>arXiv:2602.04926v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) is now standard for knowledge-intensive LLM tasks, but most systems still treat every query as fresh, repeatedly re-retrieving long passages and re-reasoning from scratch, inflating tokens, latency, and cost. We present AutoPrunedRetriever, a graph-style RAG system that persists the minimal reasoning subgraph built for earlier questions and incrementally extends it for later ones. AutoPrunedRetriever stores entities and relations in a compact, ID-indexed codebook and represents questions, facts, and answers as edge sequences, enabling retrieval and prompting over symbolic structure instead of raw text. To keep the graph compact, we apply a two-layer consolidation policy (fast ANN/KNN alias detection plus selective $k$-means once a memory threshold is reached) and prune low-value structure, while prompts retain only overlap representatives and genuinely new evidence. We instantiate two front ends: AutoPrunedRetriever-REBEL, which uses REBEL as a triplet parser, and AutoPrunedRetriever-llm, which swaps in an LLM extractor. On GraphRAG-Benchmark (Medical and Novel), both variants achieve state-of-the-art complex reasoning accuracy, improving over HippoRAG2 by roughly 9--11 points, and remain competitive on contextual summarize and generation. On our harder STEM and TV benchmarks, AutoPrunedRetriever again ranks first, while using up to two orders of magnitude fewer tokens than graph-heavy baselines, making it a practical substrate for long-running sessions, evolving corpora, and multi-agent pipelines.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.04926v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Scaling Laws for Embedding Dimension in Information Retrieval</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05062</link><description>arXiv:2602.05062v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Dense retrieval, which encodes queries and documents into a single dense vector, has become the dominant neural retrieval approach due to its simplicity and compatibility with fast approximate nearest neighbor algorithms. As the tasks dense retrieval performs grow in complexity, the fundamental limitations of the underlying data structure and similarity metric -- namely vectors and inner-products -- become more apparent. Prior recent work has shown theoretical limitations inherent to single vectors and inner-products that are generally tied to the embedding dimension. Given the importance of embedding dimension for retrieval capacity, understanding how dense retrieval performance changes as embedding dimension is scaled is fundamental to building next generation retrieval models that balance effectiveness and efficiency. In this work, we conduct a comprehensive analysis of the relationship between embedding dimension and retrieval performance. Our experiments include two model families and a range of model sizes from each to construct a detailed picture of embedding scaling behavior. We find that the scaling behavior fits a power law, allowing us to derive scaling laws for performance given only embedding dimension, as well as a joint law accounting for embedding dimension and model size. Our analysis shows that for evaluation tasks aligned with the training task, performance continues to improve as embedding size increases, though with diminishing returns. For evaluation data that is less aligned with the training task, we find that performance is less predictable, with performance degrading with larger embedding dimensions for certain tasks. We hope our work provides additional insight into the limitations of embeddings and their behavior as well as offers a practical guide for selecting model and embedding dimension to achieve optimal performance with reduced storage and compute costs.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05062v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Price of universality in vector quantization is at most 0.11 bit</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05790</link><description>arXiv:2602.05790v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Fast computation of a matrix product $W^\top X$ is a workhorse of modern LLMs. To make their deployment more efficient, a popular approach is that of using a low-precision approximation $\widehat W$ in place of true $W$ ("weight-only quantization''). Information theory demonstrates that an optimal algorithm for reducing precision of $W$ depends on the (second order) statistics of $X$ and requires a careful alignment of vector quantization codebook with PCA directions of $X$ (a process known as "waterfilling allocation''). Dependence of the codebook on statistics of $X$, however, is highly impractical. This paper proves that there exist a universal codebook that is simultaneously near-optimal for all possible statistics of $X$, in the sense of being at least as good as an $X$-adapted waterfilling codebook with rate reduced by 0.11 bit per dimension. Such universal codebook would be an ideal candidate for the low-precision storage format, a topic of active modern research, but alas the existence proof is non-constructive.
  Equivalently, our result shows existence of a net in $\mathbb{R}^n$ that is a nearly-optimal covering of a sphere simultaneously with respect to all Hilbert norms.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05790v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Multi-Token Prediction via Self-Distillation</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06019</link><description>arXiv:2602.06019v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Existing techniques for accelerating language model inference, such as speculative decoding, require training auxiliary speculator models and building and deploying complex inference pipelines. We consider a new approach for converting a pretrained autoregressive language model from a slow single next token prediction model into a fast standalone multi-token prediction model using a simple online distillation objective. The final model retains the exact same implementation as the pretrained initial checkpoint and is deployable without the addition of any auxiliary verifier or other specialized inference code. On GSM8K, our method produces models that can decode more than $3\times$ faster on average at $&lt;5\%$ drop in accuracy relative to single token decoding performance.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06019v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] PhysicsAgentABM: Physics-Guided Generative Agent-Based Modeling</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.06030</link><description>arXiv:2602.06030v1 Announce Type: cross 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM)-based multi-agent systems enable expressive agent reasoning but are expensive to scale and poorly calibrated for timestep-aligned state-transition simulation, while classical agent-based models (ABMs) offer interpretability but struggle to integrate rich individual-level signals and non-stationary behaviors. We propose PhysicsAgentABM, which shifts inference to behaviorally coherent agent clusters: state-specialized symbolic agents encode mechanistic transition priors, a multimodal neural transition model captures temporal and interaction dynamics, and uncertainty-aware epistemic fusion yields calibrated cluster-level transition distributions. Individual agents then stochastically realize transitions under local constraints, decoupling population inference from entity-level variability. We further introduce ANCHOR, an LLM agent-driven clustering strategy based on cross-contextual behavioral responses and a novel contrastive loss, reducing LLM calls by up to 6-8 times. Experiments across public health, finance, and social sciences show consistent gains in event-time accuracy and calibration over mechanistic, neural, and LLM baselines. By re-architecting generative ABM around population-level inference with uncertainty-aware neuro-symbolic fusion, PhysicsAgentABM establishes a new paradigm for scalable and calibrated simulation with LLMs.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.06030v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Symplectic convolutional neural networks</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2508.19842</link><description>arXiv:2508.19842v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: We propose a new symplectic convolutional neural network (CNN) architecture by leveraging symplectic neural networks, proper symplectic decomposition, and tensor techniques. Specifically, we first introduce a mathematically equivalent form of the convolution layer and then, using symplectic neural networks, we demonstrate a way to parameterize the layers of the CNN to ensure that the convolution layer remains symplectic. To construct a complete autoencoder, we introduce a symplectic pooling layer. We demonstrate the performance of the proposed neural network on three examples: the wave equation, the nonlinear Schr\"odinger (NLS) equation, and the sine-Gordon equation. The numerical results indicate that the symplectic CNN outperforms the linear symplectic autoencoder obtained via proper symplectic decomposition.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2508.19842v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Downgrade to Upgrade: Optimizer Simplification Enhances Robustness in LLM Unlearning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.00761</link><description>arXiv:2510.00761v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language model (LLM) unlearning aims to surgically remove the influence of undesired data or knowledge from an existing model while preserving its utility on unrelated tasks. This paradigm has shown promise in addressing privacy and safety concerns. However, recent findings reveal that unlearning effects are often fragile: post-unlearning manipulations such as weight quantization or fine-tuning can quickly neutralize the intended forgetting. Prior efforts to improve robustness primarily reformulate unlearning objectives by explicitly assuming the role of vulnerability sources. In this work, we take a different perspective by investigating the role of the optimizer, independent of unlearning objectives and formulations, in shaping unlearning robustness. We show that the 'grade' of the optimizer, defined by the level of information it exploits, ranging from zeroth-order (gradient-free) to first-order (gradient-based) to second-order (Hessian-based), is tightly linked to the resilience of unlearning. Surprisingly, we find that downgrading the optimizer, such as using zeroth-order methods or compressed-gradient variants (e.g., gradient sign-based optimizers), often leads to stronger robustness. While these optimizers produce noisier and less precise updates, they encourage convergence to harder-to-disturb basins in the loss landscape, thereby resisting post-training perturbations. By connecting zeroth-order methods with randomized smoothing, we further highlight their natural advantage for robust unlearning. Motivated by these insights, we propose a hybrid optimizer that combines first-order and zeroth-order updates, preserving unlearning efficacy while enhancing robustness. Extensive experiments on the MUSE and WMDP benchmarks, across multiple LLM unlearning algorithms, validate that our approach achieves more resilient forgetting without sacrificing unlearning quality.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.00761v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] Progressive multi-fidelity learning with neural networks for physical system predictions</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2510.13762</link><description>arXiv:2510.13762v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Highly accurate datasets from numerical or physical experiments are often expensive and time-consuming to acquire, posing a significant challenge for applications that require precise evaluations, potentially across multiple scenarios and in real-time. Even building sufficiently accurate surrogate models can be extremely challenging with limited high-fidelity data. Conversely, less expensive, low-fidelity data can be computed more easily and encompass a broader range of scenarios. By leveraging multi-fidelity information, prediction capabilities of surrogates can be improved. However, in practical situations, data may be different in types, come from sources of different modalities, and not be concurrently available, further complicating the modeling process. To address these challenges, we introduce a progressive multi-fidelity surrogate model. This model can sequentially incorporate diverse data types using tailored encoders. Multi-fidelity regression from the encoded inputs to the target quantities of interest is then performed using neural networks. Input information progressively flows from lower to higher fidelity levels through two sets of connections: concatenations among all the encoded inputs, and additive connections among the final outputs. This dual connection system enables the model to exploit correlations among different datasets while ensuring that each level makes an additive correction to the previous level without altering it. This approach prevents performance degradation as new input data are integrated into the model and automatically adapts predictions based on the available inputs. We demonstrate the effectiveness of the approach on numerical benchmarks and a real-world case study, showing that it reliably integrates multi-modal data and provides accurate predictions, maintaining performance when generalizing across time and parameter variations.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2510.13762v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-LG] The Double Life of Code World Models: Provably Unmasking Malicious Behavior Through Execution Traces</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2512.13821</link><description>arXiv:2512.13821v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Large language models (LLMs) increasingly generate code with minimal human oversight, raising critical concerns about backdoor injection and malicious behavior. We present Cross-Trace Verification Protocol (CTVP), a novel AI control framework that verifies untrusted code-generating models through semantic orbit analysis. Rather than directly executing potentially malicious code, CTVP leverages the model's own predictions of execution traces across semantically equivalent program transformations. By analyzing consistency patterns in these predicted traces, we detect behavioral anomalies indicative of backdoors. Our approach introduces the Adversarial Robustness Quotient (ARQ), which quantifies the computational cost of verification relative to baseline generation, demonstrating exponential growth with orbit size. Theoretical analysis establishes information-theoretic bounds showing non-gamifiability - adversaries cannot improve through training due to fundamental space complexity constraints. This work demonstrates that semantic orbit analysis provides a theoretically grounded approach to AI control for code generation tasks, though practical deployment requires addressing the high false positive rates observed in initial evaluations.</description><author>cs.LG updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2512.13821v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] FedMosaic: Federated Retrieval-Augmented Generation via Parametric Adapters</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05235</link><description>arXiv:2602.05235v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) enhances Large Language Models (LLMs) by grounding generation in external knowledge to improve factuality and reduce hallucinations. Yet most deployments assume a centralized corpus, which is infeasible in privacy aware domains where knowledge remains siloed. This motivates federated RAG (FedRAG), where a central LLM server collaborates with distributed silos without sharing raw documents. In context RAG violates this requirement by transmitting verbatim documents, whereas parametric RAG encodes documents into lightweight adapters that merge with a frozen LLM at inference, avoiding raw-text exchange. We adopt the parametric approach but face two unique challenges induced by FedRAG: high storage and communication from per-document adapters, and destructive aggregation caused by indiscriminately merging multiple adapters. We present FedMosaic, the first federated RAG framework built on parametric adapters. FedMosaic clusters semantically related documents into multi-document adapters with document-specific masks to reduce overhead while preserving specificity, and performs selective adapter aggregation to combine only relevance-aligned, nonconflicting adapters. Experiments show that FedMosaic achieves an average 10.9% higher accuracy than state-of-the-art methods in four categories, while lowering storage costs by 78.8% to 86.3% and communication costs by 91.4%, and never sharing raw documents.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05235v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] IESR:Efficient MCTS-Based Modular Reasoning for Text-to-SQL with Large Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05385</link><description>arXiv:2602.05385v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Text-to-SQL is a key natural language processing task that maps natural language questions to SQL queries, enabling intuitive interaction with web-based databases. Although current methods perform well on benchmarks like BIRD and Spider, they struggle with complex reasoning, domain knowledge, and hypothetical queries, and remain costly in enterprise deployment. To address these issues, we propose a framework named IESR(Information Enhanced Structured Reasoning) for lightweight large language models: (i) leverages LLMs for key information understanding and schema linking, and decoupling mathematical computation and SQL generation, (ii) integrates a multi-path reasoning mechanism based on Monte Carlo Tree Search (MCTS) with majority voting, and (iii) introduces a trajectory consistency verification module with a discriminator model to ensure accuracy and consistency. Experimental results demonstrate that IESR achieves state-of-the-art performance on the complex reasoning benchmark LogicCat (24.28 EX) and the Archer dataset (37.28 EX) using only compact lightweight models without fine-tuning. Furthermore, our analysis reveals that current coder models exhibit notable biases and deficiencies in physical knowledge, mathematical computation, and common-sense reasoning, highlighting important directions for future research. We released code at https://github.com/Ffunkytao/IESR-SLM.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05385v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] Causal Front-Door Adjustment for Robust Jailbreak Attacks on LLMs</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05444</link><description>arXiv:2602.05444v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Safety alignment mechanisms in Large Language Models (LLMs) often operate as latent internal states, obscuring the model's inherent capabilities. Building on this observation, we model the safety mechanism as an unobserved confounder from a causal perspective. Then, we propose the \textbf{C}ausal \textbf{F}ront-Door \textbf{A}djustment \textbf{A}ttack ({\textbf{CFA}}$^2$) to jailbreak LLM, which is a framework that leverages Pearl's Front-Door Criterion to sever the confounding associations for robust jailbreaking. Specifically, we employ Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) to physically strip defense-related features, isolating the core task intent. We further reduce computationally expensive marginalization to a deterministic intervention with low inference complexity. Experiments demonstrate that {CFA}$^2$ achieves state-of-the-art attack success rates while offering a mechanistic interpretation of the jailbreaking process.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05444v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] Stop Rewarding Hallucinated Steps: Faithfulness-Aware Step-Level Reinforcement Learning for Small Reasoning Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05897</link><description>arXiv:2602.05897v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: As large language models become smaller and more efficient, small reasoning models (SRMs) are crucial for enabling chain-of-thought (CoT) reasoning in resource-constrained settings. However, they are prone to faithfulness hallucinations, especially in intermediate reasoning steps. Existing mitigation methods based on online reinforcement learning rely on outcome-based rewards or coarse-grained CoT evaluation, which can inadvertently reinforce unfaithful reasoning when the final answer is correct. To address these limitations, we propose Faithfulness-Aware Step-Level Reinforcement Learning (FaithRL), introducing step-level supervision via explicit faithfulness rewards from a process reward model, together with an implicit truncated resampling strategy that generates contrastive signals from faithful prefixes. Experiments across multiple SRMs and Open-Book QA benchmarks demonstrate that FaithRL consistently reduces hallucinations in both the CoT and final answers, leading to more faithful and reliable reasoning. Code is available at https://github.com/Easy195/FaithRL.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05897v1</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] Invisible Walls in Cities: Designing LLM Agent to Predict Urban Segregation Experience with Social Media Content</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.04773</link><description>arXiv:2503.04773v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Understanding experienced segregation in urban daily life is crucial for addressing societal inequalities and fostering inclusivity. The abundance of user-generated reviews on social media encapsulates nuanced perceptions and feelings associated with different places, offering rich insights into segregation. However, leveraging this data poses significant challenges due to its vast volume, ambiguity, and confluence of diverse perspectives. To tackle these challenges, we propose a novel Large Language Model (LLM) agent to automate online review mining for segregation prediction. Specifically, we propose a reflective LLM coder to digest social media content into insights consistent with real-world feedback, and eventually produce a codebook capturing key dimensions that signal segregation experience, such as cultural resonance and appeal, accessibility and convenience, and community engagement and local involvement. Guided by the codebook, LLMs can generate both informative review summaries and ratings for segregation prediction. Moreover, we design a REasoning-and-EMbedding (RE'EM) framework, which combines the reasoning and embedding capabilities of language models to integrate multi-channel features for segregation prediction.
  Experiments on real-world data demonstrate that our agent substantially improves prediction accuracy, with a 22.79% elevation in R$^{2}$ and a 9.33% reduction in MSE. The derived codebook is generalizable across three different cities, consistently improving prediction accuracy. Moreover, our user study confirms that the codebook-guided summaries provide cognitive gains for human participants in perceiving places of interest (POIs)' social inclusiveness. Our study marks an important step toward understanding implicit social barriers and inequalities, demonstrating the great potential of promoting social inclusiveness with Web technology.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2503.04773v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] Fin-R1: A Large Language Model for Financial Reasoning through Reinforcement Learning</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2503.16252</link><description>arXiv:2503.16252v4 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: In recent years, general-purpose large language models (LLMs) such as GPT, Gemini, Claude, and DeepSeek have advanced at an unprecedented pace. Despite these achievements, their application to finance remains challenging, due to fragmented data sources, intransparent reasoning processes, and weak transferability to business applications. In response, we introduce Fin-R1, a reasoning LLM designed for financial scenarios. With a compact size of 7 billion parameters, Fin-R1 reduces deployment costs while addressing the aforementioned challenges. Its development follows a two-stage pipeline. First, we construct Fin-R1-Data, a high-quality financial dataset consisting of 60,091 chain-of-thought (CoT) samples, distilled and filtered from multiple authoritative benchmarks to ensure consistency and reliability. Second, we train Fin-R1 using Fin-R1-Data through supervised fine-tuning (SFT), followed by reinforcement learning (RL). This stage substantially improves the model's ability to solve complex financial reasoning tasks, yielding outputs that are both accurate and interpretable. Despite its relatively small parameter scale, Fin-R1 achieves competitive empirical performance across established financial benchmarks and demonstrates practical utility in compliance checking and robo-advisory. Our code is publicly available at https://github.com/SUFE-AIFLM-Lab/Fin-R1, and has already attracted over 700 stars.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2503.16252v4</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-CL] DecompressionLM: Deterministic, Diagnostic, and Zero-Shot Concept Graph Extraction from Language Models</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.00377</link><description>arXiv:2602.00377v2 Announce Type: replace 
Abstract: Existing knowledge probing methods rely on pre-defined queries, limiting extraction to known concepts. We introduce DecompressionLM, a stateless framework for zero-shot concept graph extraction that discovers what language models encode without pre-specified queries or shared cross-sequence state. Our method targets three limitations of common decoding-based probing approaches: (i) cross-sequence coupling that concentrates probability mass on high-frequency prefixes, (ii) competitive decoding effects that suppress long-tail concepts, and (iii) scalability constraints arising from sequential exploration. Using Van der Corput low-discrepancy sequences with arithmetic decoding, DecompressionLM enables deterministic, embarrassingly parallel generation without shared state across sequences. Across two model families and five quantization variants, we find that activation-aware quantization (AWQ-4bit) expands concept coverage by 30-170%, while uniform quantization (GPTQ-Int4) induces 71-86% coverage collapse - divergent behaviors not reliably reflected by explanation-level perplexity. Corpus-based verification further reveals a 19.6-point hallucination gap between top- and bottom-ranked MMLU-Pro Law models. DecompressionLM establishes concept coverage as a complementary evaluation dimension for assessing knowledge breadth and factual grounding in compressed models intended for deployment.</description><author>cs.CL updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.00377v2</guid></item><item><title>[arXiv-IR] GLASS: A Generative Recommender for Long-sequence Modeling via SID-Tier and Semantic Search</title><link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2602.05663</link><description>arXiv:2602.05663v1 Announce Type: new 
Abstract: Leveraging long-term user behavioral patterns is a key trajectory for enhancing the accuracy of modern recommender systems. While generative recommender systems have emerged as a transformative paradigm, they face hurdles in effectively modeling extensive historical sequences. To address this challenge, we propose GLASS, a novel framework that integrates long-term user interests into the generative process via SID-Tier and Semantic Search. We first introduce SID-Tier, a module that maps long-term interactions into a unified interest vector to enhance the prediction of the initial SID token. Unlike traditional retrieval models that struggle with massive item spaces, SID-Tier leverages the compact nature of the semantic codebook to incorporate cross features between the user's long-term history and candidate semantic codes. Furthermore, we present semantic hard search, which utilizes generated coarse-grained semantic ID as dynamic keys to extract relevant historical behaviors, which are then fused via an adaptive gated fusion module to recalibrate the trajectory of subsequent fine-grained tokens. To address the inherent data sparsity in semantic hard search, we propose two strategies: semantic neighbor augmentation and codebook resizing. Extensive experiments on two large-scale real-world datasets, TAOBAO-MM and KuaiRec, demonstrate that GLASS outperforms state-of-the-art baselines, achieving significant gains in recommendation quality. Our codes are made publicly available to facilitate further research in generative recommendation.</description><author>cs.IR updates on arXiv.org</author><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">oai:arXiv.org:2602.05663v1</guid></item><item><title>[TSE] The Power of Small LLMs: A Multi-Agent for Code Generation via Dynamic Precaution Tuning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TSE.2025.3632508</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tse</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tse/ZhangLTZ26</guid></item><item><title>[TSE] Shield Broken: Black-Box Adversarial Attacks on LLM-Based Vulnerability Detectors.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TSE.2025.3638998</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tse</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tse/JiangHTSW26</guid></item><item><title>[TSE] MirrorFuzz: Leveraging LLM and Shared Bugs for Deep Learning Framework APIs Fuzzing.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/TSE.2025.3619966</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/tse</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jan 2026 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/tse/OuLYWWCCTP26</guid></item><item><title>[TOSEM] PonziHunter: Hunting Ethereum Ponzi Contract via Static Analysis and Contrastive Learning on the Bytecode Level</title><link>https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3735971?af=R</link><description>ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology, Volume 35, Issue 2, Page 1-21, February 2026. &lt;br /&gt;</description><author>Association for Computing Machinery: ACM Transactions on Software Engineering and Methodology: Table of Contents</author><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 04:18:39 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">https://dl.acm.org/doi/abs/10.1145/3735971?af=R</guid></item><item><title>[CCS] Demo: Reverse Engineering Android Apps with Code Coverage.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3762169</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Pilgun25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS] Poster: Insecure Coding Habits Die Hard. Can PEFT Really Turn LLMs into Secure Coders?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3760716</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/ChaeCKJOK25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS] Poster: Leveraging Large Language Models to Effectively and Efficiently Identify Vulnerability Patches for WordPress Plugins.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3760720</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/LengZZS25</guid></item><item><title>[CCS] AI-Augmented Static Analysis: Bridging Heuristics and Completeness for Practical Reverse Engineering.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3719027.3765565</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ccs</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ccs/Santra25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec] LLMxCPG: Context-Aware Vulnerability Detection Through Code Property Graph-Guided Large Language Models.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/lekssays</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/LekssaysMT0K25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec] We Have a Package for You! A Comprehensive Analysis of Package Hallucinations by Code Generating LLMs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/spracklen</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/SpracklenWSMV25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec] Logs In, Patches Out: Automated Vulnerability Repair via Tree-of-Thought LLM Analysis.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/kim-youngjoon</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/Kim0KY25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec] APPATCH: Automated Adaptive Prompting Large Language Models for Real-World Software Vulnerability Patching.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/nong</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/NongY0HC25</guid></item><item><title>[USENIXSec] From Alarms to Real Bugs: Multi-target Multi-step Directed Greybox Fuzzing for Static Analysis Result Verification.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/usenixsecurity25/presentation/bao-andrew</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/uss</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/uss/BaoZWCMY25</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] GPTVD: vulnerability detection and analysis method based on LLM's chain of thoughts.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00550-4</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/ChenHCSY26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] BRMDS: an LLM-based multi-dimensional summary generation approach for bug reports.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00553-1</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/ZhangLFYD26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] ByteEye: A smart contract vulnerability detection framework at bytecode level with graph neural networks.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00559-9</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/YangLDFXL26</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] SPVR: syntax-to-prompt vulnerability repair based on large language models.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1007/s10515-025-00579-5</link><description></description><author>dblp: new issues for streams/journals/ase</author><pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:journals/ase/WangLGWXW26</guid></item><item><title>[SOSP] KNighter: Transforming Static Analysis with LLM-Synthesized Checkers.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3731569.3764827</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/sosp</author><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/sosp/YangZXLZ25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI] CoderAgent: Simulating Student Behavior for Personalized Programming Learning with Large Language Models.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/34</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/ZhanLGZ0SLH25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI] POLO: An LLM-Powered Project-Level Code Performance Optimization Framework.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/814</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/BaiXWY0025</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI] Can We Translate Code Better with LLMs and Call Graph Analysis?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/848</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/Luo25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI] SecV: LLM-based Secure Verilog Generation with Clue-Guided Exploration on Hardware-CWE Knowledge Graph.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/895</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/FanXK25</guid></item><item><title>[IJCAI] How to Teach Programming in the AI Era? Using LLMs as a Teachable Agent for Debugging (Extended Abstract).</title><link>https://doi.org/10.24963/ijcai.2025/1217</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ijcai</author><pubDate>Sun, 21 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ijcai/Ma0KW25</guid></item><item><title>[EuroS&amp;P] Mitigating Information Leakage in Large Language Models: Evaluating the Impact of Code Obfuscation on Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/EuroSPW67616.2025.00007</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/eurosp</author><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/eurosp/GulayY25</guid></item><item><title>[S&amp;P] Code Vulnerability Repair with Large Language Model Using Context-Aware Prompt Tuning.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/SPW67851.2025.00040</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/sp</author><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/sp/KhanLG25</guid></item><item><title>[OSDI] Stripeless Data Placement for Erasure-Coded In-Memory Storage.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/osdi25/presentation/gao</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/osdi</author><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/osdi/GaoSY0H25</guid></item><item><title>[OSDI] Paralegal: Practical Static Analysis for Privacy Bugs.</title><link>https://www.usenix.org/conference/osdi25/presentation/adam</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/osdi</author><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/osdi/AdamZZRHJCKS25</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA] Revisiting the Combination of Static Analysis Error Traces and Dynamic Symbolic Execution: A Potential Approach for True Positive Confirmation (Registered Report).</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3731720</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/Xu0P25</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA] A Preliminary Study of Large Language Models for Multilingual Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3731746</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/YuSF0TK025</guid></item><item><title>[ISSTA] Patch the Leak: Strengthening CodeLLMs Against Privacy Extraction Threats.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3713081.3732931</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/issta</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/issta/GuoMXWD025</guid></item><item><title>[ACSAC] Software Vulnerability Detection Using LLM: Does Additional Information Help?</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1109/ACSACW65225.2024.00031</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/acsac</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/acsac/ShimmiSSOR24</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS] A Comprehensive Memory Safety Analysis of Bootloaders.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/a-comprehensive-memory-safety-analysis-of-bootloaders/</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/WangWWLS0H25</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS] From Large to Mammoth: A Comparative Evaluation of Large Language Models in Vulnerability Detection.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/from-large-to-mammoth-a-comparative-evaluation-of-large-language-models-in-vulnerability-detection/</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/LinM25</guid></item><item><title>[NDSS] PropertyGPT: LLM-driven Formal Verification of Smart Contracts through Retrieval-Augmented Property Generation.</title><link>https://www.ndss-symposium.org/ndss-paper/propertygpt-llm-driven-formal-verification-of-smart-contracts-through-retrieval-augmented-property-generation/</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/ndss</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/ndss/0012XW00S025</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Language-Agnostic Static Analysis of Probabilistic Programs.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695031</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/Bock0C24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Leveraging Large Language Model to Assist Detecting Rust Code Comment Inconsistency.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695010</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/ZhangL0X24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Three Heads Are Better Than One: Suggesting Move Method Refactoring Opportunities with Inter-class Code Entity Dependency Enhanced Hybrid Hypergraph Neural Network.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695068</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/CuiWWJQZHWL24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] AdvSCanner: Generating Adversarial Smart Contracts to Exploit Reentrancy Vulnerabilities Using LLM and Static Analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695482</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WuXPLW00W24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] STASE: Static Analysis Guided Symbolic Execution for UEFI Vulnerability Signature Generation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695543</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/ShafiuzzamanDSB24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Efficient Incremental Code Coverage Analysis for Regression Test Suites.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695551</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangW024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Enhancing Compositional Static Analysis with Dynamic Analysis.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695599</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/DistefanoMACSGH24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Unity Is Strength: Collaborative LLM-Based Agents for Code Reviewer Recommendation.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695291</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangZZLCZ024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Oracle-Guided Vulnerability Diversity and Exploit Synthesis of Smart Contracts Using LLMs.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695292</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/EshghieA24</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] ContractTinker: LLM-Empowered Vulnerability Repair for Real-World Smart Contracts.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695349</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/WangZGXG024</guid></item><item><title>[ASE] Bridging Gaps in LLM Code Translation: Reducing Errors with Call Graphs and Bridged Debuggers.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3691620.3695322</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/kbse</author><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/kbse/LuoYZLX24</guid></item><item><title>[POPL] Hypercollecting semantics and its application to static analysis of information flow.</title><link>https://doi.org/10.1145/3009837.3009889</link><description></description><author>dblp: new volumes for streams/conf/popl</author><pubDate>Tue, 27 Dec 2016 23:00:00 GMT</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="true">dblp:conf/popl/AssafNSTT17</guid></item></channel></rss>